<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: napowrimo | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/napowrimo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-23T12:31:48-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NaNoWriMo 2016 #2: About Owners]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-number-2-about-owners/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-08T08:07:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-number-2-about-owners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am, taking on a November writing project again.
If you haven&rsquo;t seen me do this before, here&rsquo;s what I do.
I don&rsquo;t have a novel in me right now, so for NaNoWriMo I just do as many short stories as I can.
I use the social momentum and recognition of NaNoWriMo to push myself to spend a lot of time writing and to explain to others what I&rsquo;m doing.
As with the novels people produce during NaNo, I try to be very forgiving towards myself and my work; it is okay to just drop an idea when I get stuck and move on to the next story.</p>

<p>This is another installment of this year&rsquo;s project.
It&rsquo;s centered around a hyena boy with a big ol' kink for sissy-play getting commandingly fucked.
Content note: slurs.</p>

<!--more-->


<hr />

<p>When the sun through the blinds woke him, <span>Faije</span> straddled
hir belly. Wagging his tail and resting his paws on hir shoulders, he
nuzzled up from the top of hir breasts to hir throat and jaw, gently
headbutting hir muzzle from beneath as shi batted at him. Quiet laughs
rose from <span>Chaiax</span>&rsquo;s massive chest as shi pushed hirself up
on hir elbows, giving him a bite and a kiss in quick succession.
<span>Faije</span> threw his arms around hir thick neck, surrendering to
hir kiss. Shi leaned on one arm, hir other around the diminutive hyena.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<em>Someone</em> woke up frisky,&rdquo; the huge tiger-dragon chuckled, smiling
widely. &ldquo;Last night was really good,&rdquo; he said with a blush, ears
flicking as he sat back, hands in his lap. &ldquo;Thank you again.&rdquo; A pause.
&ldquo;Thank you, <em>Mistress</em>?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The big hybrid stroked his back, smiling and nodding.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You know, we&rsquo;ve been doing this for a while and I dig how it&rsquo;s been
working out. So let&rsquo;s talk about that. Over breakfast, though — I&rsquo;m
hungry as fuck.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Faije</span> nodded eagerly, wiggling his soft rump against hir
and wagging his tail. It struck something, and he looked over his
shoulder, then shivered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Fuck. I&rsquo;m <em>still</em> not used to how huge you are. I was wondering what my
tail hit that was so heavy and it was your cock.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You say things like that and I want to throw you down and fuck you just
to make sure you remember!&rdquo; A smirk, a pointed look. &ldquo;Is that what
you&rsquo;re aiming for, you insatiable spotty bitch?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Faije</span> blushed in a way that made hir roll over on top of
him for another kiss, hir tongue invading his muzzle. Heavy hands pinned
his wrists as shi growled deeply — he closed his eyes and sucked on hir
tongue, moaning softly, squirming just a little to confirm how helpless
he was under the huge predator. He raised his legs, squeezing them
against hir thighs as shi rocked back and forth.</p>

<p>Long moments later, shi rolled off of him, stood, and offered him a
hand. He took it, was pulled, stood, and then yelped as shi took another
grasp on him and threw him over hir shoulder ass-up and head-down. At
hir touch, he cooperatively shook his ass and got felt up all the way to
the kitchen.</p>

<p>Shi made breakfast with him quietly, both clad in nothing but aprons. He
had to tug a footstool from place to place to conveniently reach the
counters of the huge draco-feline&rsquo;s kitchen. It in turn made it
convenient for hir to reach him, intermittent caresses laid on him, the
hyena returning the gestures when shi was within reach. Soon they sat
side by side, looking out the window, consuming eggs, sausages, and
savory roughage.</p>

<p><span>Chaiax</span> smiled as <span>Faije</span> reached over and
absently trailed his fingers down hir densely muscled forearm. Shi
turned hir hand over as he reached it, giving his a gentle squeeze.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Precious puppy,&rdquo; shi rumbled, leaning over to nuzzle his ears.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Big strong tigerdragon,&rdquo; he cooed.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Would you like to talk more about what you&rsquo;re feeling,
<span>Faije</span>?&rdquo; shi asked, stressing his name for a moment.</p>

<p>He nodded slowly, hugging hir arm, nosing against it, closing his eyes
for a minute to savor the feel of hir fur on his muzzle and against his
nose.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah. I had a dream about <span>Darja</span> last night — did I ever
tell you about him?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hmmm — I think I remember that name as an ex-boyfriend or as someone
who got you into kink?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Both.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Ah, thanks for clarifying. What about him?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He was the first time I&rsquo;d run into the idea that some people just
choose to be eunuchs, do the needful, and move on with their life. Good
role model that way. The dream was about you and him and me. I dreamed
that you&rsquo;d been the one to claim him, rather than him doing it to
himself, and he was showing off, telling me how good it was, telling me
I should surrender to you.&rdquo; A shiver. &ldquo;I begged. It was pretty hot.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi reached around with hir free hand, rubbing his nape.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Ah. So, lots of thoughts about being your in-scene sissy-bitch-yeen
self on more of a full-time basis?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He nodded, hiding his face against hir bicep for a minute. Shi could
feel his blush.</p>

<p>&ldquo;There was a bit of the dream where he was masturbating in this way I
saw him do pretty often when I was living with him: he&rsquo;d slip a chubby
bullet vibe into his sheath, close it up with a little surgical tape,
and the vibe would buzz right against his nub and he&rsquo;d rub over it on
the outside.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A soft, hungry growl.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<em>Gracious.</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah. Part of why I saw it a bunch is that he&rsquo;d do it with me watching,
he&rsquo;d do it <em>at</em> me. Legs spread, showing off, taunting me — I was really
into chastity-cage stuff then — telling me exactly how desperate I&rsquo;d
have to be before I got my cock loose.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi gave him a surprised glance. He looked up at hir, then raised a
finger, shaking it in realization.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh — I get it! You thought he was someone different because I talked
about a <em>dom</em> that got me into kink stuff. No, no, that was him. He went
back and forth. There were plenty of people he liked being subby for,
and sometimes we&rsquo;d just cuddle and fantasize about being some stud&rsquo;s
pets together. But he topped me on the regular and liked it quite a bit,
he was absolutely the dom in that relationship.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I guess I had a blind spot about that,&rdquo; shi conceded, rubbing hir chin.
&ldquo;Jeeze. Now that I&rsquo;m looking at it directly, that was goddamn ridiculous
of me: whether or not someone wants to top or has dominance urges is
pretty damn thoroughly separate from the shape of their body.&rdquo;</p>

<div style="text-align:center">* * *</div>


<p>&ldquo;How much someone wants or needs to be a dom has nothing to do with the
shape of their body,&rdquo; <span>Darja</span> drawled, flexing a flogger in
gloved hands.</p>

<p><span>Faije</span> nodded, making a noncommittal noise through his
ball-gag. His wrists were cuffed behind his back, and he knelt with his
thighs spread. <span>Darja</span> grinned, swinging the flogger lazily,
then letting its tip drift up and tease the gleaming steel cage locked
around <span>Faije</span>&rsquo;s sheath and fat nuts. He shuddered, pulling
in a breath and closing his eyes — but the blow to his groin that
followed was almost a tap. Still, the spikes inside the cage forced his
prick to retreat moments later.</p>

<p><span>Darja</span> reached down and casually fondled the silicone cock
that swayed obscenely from his strap-on harness.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You know, I&rsquo;ve been using these for long enough that having a big ol'
dick feels pretty normal when I&rsquo;m wearing it, even though I know
intellectually that it&rsquo;s not part of my body. What I keep getting a buzz
of newness from, though, is these.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He demonstratively jostled the hefty artifical scrotum beneath his cock,
noting how the other hyena&rsquo;s eyes followed it.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Feels pretty good, let me tell you, pret-ty good, to be able to adjust
these big ol' balls any time I please.&rdquo; A smirk. &ldquo;Or to have you adjust
them — with your tongue, of course. Treat &lsquo;em like they&rsquo;re more
important than yours, because they are.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Another blow from the flogger, sudden and harsh, leaving
<span>Faije</span> squealing and yipping through the ball-gag, his head
hanging. With a chuckle, <span>Darja</span> pulled <span>Faije</span>&rsquo;s
head up by the strap of the gag, pushing his nose into the musky divot
under the monstrous equine cock, lips on the velvety pouch around
<span>Darja</span>&rsquo;s balls. The artificial cock drooled cum-lube down
his back from its internal tube.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Do you want your mouth unlocked, faggot? Do you want to try and fit
this into your throat? Do you want it badly enough to beg for it?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Please,&rdquo; he groaned around the ball-gag, drooling through the holes in
it.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I can&rsquo;t hear you clearly,&rdquo; <span>Darja</span> taunted. &ldquo;Louder, pup.&rdquo;</p>

<p>When <span>Faije</span> inhaled to try again, <span>Darja</span> shifted
around and dragged his flare across <span>Faije</span>&rsquo;s forehead, the
slimy, milky trail it left dribbling down his brow and muzzle. He
whimpered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<em>Please!</em>&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;There we go.&rdquo; He loosened the strap, then pulled the ball most of the
way out of <span>Faije</span>&rsquo;s muzzle. &ldquo;Please what?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Please fuck my throat,&rdquo; <span>Faije</span> panted, feeling the cage&rsquo;s
spikes digging into his cock again.</p>

<div style="text-align:center">* * *</div>


<p>&ldquo;The sex was pretty damn good,&rdquo; <span>Faije</span> reminisced, &ldquo;but we
didn&rsquo;t click as far as the actual relationship part. Plus, that
motherfucker never in the entire time I knew him did his own dishes.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Chaiax</span> raised an eyebrow at the heated tone in his voice.
He laughed hollowly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I mean — forgive me for sucking up, but that&rsquo;s a thing I like about
you: you do really well at not assuming that because I&rsquo;m your sub, I&rsquo;m
your houseboy too.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you,&rdquo; shi said drily. &ldquo;I do worry about that a bit in the context
of turning up the intensity dial, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;About what particularly? Dishes?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;More about me taking shit for granted. I&rsquo;m always suspicious of that;
I&rsquo;m suspicious because I&rsquo;ve fucked up at that <em>a lot</em> in my life.&rdquo; Shi
smiled, leaning down to kiss his ears. &ldquo;And I like you a lot, so I&rsquo;m
wary at the thought of fucking up when it comes to you and your place in
my life.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He leaned into hir touch as shi scrubbed his back with hir fingertips,
then tugged hir hand around and kiss-nuzzled along hir scaly inner arm
to hir wrist and palm. Shi casually flexed hir talons.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi snuffled at the top of his head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m definitely open to twiddling with the intensity dial. Calling me by
kink titles on the regular is a good place to start, even though I do
have small hang-ups about it. Easy to turn the dial up or down from
there. I like things like that, where you can adjust the intensity real
easy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, totally. So I&rsquo;ll call you Mistress, like, casually?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That, that&rsquo;s actually the hang-up right there. A bunch of gendered
titles don&rsquo;t <em>quite</em> work for me just because gendered, and then there&rsquo;s
also stuff about them that&rsquo;s more to do with my particular hang-ups.
Without going into the whole thing right this moment — please call me
<em>Owner</em>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He nodded solemnly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you for expressing that clearly, Owner; I&rsquo;ll do that.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Flexing hir talons, shi gently scritched his chin.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good puppy. You can call me that casually, at your discretion. Once in
a while I&rsquo;ll prompt you. And are there particular terms for you I should
use or avoid using?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Can you call me your boyfriend?&rdquo; he asked shyly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I can definitely do that.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He squeezed himself against hir, hugging hir arm, half climbing into hir
lap. Shi helped him the rest of the way, wrapping hir arms around him
protectively. He burrowed against hir, nudging the top of his head
against the furry fringe on hir jaw, kissing the scales on hir throat.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Please do that.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem, cute boyfriend yeen.&rdquo;</p>

<div style="text-align:center">* * *</div>


<p><span>Faije</span> was blindfolded and draped over <span>Darja</span>&rsquo;s
lap, face-down on the couch, wrists unbound but folded behind his back
again. <span>Darja</span> caressed his ass with one hand, lazily
spanking him, watching his rump jiggle and his anus quiver around the
thick toy in it.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pretty sissyspots,&rdquo; he cooed. &ldquo;You are coming along with your training
so well, you&rsquo;ve got such a charming, easily-gaped boi-pussy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you,&rdquo; he groaned.</p>

<p><span>Darja</span> reached down and gently squeezed his balls, hand
wrapping around the other hyena&rsquo;s scrotum.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Mmmm. Bet you can&rsquo;t wait for someone big and virile to come along and
relieve you of these,&rdquo; he said in a slow, sing-song voice. &ldquo;Bet you
can&rsquo;t wait for us to be hypnotized bitches together, shooting blanks for
a potent Master.&rdquo; <span>Faije</span> whimpered. <span>Darja</span>
leaned down and nipped his scruff gently. &ldquo;Gonna be lovely to fuck you
once you&rsquo;re properly sissified,&rdquo; he crooned. &ldquo;Kiss you, rub my chest
against yours, grind our empty sheaths together. Tell each other what we
taste when we&rsquo;re swallowing Master&rsquo;s dick.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;God yes. Working his dick over together, getting tongues and lips all
over it, kissing around it.&rdquo; &ldquo;Three-way makeouts between you, me, and a
massive slab of cock.&rdquo; &ldquo;Drinking from a bowl of jizz together.&rdquo;
&ldquo;Tongue-cleaning it off each other&rsquo;s faces.&rdquo; &ldquo;Bent over side by side,
tails up, showing off our puffy, perma-gaped assholes.&rdquo; &ldquo;Kneeling side
by side, gagging on monster cocks together, just able to see each other
right in the corner of the eye, hear each other&rsquo;s voices as they
throat-fuck us all rough and savage.&rdquo; <span>Darja</span> rubbed along
his perineum firmly and slowly, fingertips sliding back and forth from
the base of the toy to his scrotum and back. With his other hand, he
added slow, rough spanks, prompting moans from <span>Faije</span>, the
intact hyena relaxing further and further.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hnnnnffff. Do you have anyone in mind to come collar us both and make
us his bitches?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Not really. I might bail for a while and look for one for myself.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Wait, what? What the hell?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I kinda need that? I need a dom. I like what we&rsquo;ve got, but no, I don&rsquo;t
really want to settle down in this kind of relationship, I want to have
this kind of thing on the side or have some kind of poly thing going
that includes this. You know, like we spend a lot of time talking
about.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Faije</span> brought his arms around, leaned on his elbows, and
covered his face with his hands.</p>

<p>&ldquo;No, that is <em>not</em> what I thought we were talking about,&rdquo; he snapped. &ldquo;I
thought we talk about mutual-sub stuff as, like, a pleasant thing that
could happen but if it doesn&rsquo;t we keep doing what we&rsquo;re doing and that&rsquo;s
chill.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well&hellip; no.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He turned, weight on one arm, glaring at <span>Darja</span>, and found
him glaring back indignantly.</p>

<div style="text-align:center">* * *</div>


<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t hear that title a lot, though,&rdquo; he admitted, &ldquo;so I&rsquo;m gonna ask
you to expand on it even though I&rsquo;ve got a guess. What does &lsquo;Owner&rsquo; mean
to you?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi leaned back in hir chair, still holding him against hirself, staring
into space contemplatively. Their aprons were hung over the chair&rsquo;s
back, leaving their bodies pressed warmly together.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s actually a really good question. Is it okay if I just kinda
wander around and poke at it for a while?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Go for it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I will. So. Part of why I like Owner/pet as a relationship model is
that it&rsquo;s possible to do badly at it. Or to do well, since they go
together. With no hate towards people who are making it work for them —
it&rsquo;s a lot trickier to talk about being bad at, like, Mistress/slave
stuff, that kind of relationship. It&rsquo;s modeled on a coercive power
relationship that you can&rsquo;t really be good or bad at. When I say you&rsquo;re
my pet, though, people have an image in their head of people being good
or bad at that. Being good at it means less fear and coercion and more
training and affection.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Faije</span> nodded, making himself comfortable in hir lap,
sighing as hir heavy hand slid down his back from time to time.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Plus it implies, like, this back-and-forth. You&rsquo;re not disposable to
me. I care about you; I care a lot about you. The way some people do it,
caring about your sub, being invested in them, having intense emotions
about them that you can&rsquo;t necessarily control, is an intolerable form of
vulnerability. That vulnerability is what makes the whole thing click
for me, though. What I get out of that vulnerability — which, shit, it&rsquo;s
uncomfortable because that&rsquo;s just inherent in vulnerability — what I get
out of it is a feeling of being secure in owning you. I have plenty of
intense emotions about you and I can&rsquo;t necessarily control them. I
<em>crave</em> to own you, to collar you, to have you kneeling and kissing my
hands. You can see how much I want you, see my desire to make you a
happy, treasured pet. That&rsquo;s a form of control you have over me, and
yeah, someone really hardcore might find that unacceptable. For me,
though, it gives me a secure, meaningful sense of owning you that I
can&rsquo;t get by being aloof.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I could do some of that right now,&rdquo; he suggested. &ldquo;I like kissing your
hands, noticing how you can just wrap your whole hand around my muzzle.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi laughed gently, wrapping one hand over his muzzle for a moment.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Let me think through this, spottybitch boyfriend.&rdquo; He kissed hir palm
and nodded, his ears perking up attentively as shi continued. &ldquo;I want to
own you — and particularly, I want to own you <em>at your best</em>. I want you
to be improved by being my pet; I want to support you as you build
yourself. I crave to have my collar around your most fully realized,
happiest self. On top of wanting that for its own sake, just because
you&rsquo;re a person and you deserve self-actualization, I trust that that
version of you is still interested in being my pet, and I know that if
you <em>are</em> that self, you can feel safe and happy in being owned because
your life is in good order, you have your needs met.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh,&rdquo; he said quietly, palms on hir biceps. &ldquo;Oh, huh. I&rsquo;m&hellip; not used to
that.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi nodded, touching noses with him.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You see how it kinda loops around. When things reach that point, I get
to have this really amazing confidence and security in things. I get to
have the comfort of feeling like I&rsquo;m doing a good job and the dom-thrill
of &lsquo;my pet is loyal to me and earnestly, of their own will, wants to
make me happy and be a good pet for me&rsquo;. For me, the coercive-model
relationships fall apart because of not having that. There&rsquo;s this fear
of, what if I&rsquo;m actually fucking with them and not realizing it, or what
if they&rsquo;re not into it and just going through the motions. I think that
comes from trying to not have an emotional investment in someone you&rsquo;re
in a relationship with. You can&rsquo;t get that stuff for free, you can&rsquo;t get
a loyal, adoring, eager sub for free. You have to go through the
vulnerability, you have to invest yourself.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He knocked his knuckles on hir shoulder lightly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Is that why you don&rsquo;t like calling me slurs?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pretty much. Even in-scene, I don&rsquo;t want to say something with the
subtext of &lsquo;you don&rsquo;t matter to me, you&rsquo;re disposable&rsquo; — it clashes hard
with this stuff I&rsquo;m telling you about. I need to tell you that you&rsquo;re
valued as a pet. Which is why stuff like &lsquo;fag princess&rsquo; is completely
fine.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I think I get it.&rdquo; He nodded, then frowned and looked up. &ldquo;Wait, you&rsquo;re
talking like you <em>had</em> a relationship where this was going on. Why
aren&rsquo;t you still in that one?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi jerked hir head back, flinching and looking away. Hir hands withdrew
in a jerky motion, and shi crossed them over hir chest. A tight-lipped
scowl followed.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Remember, a few minutes ago, I said I&rsquo;d fucked up a lot?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He slowly winced.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah?&rdquo;</p>

<p>A pause. Shi inhaled, then shook hir head, then spoke.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He gingerly touched hir shoulder with his fingertips.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Do you want me to go clean up the dishes?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hir jaw tensed visibly, then relaxed. A sigh.</p>

<p>&ldquo;No. Just, please let it be okay to not explain my fuck-ups right this
moment?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It is okay to not explain your fuck-ups right this moment,&rdquo; he repeated
back.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you.&rdquo; Shi turned hir face back towards him, grimacing, unfolding
hir arms, making a sad laugh. &ldquo;Did I mention that vulnerability is
really difficult?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s really, really difficult,&rdquo; he concurred.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Most days I do okay at believing that I might be able to build
something like that again — that I haven&rsquo;t permanently fucked up.&rdquo; Shi
leaned forward, hir hands on his thighs, licking his muzzle. &ldquo;Trying to
build something like that with you sounds really good. Could we do
that?&rdquo;</p>

<p>His tail lifted and wagged for a moment, and he smiled shyly. He put his
hands on top of hirs, squeezing gently, leaning forward to nuzzle into
hir licks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It does sound really good. I&rsquo;d really like to be my best sissy-bitch
self for you. For my Owner.&rdquo;</p>

<div style="text-align:center">* * *</div>


<p>He was panting, sniffling, crying a little. Hir huge hand cupped his
head, hir thumb rubbing one ear. Shi leaned in and spoke quietly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Need a break?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He leaned into hir touch, closing his eyes and taking deep breaths.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Slow down for a bit?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi pushed hirself up again, shifting forward on hir knees to give him
some slack in the short chains connecting his wrist-cuffs to the bed&rsquo;s
headboard. Hir prick flopped down on top of his, drooling in spurts onto
his belly-fluff. Shi lifted his legs, caressed his stockings, and smiled
archly at him.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Look at that. Fat, heavy draconic dick lying over yours and just
<em>erasing</em> it. Like that little sissy stub isn&rsquo;t even there anymore.&rdquo;</p>

<p>His legs quivered under hir hands, tensing and relaxing.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Goes to show how you just need a proper cock to wrap that lovely tongue
of yours around, doesn&rsquo;t it, princess?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Please!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi rocked back and forth, pressing heavy, scaly, twitching nuts against
his rump as hir cock dribbled sticky precum, flexing in the air with hir
heartbeat. Hir talons dug into him through the stockings, dense and
black against the pink fabric.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Or spreading that charmingly fuckable asshole of yours.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pleeeeease&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh? Is that the sound of sissy-yeen needing a powerful dracotiger knot
<em>conquering</em> his asshole?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Please yes, please Owner, tame my asshole, conquer me, bitchify me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Gosh, all that after you&rsquo;ve just been <em>guzzling</em> down my cock and
showing off how it makes your throat bulge? You <em>are</em> a greedy little
bitch-yeen. No wonder I like you so much.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi reached down and rubbed hir fingertips over the spearhead tip of hir
cock, a strand of precum briefly following hir hand as it rose again.
Shi made eye contact as shi reached for <span>Faije</span>, raising hir
eyebrows curiously. He nodded firmly, then closed his eyes as shi wiped
hir precum across his nose with the pad of hir thumb.
<span>Chaiax</span> smiled hungrily as he shivered, hir lips pulling
back from hir fangs.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Owner marks me,&rdquo; he whimpered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s right,&rdquo; shi purred. &ldquo;Marking my treasured bitch-princess yeen.
Letting my scent march right into that nose of his and remind him how
much he needs my cum.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I need your cum, Owner,&rdquo; he repeated, nodding.</p>

<p>Shi leaned back, pushing on his legs, one hand on hir cock. Adjusting,
shi slid hirself down, head pressing against his asshole, feeling it
quiver.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Need it bad?&rdquo; shi growled.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Need it so, so bad,&rdquo; he groaned. &ldquo;Please, Owner. Please. Fuck me, make
me your impotent sissy, use me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi leaned into him, one hand on the bed beside him, making eye contact
as shi eased heavy, unwieldly, monstrous dracotiger cock into his
asshole. His lips quivered and his eyes widened as shi caught his
attention.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Just what you need,&rdquo; shi whispered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Just what I need.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A potent Owner.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A potent Owner — god, so potent, <em>please</em> Owner&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>An abrupt shove, a snarl. <span>Faije</span> squealed, his toes
spreading in the air. Hir cock was deep enough into him to remove hir
hand, now on his head, digging fingers into his short shock of hair,
pulling roughly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;To tame you like you need.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Tame me like I need! I need to be tamed!&rdquo;</p>

<p>With a snarl, shi broke eye contact, leaning in and biting the side of
his neck. Short, sharp thrusts pushed curved, ridged, knotted dracotiger
cock deep into him, hir sheath folding back as shi hilted in him. Hir
hands scooped under him, claws digging into his back and making him
howl. With hir head getting in the way of his looking down, all he could
see were hir thick, curved horns moving as shi bit and kissed his neck.
His legs kicked idly in the air. <span>Chaiax</span> groaned happily,
savoring the squeeze of his asshole far down hir cock, the soft, sloppy
warmth deeper inside him, the feel of hir unswollen knot teasing him.
After a minute, shi raised hir head and growled, whiskers brushing the
side of his head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It makes you want to <em>surrender</em>, doesn&rsquo;t it? Surrender to that huge,
hungry predator cock inside you. You&rsquo;ve always known you ought to be an
impotent, blanks-shooting sissy bitch. I bet you can&rsquo;t keep yourself
from imagining shrinking as I push into you — every inch of penetration
taking some size off of you as you feel that predator cock sinking in,
deeper and deeper, blatantly huge and potent, so clearly the kind of
cock that makes yours disposable.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He closed his eyes tight and nodded, his ass quivering around hir as he
listened. Hir tongue, long and rough, caressed around his ear.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m a sissy,&rdquo; he groaned. &ldquo;Owner&rsquo;s cock is all that matters. I should
be an <em>impotent</em> sissy, presenting my asshole and my empty sheath for
Owner.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi watched him focus on the image, hir eyes alight with hunger.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Soon,&rdquo; shi growled. &ldquo;Rrrrrrrhhhhhhrrrr. You&rsquo;re <em>such</em> a good
bitch-yeen, such a good sissy-toy. Soon we&rsquo;ll train you to feel those
poor nuts shrinking when you&rsquo;re in the presence of ultra-virile
dracotiger nuts. Teach you what it feels like to have your cock
shrinking, recognizing before you do that you&rsquo;re in the presence of
someone with real potency.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He squealed at the suggestion, his thighs pressing against hir sides,
his paws jerking in the air. Shi began to rut him again, putting hir
weight on him, taloned toes digging into the bed with hir thrusts.
Despite the words, his prick was a mess of thin, drooly precum, smearing
it all over hir belly&rsquo;s scales as shi pressed down onto him. Shi threw
hirself into the frantic, bestial fucking for longer than the first
time, then pushed hirself up again, huffing, hir shoulders shaking with
adrenaline.</p>

<p>Shi made eye contact again, a flourishing gesture commanding his
attention. Shi reached down with one huge paw, wrapping it around his
prick, squeezing lightly. Hir other held his chin, commanding his gaze.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Not just imagining yourself shrinking with penetration,&rdquo; shi rumbled,
&ldquo;imagining yourself helpless to keep what you&rsquo;ve got, shrinking as you
get closer and closer to climax. Do you want to climax for Owner,
sissy-pet?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Please yes, please Owner, climax for you,&rdquo; he moaned.</p>

<p>Hir hand moved steadily on his prick as shi leaned back, finding a
favorable angle for slow, steady thrusts into him.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You want to climax for Owner, even though you know you&rsquo;re going to have
nothing but a nub?&rdquo; shi taunted.</p>

<p>He practically sobbed, his arms waving, jerked back by the cuffs. &ldquo;I
want to climax for Owner! I want to be Owner&rsquo;s sissy-fag pet!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You want to climax for Owner,&rdquo; shi growled, &ldquo;even as you feel yourself
shrinking, softening, surrendering.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi flexed hir tail smugly at his squealing, babbling pleas, hir hand
moving on his prick and steadily picking up speed. He kicked from time
to time, arching his back, pressing up against hir touch. Between
thrusts, shi rubbed his belly. In hisses, shi reminded him of surrender,
of impotence, of how overwhelming dracotiger cock was compared to his.</p>

<p>Arching his back and yipping in a quick, high cadence, he came all over
hir hand and his own belly, his eyes still closed, his chest heaving.
With a huff of effort, shi pulled out of him, then leaned in, hand on
hir own cock as shi stared into his eyes. The panting, dazed hyena
whimpered at hir, his eyes not quite focusing, his jaw hanging open.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<strong>Mine</strong>,&rdquo; shi growled.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yours!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;My owned, precious bitch-yeen.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yours, please, hff, Owner!&rdquo;</p>

<p>He squirmed under hir, feeling hir hand moving more quickly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;My owned, tamed, <em>impotent</em> sissy-yeen.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yours, owned, tamed, impotent!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hir panting kept hir from starting another sentence — shi grimaced,
hunched, then roared as shi straightened up, shoulders back, legs
tensed. Hir cock erupted, delivering jet after jet of thick, heavy, rich
spunk to splatter onto the hyena. Shi started with his belly, lingering
there to erase his efforts, then left ribbons of dracotiger sperm on his
chest, finally a few on his face, one drooling from the side of his
muzzle as he whimpered.</p>

<p>Shi panted for a moment, grinning smugly at him. He nodded briefly, eyes
wide, whimpering happily.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Where&rsquo;s your cum, sissy-yeen?&rdquo; shi asked. &ldquo;You made some really cute
noises there; I&rsquo;m pretty sure you came. Did you climax for me like a
good spottybitch?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I did, Owner. I came for you.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He fidgeted, thighs rubbing against hir, as shi smirked.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh? But there certainly isn&rsquo;t any hyena cum here, is there?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Shi dragged hir forefinger across his belly, then presented it, wet and
gooey, to his lips. As he sucked on it, wrapping his tongue around it
eagerly, shi posed another question.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course, there wouldn&rsquo;t be if you&rsquo;re a blanks-shooting sissy-yeen.
It&rsquo;d just be gone, wouldn&rsquo;t it? It&rsquo;d just be erased by all that heavy,
powerful cum from your Owner.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The vibration of his groan was easy to feel around hir finger. With hir
other hand, shi reached around, talons digging into his scruff. Slurping
off of hir finger, he panted, nodding shallowly. Shi coaxed him up,
smiling.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Spottypet. Is there anything you&rsquo;d like to say?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you, Owner,&rdquo; he moaned, shaking.</p>

<p>The thanking continued until well after shi untied him and laid with
him, holding him against hirself while adrenaline left his system,
feeling him shiver, hearing his happy crooning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NaNoWriMo 2016, #1: The Village It Takes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-01-the-village-it-takes/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-04T16:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-01-the-village-it-takes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am, taking on a November writing project again.
If you haven&rsquo;t seen me do this before, here&rsquo;s what I do.
I don&rsquo;t have a novel in me right now, so for NaNoWriMo I just do as many short stories as I can.
I use the social momentum and recognition of NaNoWriMo to push myself to spend a lot of time writing and to explain to others what I&rsquo;m doing.
As with the novels people produce during NaNo, I try to be very forgiving towards myself and my work; it is okay to just drop an idea when I get stuck and move on to the next story.
It&rsquo;s been working out very well so far: here&rsquo;s the first one for this year.</p>

<!--more-->


<hr />

<p>&ldquo;Hey. Hey, hey. Mommo. What&rsquo;s that? That&rsquo;s not orange juice.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> crouched, then jumped up, catching her mother&rsquo;s
dress in little hands and huffing as she began to climb.
<span>Myrtle</span> casually reached around with one hand, nudging her
cub upwards.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s a martini, honey. Not for kittens.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Why?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> laughed quietly, her martini glass clinking as she
set it down on the sun-warmed glass tabletop amid a few bottles, a large
carafe of juice, and a half-shrinkwrapped cluster of juice boxes.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I see someone&rsquo;s discovered &lsquo;why,&rsquo; haven&rsquo;t they.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A couple weeks ago, actually.&rdquo; She turned her head back to the small
lion. &ldquo;Martinis are difficult, kitten.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> hauled herself up to <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s shoulder,
leaning over it, her chest on the lioness' wide shoulder, one paw on her
collarbone, the other waving towards <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s martini.
<span>Myrtle</span> reached up with her free hand, rubbing
<span>Rynher</span>&rsquo;s head and giving her a few fond licks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Whyyyyyyy are they difficult?&rdquo; <span>Rynher</span> asked, her toeclaws
digging into the back of <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s dress as she headbutted
her mother&rsquo;s jaw.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Because they&rsquo;re complicated,&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> replied, sipping
her own. &ldquo;Would you like me to tell you about how they&rsquo;re complicated?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> wiggled for a moment, dark-tipped tail flicking.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yes please!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Polite kitten!&rdquo; The tigress beamed, leaning forward, elbows on the
table. &ldquo;Okay. Martinis have a lot of alcohol in them. Alcohol has good
and bad things in it. The bad things depend on how big your body is:
they spread out more in bigger people&rsquo;s bodies. Your mom and I are big
cats, so we can drink some alcohol and we get the good parts with only a
little bit of the bad parts. If <em>you</em> drank alcohol, you&rsquo;d get some good
parts, but because you&rsquo;re a small cat, you&rsquo;d get a lot of the bad parts
like losing your sense of balance, throwing up, and headaches. It would
not be fun, and it might hurt you badly. So that&rsquo;s why alcohol is okay
for big cats and not okay for small cats.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> put her own glass down as the explanation proceeded,
keeping one hand on <span>Rynher</span>&rsquo;s back to steady her. She
extracted a juice box from the clump, speared its straw in, and lifted
it for <span>Rynher</span>, who squealed happily, putting both paws
forward for it.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Do you understand that, kitten?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yuh-huh!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What do you say?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She turned to <span>Arabella</span>.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you Miss <span>Arabella</span>!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good kitten.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> took the juice box in both hands and sucked on its
straw happily. <span>Myrtle</span> made eye contact with
<span>Arabella</span>, pointing briefly up at her cub, then away.
<span>Arabella</span> nodded, stood, and came around behind her: she
gently put both hands on <span>Rynher</span>, picked her up, extracted
her toeclaws, and put her down on the patio. She scampered away, both
adults grinning after her.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thanks for the save.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem. Mine are just getting there too. <span>Cam</span>&rsquo;s better
at the &lsquo;why&rsquo; game than I am, but I&rsquo;m okay at it. Probably goes with his
job.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh yeah — how&rsquo;s his quest for tenure going?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> rolled her eyes and shook her head.
<span>Myrtle</span> raised her eyebrows curiously, then turned away,
craning her neck to get a look at the four kittens as
<span>Rynher</span> rejoined the other three, splashing around in the
swimming pool across the yard.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That bad, huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;d rather not get into it, and honestly I think you shouldn&rsquo;t mention
it to him today either. He&rsquo;s focusing on making us lunch right now, and
after that he&rsquo;s gonna shut himself in the bedroom with a couple of
dildos for stress-relief time.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You think he&rsquo;ll want company?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Ask him, not me. But if I had to guess, I&rsquo;d say he&rsquo;ll want the kind of
company that can top the hell out of him. The kittens had a cold
recently, so of course we both got it, and that pushed things to an even
lower level than normal. So your odds are pretty good.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cool. I might go for that. You okay soloing all four of the kids for a
while? I imagine <span>Lilwen</span> is gonna have her hands full
already.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, I&rsquo;ll be fine. After pool time and lunch they should all be a bit
tired anyhow; I&rsquo;ll throw some pillows on the trampoline and have them
all make a nest.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Great. Thanks babe.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> leaned over and kissed the side of her muzzle.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Save some of him for me, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p>They laughed together, then picked up their glasses and sipped in
unison. At the sound of a sliding door, they turned, then grinned
widely.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Lilwen</span>!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Heyyyy!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Welcome welcome!&rdquo;</p>

<p>The leopard stepped through the door gingerly, <span>Campbell</span> ushering
her out. In a sling against her chest she held a little bundle, a tiny paw
reaching out of it and batting slowly at her bosom. <span>Arabella</span> and
<span>Myrtle</span> rose together, smiling widely, coming to meet her.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How&rsquo;ve you <em>been</em>, babe?&rdquo; She made a resigned smile as she carefully
hugged them.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Really tired, basically all of the time. I thought I was gonna be done
after, you know, birth, but the whole thing is <em>still</em> kicking my ass.
Thanks again for setting this up for me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course! This stuff&rsquo;s really difficult. We just wanted to make time
for you to sit down and have a breather.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And to get introduced to the
itty-bitty one, of course.&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> pulled a grin out,
standing up straighter, ears perking.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Her name&rsquo;s <span>Sinavena</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And what a fine little thing <span>Sinavena</span> is!&rdquo; Arabella leaned
in, wiggling her fingers gently at the bundled-up, grey-furred cub.
&ldquo;Hey little terror. How you feelin' today?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Diminutive paws waved at her fingers eagerly, accompanied by high,
squeaky mews.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pretty fierce for all of, what, three and a half weeks?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shit, most days she&rsquo;s got more energy than I do.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh, that reminds me —&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> straightened up, beckoning to <span>Lilwen</span> with a
wave over her shoulder as she returned to the table. She picked up a tall
shopping bag, turned around, then chuckled and smiled patiently as she saw
<span>Lilwen</span> and <span>Myrtle</span> sharing a slow kiss,
<span>Myrtle</span> leaning over the leopardess' shoulder while kneading her
shoulders firmly. When they finished, <span>Arabella</span> stepped forward,
eyebrows raised expectantly. <span>Lilwen</span> shrugged at her, rocking her
cub demonstratively.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Be my hands for a minute?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem.&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span> stepped forward, taking the bag and
holding it open for the tigress, who reached into it. She withdrew a
dark blue dress with a flourish, shaking it out to unfold it, holding it
by the collar as she gestured to the its palm-wide grey stripes that
fell from shoulders to hips to knees.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course <span>Sinavena</span> won&rsquo;t be climbing age for a while yet,
but she&rsquo;ll get there quicker than you think. Probably quicker than mine
— <span>Teruleth</span>&rsquo;s not much of a climber. Not as active as I&rsquo;d
like at all, really: I have to encourage him to swim, too. But
<span>Gadayra</span> is just up and down and up and down all day, she&rsquo;s
the fittest little thing.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No wonder you learned to make these
yourself. It&rsquo;s so nice!&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> reached out with one hand,
rubbing the thick cloth between forefinger and thumb.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, it&rsquo;ll have little pawprints all over it soon enough, but that&rsquo;s
its own kind of nice.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, it&rsquo;s one of those things where if it looks
pristine, that&rsquo;s not good.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And little <span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s gonna
have strong claws to dig into it soon, isn&rsquo;t she?&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span>
leaned over as she raised the question, presenting her own fingers for
<span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s inquisitive paws. The kitten grabbed eagerly at
her, then chewed on the presented fingers with stubby little milk-fangs.
An indulgent smile met the chewing.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Soon, but hopefully not quite yet. I want her claws in the dress, not
in my tits.&rdquo;</p>

<p>They laughed together, returning to the table.</p>

<p>&ldquo;So — congratulations! Welcome back. Super happy for you.&rdquo;
<span>Arabella</span> beamed at <span>Lilwen</span>, raising her glass
in a toast as she leaned back. &ldquo;Okay if I throw a nosy question at you?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Go for it.&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> shifted her sling, coaxing the kitten
towards her breast, hand gently holding the back of her grey-furred
head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How&rsquo;d the perineal massage work out?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> snort-laughed indelicately, splashing some of her
martini on her face, then holding her hand over her muzzle as she
snickered. <span>Lilwen</span> chuckled, her ears flicking, guiding the
kitten&rsquo;s paws towards herself with one finger.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I mean, I don&rsquo;t have a lot of basis for comparison. I haven&rsquo;t tried
having a kid without it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Did it feel like it helped?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, it felt like — let me put it this
way, I have <em>zero</em> questions left about what I can take. I&rsquo;m like, okay,
I got her out, smaller stuff I&rsquo;ll be fine with.&rdquo; They laughed together,
and <span>Lilwen</span> leaned back in her chair, sighing. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m still
pretty sore, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> nodded sympathetically. &ldquo;Yup. Took a full month for
me before I could sit down to piss comfortably.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Worth it,&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> opined, jabbing her forefinger
emphatically.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hell yeah, worth it. But you and I are saying that with the benefit of
a few years already behind us to get used to it.&rdquo; She nodded towards the
leopard. &ldquo;Give her a while before the evangelizing, huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not evangelizing.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Arabella</span>, honey, I have known you for a solid ten years. I
don&rsquo;t doubt your politics at all, but you were always kinda pretty het
compared to the rest of us, you were always really clear that you wanted
kids.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh come on. I sucked a lot of dick in college, which is emphatically
not the same thing, and then I settled down and married a nice girl. I
ended up with a husband and that&rsquo;s working out great, but come on, I was
never <em>that</em> het. That&rsquo;s actually a thing that makes me and
<span>Cam</span> uncomfortable sometimes: we look really het at events
compared to you and <span>Iris</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Lilwen</span> gave <span>Arabella</span> a puzzled look. &ldquo;Didn&rsquo;t
know you&rsquo;d had another marriage before <span>Cam</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I hadn&rsquo;t.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A high, sustained, squeal-yowl interrupted them, along with a chorus of
&ldquo;Mom!&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> swore, lunging up, her chair clattering over
backwards, glass falling onto the table. She dashed towards the pool,
hands pulling her dress open. <span>Myrtle</span> grabbed
<span>Lilwen</span>&rsquo;s shoulder hard as she soothed
<span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s upset at the noises.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You: chill. We&rsquo;ll handle it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She rose and briskly jogged after the tigress, turning aside to come
through the gate in the low fence that <span>Arabella</span> had simply
vaulted directly over, leaving her heavy dress behind. There was a brief
splash as she dove into the pool headlong, submerging as she moved
towards the splashing, thrashing kitten on the other side.
<span>Myrtle</span> forced herself to move slowly on the wet concrete
around the pool, approaching <span>Rynher</span>, <span>Terandil</span>,
and <span>Gadayra</span> as they huddled worriedly in a knot. She fell
to a crouch and her hands shot out, grabbing the two smallest ones by
their scruffs, her head dipping to pick up the remaining cub by her
teeth.</p>

<p>Turning around and putting them down again, she growled, fangs bared
demonstratively. &ldquo;<strong>Stay here</strong>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She heard a wet splat and wheezy coughs as she turned around.
<span>Arabella</span> had dove under the kitten in the pool and lifted
him out by rising directly under him, her head and one hand shoving him
up out of the water. He curled up on his side, shaking as he coughed.
The tigress rose from the pool, dripping all over, panting. She nodded
wearily as the kitten cried, sitting down cross-legged and holding him
against her chest.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shhhh. It&rsquo;s okay, <span>Ruru</span>. Mom&rsquo;s here. I got you. Keep
breathing. You&rsquo;re gonna be okay.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He clung to her as <span>Myrtle</span> ushered the other three away,
herding two of them and carrying the third in one arm. When she returned
to the table, <span>Campbell</span> was there with <span>Lilwen</span>,
frowning in concern.</p>

<p>&ldquo;What happened?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> coaxed the trio onto a bench together and chuffed
encouragingly at them as she distributed juice boxes and thin, soft
strips of jerky.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Ruru</span> fell in,&rdquo; <span>Terandil</span> volunteered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Uh-huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And he fell in the deep part, he was scared.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> stood on his tiptoes to get a look at the pool,
then visibly relaxed, nodding and prompting the kittens to continue with
a wave. They looked back and forth among themselves, recounting it
slowly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;He was trying to climb out.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We tried to help him.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He couldn&rsquo;t grab hands.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And I was telling people not to fall in more,&rdquo; <span>Gadayra</span>
piped up.</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> dragged out a smile. &ldquo;Oh yeah? Being a clever
kitten and remembering the rules?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah!&rdquo;</p>

<p>He stepped forward to kiss the top of <span>Gadayra</span>&rsquo;s head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good job, <span>Gada</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> looked expectantly at the three of them. &ldquo;Everyone
remembers that rule, right?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You can&rsquo;t help someone out if you fall in,&rdquo; they chorused, nodding.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good job!&rdquo; <span>Campbell</span> nodded firmly. &ldquo;You kept that in mind
and made it so Mom could come and help. That was the right thing to do.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> returned, holding <span>Teruleth</span> with both
hands, curled up with his arms around her neck. She wrapped
<span>Teruleth</span> in a dry towel, then sat down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Okay. <em>Okay</em>. Emergency over.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> draped a towel over her shoulders in turn, leaning
down for fretful licks and cheek-rubs. She leaned up to kiss him
briefly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Ruru</span> fell in and got scared. He&rsquo;s okay now.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> spoke up.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Kids, please go grab blankets and pillows from the closet and set them
up on the trampoline, okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The kittens nodded and trotted off, <span>Campbell</span> following them
after a nod from <span>Arabella</span>. <span>Myrtle</span> sat down
beside her, stroking her back up and down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You doing okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Give me a few minutes for my heart rate to settle down. I&rsquo;m just glad
this guy&rsquo;s okay.&rdquo; She nuzzled down at <span>Teruleth</span>, who made a
quiet, shaky mew and hid his head under her chin. &ldquo;You&rsquo;re gonna be
okay,&rdquo; she repeated to him. &ldquo;You forgot to be careful for a minute, but
now you&rsquo;re okay, and you can learn to be more careful. Everyone forgets
sometimes; that&rsquo;s why we practice things. So we&rsquo;re gonna practice that
again later, carefully, so you don&rsquo;t have to be scared like that again.
Okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The small tiger nodded, still curled up against her. She gave him a warm
squeeze.</p>

<p>&ldquo;And right now we&rsquo;re all gonna have a nice lunch together and you&rsquo;re
gonna take a nap in the blanket fort with <span>Gada</span>,
<span>Tern</span>, and <span>Rynnie</span>. How&rsquo;s that sound?&rdquo; Another
nod, slightly more energetic. <span>Arabella</span> carefully put him
down, draping the towel over his shoulders like a cape. &ldquo;Good. Okay: go
help <span>Gada</span> with putting the blanket fort together, all
right?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;All right.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He trotted off with increasing steadiness, and <span>Arabella</span>
slumped in her chair, putting her hands over her face.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Criminy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You keep breathing too, babe,&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span> said, coming around
behind her and rubbing her shoulders.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, that looked like three quarters of a heart attack,&rdquo;
<span>Lilwen</span> concurred.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Maybe just one quarter of a heart attack, but yeah.&rdquo; She chuckled
ruefully. &ldquo;What I got from him was that they were roughhousing, he
tripped and fell into the pool, swallowed some water, and panicked. So
once I got him out, he was fine, just shaken.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Honestly, you look more shaken than he does.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I probably am: <em>I&rsquo;m</em> old enough to be fuckin' terrified of mortality —
especially my kids' mortality.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Lilwen</span> grimaced. &ldquo;Yeah, that&rsquo;s reasonable. I had that scare
at six months, I was telling you about the one set of ultrasounds.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That was pretty horrible.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Right, and until they figured out what was actually happening, I was a
wreck. So I feel you on that.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> leaned forward over <span>Arabella</span>&rsquo;s
shoulder.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How about I drag out the air mattress and the three of us just cuddle
on that out here while the kids are napping?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That sounds like a good plan, yeah.&rdquo; She smiled at <span>Lilwen</span>.
&ldquo;Plus it&rsquo;ll let us fuss over you for a while — you sure look like you
need it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am completely okay with this plan,&rdquo; she laughed.</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> returned, and they cleared space on the table for
the tray he carried, called the kittens for lunch, and all sat down
together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
