<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: napowrimo | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/napowrimo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-08T02:11:27-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NaNoWriMo 2016, #1: The Village It Takes]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-01-the-village-it-takes/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-04T16:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-01-the-village-it-takes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am, taking on a November writing project again.
If you haven&rsquo;t seen me do this before, here&rsquo;s what I do.
I don&rsquo;t have a novel in me right now, so for NaNoWriMo I just do as many short stories as I can.
I use the social momentum and recognition of NaNoWriMo to push myself to spend a lot of time writing and to explain to others what I&rsquo;m doing.
As with the novels people produce during NaNo, I try to be very forgiving towards myself and my work; it is okay to just drop an idea when I get stuck and move on to the next story.
It&rsquo;s been working out very well so far: here&rsquo;s the first one for this year.</p>

<!--more-->


<hr />

<p>&ldquo;Hey. Hey, hey. Mommo. What&rsquo;s that? That&rsquo;s not orange juice.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> crouched, then jumped up, catching her mother&rsquo;s
dress in little hands and huffing as she began to climb.
<span>Myrtle</span> casually reached around with one hand, nudging her
cub upwards.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s a martini, honey. Not for kittens.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Why?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> laughed quietly, her martini glass clinking as she
set it down on the sun-warmed glass tabletop amid a few bottles, a large
carafe of juice, and a half-shrinkwrapped cluster of juice boxes.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I see someone&rsquo;s discovered &lsquo;why,&rsquo; haven&rsquo;t they.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A couple weeks ago, actually.&rdquo; She turned her head back to the small
lion. &ldquo;Martinis are difficult, kitten.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> hauled herself up to <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s shoulder,
leaning over it, her chest on the lioness' wide shoulder, one paw on her
collarbone, the other waving towards <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s martini.
<span>Myrtle</span> reached up with her free hand, rubbing
<span>Rynher</span>&rsquo;s head and giving her a few fond licks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Whyyyyyyy are they difficult?&rdquo; <span>Rynher</span> asked, her toeclaws
digging into the back of <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s dress as she headbutted
her mother&rsquo;s jaw.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Because they&rsquo;re complicated,&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> replied, sipping
her own. &ldquo;Would you like me to tell you about how they&rsquo;re complicated?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> wiggled for a moment, dark-tipped tail flicking.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yes please!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Polite kitten!&rdquo; The tigress beamed, leaning forward, elbows on the
table. &ldquo;Okay. Martinis have a lot of alcohol in them. Alcohol has good
and bad things in it. The bad things depend on how big your body is:
they spread out more in bigger people&rsquo;s bodies. Your mom and I are big
cats, so we can drink some alcohol and we get the good parts with only a
little bit of the bad parts. If <em>you</em> drank alcohol, you&rsquo;d get some good
parts, but because you&rsquo;re a small cat, you&rsquo;d get a lot of the bad parts
like losing your sense of balance, throwing up, and headaches. It would
not be fun, and it might hurt you badly. So that&rsquo;s why alcohol is okay
for big cats and not okay for small cats.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> put her own glass down as the explanation proceeded,
keeping one hand on <span>Rynher</span>&rsquo;s back to steady her. She
extracted a juice box from the clump, speared its straw in, and lifted
it for <span>Rynher</span>, who squealed happily, putting both paws
forward for it.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Do you understand that, kitten?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yuh-huh!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What do you say?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She turned to <span>Arabella</span>.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you Miss <span>Arabella</span>!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good kitten.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> took the juice box in both hands and sucked on its
straw happily. <span>Myrtle</span> made eye contact with
<span>Arabella</span>, pointing briefly up at her cub, then away.
<span>Arabella</span> nodded, stood, and came around behind her: she
gently put both hands on <span>Rynher</span>, picked her up, extracted
her toeclaws, and put her down on the patio. She scampered away, both
adults grinning after her.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thanks for the save.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem. Mine are just getting there too. <span>Cam</span>&rsquo;s better
at the &lsquo;why&rsquo; game than I am, but I&rsquo;m okay at it. Probably goes with his
job.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh yeah — how&rsquo;s his quest for tenure going?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> rolled her eyes and shook her head.
<span>Myrtle</span> raised her eyebrows curiously, then turned away,
craning her neck to get a look at the four kittens as
<span>Rynher</span> rejoined the other three, splashing around in the
swimming pool across the yard.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That bad, huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;d rather not get into it, and honestly I think you shouldn&rsquo;t mention
it to him today either. He&rsquo;s focusing on making us lunch right now, and
after that he&rsquo;s gonna shut himself in the bedroom with a couple of
dildos for stress-relief time.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You think he&rsquo;ll want company?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Ask him, not me. But if I had to guess, I&rsquo;d say he&rsquo;ll want the kind of
company that can top the hell out of him. The kittens had a cold
recently, so of course we both got it, and that pushed things to an even
lower level than normal. So your odds are pretty good.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cool. I might go for that. You okay soloing all four of the kids for a
while? I imagine <span>Lilwen</span> is gonna have her hands full
already.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, I&rsquo;ll be fine. After pool time and lunch they should all be a bit
tired anyhow; I&rsquo;ll throw some pillows on the trampoline and have them
all make a nest.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Great. Thanks babe.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> leaned over and kissed the side of her muzzle.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Save some of him for me, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p>They laughed together, then picked up their glasses and sipped in
unison. At the sound of a sliding door, they turned, then grinned
widely.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Lilwen</span>!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Heyyyy!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Welcome welcome!&rdquo;</p>

<p>The leopard stepped through the door gingerly, <span>Campbell</span> ushering her out. In a sling against her chest she held a little bundle, a tiny paw reaching out of it and batting slowly at her bosom. <span>Arabella</span> and <span>Myrtle</span> rose together, smiling widely, coming to meet her.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How&rsquo;ve you <em>been</em>, babe?&rdquo; She made a resigned smile as she carefully
hugged them.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Really tired, basically all of the time. I thought I was gonna be done
after, you know, birth, but the whole thing is <em>still</em> kicking my ass.
Thanks again for setting this up for me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course! This stuff&rsquo;s really difficult. We just wanted to make time
for you to sit down and have a breather.&rdquo; &ldquo;And to get introduced to the
itty-bitty one, of course.&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> pulled a grin out,
standing up straighter, ears perking.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Her name&rsquo;s <span>Sinavena</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And what a fine little thing <span>Sinavena</span> is!&rdquo;
<span>Arabella</span> leaned in, wiggling her fingers gently at the
bundled-up, grey-furred cub. &ldquo;Hey little terror. How you feelin' today?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Diminutive paws waved at her fingers eagerly, accompanied by high,
squeaky mews.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pretty fierce for all of, what, three and a half weeks?&rdquo; &ldquo;Shit, most
days she&rsquo;s got more energy than I do.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh, that reminds me —&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> straightened up, beckoning
to <span>Lilwen</span> with a wave over her shoulder as she returned to
the table. She picked up a tall shopping bag, turned around, then
chuckled and smiled patiently as she saw <span>Lilwen</span> and
<span>Myrtle</span> sharing a slow kiss, <span>Myrtle</span> leaning
over the leopardess' shoulder while kneading her shoulders firmly. When
they finished, <span>Arabella</span> stepped forward, eyebrows raised
expectantly. <span>Lilwen</span> shrugged at her, rocking her cub
demonstratively.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Be my hands for a minute?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem.&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span> stepped forward, taking the bag and
holding it open for the tigress, who reached into it. She withdrew a
dark blue dress with a flourish, shaking it out to unfold it, holding it
by the collar as she gestured to the its palm-wide grey stripes that
fell from shoulders to hips to knees.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course <span>Sinavena</span> won&rsquo;t be climbing age for a while yet,
but she&rsquo;ll get there quicker than you think. Probably quicker than mine
— <span>Teruleth</span>&rsquo;s not much of a climber. Not as active as I&rsquo;d
like at all, really: I have to encourage him to swim, too. But
<span>Gadayra</span> is just up and down and up and down all day, she&rsquo;s
the fittest little thing.&rdquo; &ldquo;No wonder you learned to make these
yourself. It&rsquo;s so nice!&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> reached out with one hand,
rubbing the thick cloth between forefinger and thumb.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, it&rsquo;ll have little pawprints all over it soon enough, but that&rsquo;s
its own kind of nice.&rdquo; &ldquo;Yeah, it&rsquo;s one of those things where if it looks
pristine, that&rsquo;s not good.&rdquo; &ldquo;And little <span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s gonna
have strong claws to dig into it soon, isn&rsquo;t she?&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span>
leaned over as she raised the question, presenting her own fingers for
<span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s inquisitive paws. The kitten grabbed eagerly at
her, then chewed on the presented fingers with stubby little milk-fangs.
An indulgent smile met the chewing.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Soon, but hopefully not quite yet. I want her claws in the dress, not
in my tits.&rdquo;</p>

<p>They laughed together, returning to the table.</p>

<p>&ldquo;So — congratulations! Welcome back. Super happy for you.&rdquo;
<span>Arabella</span> beamed at <span>Lilwen</span>, raising her glass
in a toast as she leaned back. &ldquo;Okay if I throw a nosy question at you?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Go for it.&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> shifted her sling, coaxing the kitten
towards her breast, hand gently holding the back of her grey-furred
head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How&rsquo;d the perineal massage work out?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> snort-laughed indelicately, splashing some of her
martini on her face, then holding her hand over her muzzle as she
snickered. <span>Lilwen</span> chuckled, her ears flicking, guiding the
kitten&rsquo;s paws towards herself with one finger.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I mean, I don&rsquo;t have a lot of basis for comparison. I haven&rsquo;t tried
having a kid without it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Did it feel like it helped?&rdquo; &ldquo;Well, it felt like — let me put it this
way, I have <em>zero</em> questions left about what I can take. I&rsquo;m like, okay,
I got her out, smaller stuff I&rsquo;ll be fine with.&rdquo; They laughed together,
and <span>Lilwen</span> leaned back in her chair, sighing. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m still
pretty sore, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> nodded sympathetically. &ldquo;Yup. Took a full month for
me before I could sit down to piss comfortably.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Worth it,&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> opined, jabbing her forefinger
emphatically.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hell yeah, worth it. But you and I are saying that with the benefit of
a few years already behind us to get used to it.&rdquo; She nodded towards the
leopard. &ldquo;Give her a while before the evangelizing, huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not evangelizing.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Arabella</span>, honey, I have known you for a solid ten years. I
don&rsquo;t doubt your politics at all, but you were always kinda pretty het
compared to the rest of us, you were always really clear that you wanted
kids.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh come on. I sucked a lot of dick in college, which is emphatically
not the same thing, and then I settled down and married a nice girl. I
ended up with a husband and that&rsquo;s working out great, but come on, I was
never <em>that</em> het. That&rsquo;s actually a thing that makes me and
<span>Cam</span> uncomfortable sometimes: we look really het at events
compared to you and <span>Iris</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Lilwen</span> gave <span>Arabella</span> a puzzled look. &ldquo;Didn&rsquo;t
know you&rsquo;d had another marriage before <span>Cam</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I hadn&rsquo;t.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A high, sustained, squeal-yowl interrupted them, along with a chorus of
&ldquo;Mom!&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> swore, lunging up, her chair clattering over
backwards, glass falling onto the table. She dashed towards the pool,
hands pulling her dress open. <span>Myrtle</span> grabbed
<span>Lilwen</span>&rsquo;s shoulder hard as she soothed
<span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s upset at the noises.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You: chill. We&rsquo;ll handle it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She rose and briskly jogged after the tigress, turning aside to come
through the gate in the low fence that <span>Arabella</span> had simply
vaulted directly over, leaving her heavy dress behind. There was a brief
splash as she dove into the pool headlong, submerging as she moved
towards the splashing, thrashing kitten on the other side.
<span>Myrtle</span> forced herself to move slowly on the wet concrete
around the pool, approaching <span>Rynher</span>, <span>Terandil</span>,
and <span>Gadayra</span> as they huddled worriedly in a knot. She fell
to a crouch and her hands shot out, grabbing the two smallest ones by
their scruffs, her head dipping to pick up the remaining cub by her
teeth.</p>

<p>Turning around and putting them down again, she growled, fangs bared
demonstratively. &ldquo;<strong>Stay here</strong>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She heard a wet splat and wheezy coughs as she turned around.
<span>Arabella</span> had dove under the kitten in the pool and lifted
him out by rising directly under him, her head and one hand shoving him
up out of the water. He curled up on his side, shaking as he coughed.
The tigress rose from the pool, dripping all over, panting. She nodded
wearily as the kitten cried, sitting down cross-legged and holding him
against her chest.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shhhh. It&rsquo;s okay, <span>Ruru</span>. Mom&rsquo;s here. I got you. Keep
breathing. You&rsquo;re gonna be okay.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He clung to her as <span>Myrtle</span> ushered the other three away,
herding two of them and carrying the third in one arm. When she returned
to the table, <span>Campbell</span> was there with <span>Lilwen</span>,
frowning in concern.</p>

<p>&ldquo;What happened?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> coaxed the trio onto a bench together and chuffed
encouragingly at them as she distributed juice boxes and thin, soft
strips of jerky.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Ruru</span> fell in,&rdquo; <span>Terandil</span> volunteered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Uh-huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And he fell in the deep part, he was scared.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> stood on his tiptoes to get a look at the pool,
then visibly relaxed, nodding and prompting the kittens to continue with
a wave. They looked back and forth among themselves, recounting it
slowly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;He was trying to climb out.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We tried to help him.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He couldn&rsquo;t grab hands.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And I was telling people not to fall in more,&rdquo; <span>Gadayra</span>
piped up.</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> dragged out a smile. &ldquo;Oh yeah? Being a clever
kitten and remembering the rules?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah!&rdquo;</p>

<p>He stepped forward to kiss the top of <span>Gadayra</span>&rsquo;s head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good job, <span>Gada</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> looked expectantly at the three of them. &ldquo;Everyone
remembers that rule, right?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You can&rsquo;t help someone out if you fall in,&rdquo; they chorused, nodding.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good job!&rdquo; <span>Campbell</span> nodded firmly. &ldquo;You kept that in mind
and made it so Mom could come and help. That was the right thing to do.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> returned, holding <span>Teruleth</span> with both
hands, curled up with his arms around her neck. She wrapped
<span>Teruleth</span> in a dry towel, then sat down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Okay. <em>Okay</em>. Emergency over.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> draped a towel over her shoulders in turn, leaning
down for fretful licks and cheek-rubs. She leaned up to kiss him
briefly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Ruru</span> fell in and got scared. He&rsquo;s okay now.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> spoke up.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Kids, please go grab blankets and pillows from the closet and set them
up on the trampoline, okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The kittens nodded and trotted off, <span>Campbell</span> following them
after a nod from <span>Arabella</span>. <span>Myrtle</span> sat down
beside her, stroking her back up and down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You doing okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Give me a few minutes for my heart rate to settle down. I&rsquo;m just glad
this guy&rsquo;s okay.&rdquo; She nuzzled down at <span>Teruleth</span>, who made a
quiet, shaky mew and hid his head under her chin. &ldquo;You&rsquo;re gonna be
okay,&rdquo; she repeated to him. &ldquo;You forgot to be careful for a minute, but
now you&rsquo;re okay, and you can learn to be more careful. Everyone forgets
sometimes; that&rsquo;s why we practice things. So we&rsquo;re gonna practice that
again later, carefully, so you don&rsquo;t have to be scared like that again.
Okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The small tiger nodded, still curled up against her. She gave him a warm
squeeze.</p>

<p>&ldquo;And right now we&rsquo;re all gonna have a nice lunch together and you&rsquo;re
gonna take a nap in the blanket fort with <span>Gada</span>,
<span>Tern</span>, and <span>Rynnie</span>. How&rsquo;s that sound?&rdquo; Another
nod, slightly more energetic. <span>Arabella</span> carefully put him
down, draping the towel over his shoulders like a cape. &ldquo;Good. Okay: go
help <span>Gada</span> with putting the blanket fort together, all
right?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;All right.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He trotted off with increasing steadiness, and <span>Arabella</span>
slumped in her chair, putting her hands over her face.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Criminy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You keep breathing too, babe,&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span> said, coming around
behind her and rubbing her shoulders.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, that looked like three quarters of a heart attack,&rdquo;
<span>Lilwen</span> concurred.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Maybe just one quarter of a heart attack, but yeah.&rdquo; She chuckled
ruefully. &ldquo;What I got from him was that they were roughhousing, he
tripped and fell into the pool, swallowed some water, and panicked. So
once I got him out, he was fine, just shaken.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Honestly, you look more shaken than he does.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I probably am: <em>I&rsquo;m</em> old enough to be fuckin' terrified of mortality —
especially my kids' mortality.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Lilwen</span> grimaced. &ldquo;Yeah, that&rsquo;s reasonable. I had that scare
at six months, I was telling you about the one set of ultrasounds.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That was pretty horrible.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Right, and until they figured out what was actually happening, I was a
wreck. So I feel you on that.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> leaned forward over <span>Arabella</span>&rsquo;s
shoulder.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How about I drag out the air mattress and the three of us just cuddle
on that out here while the kids are napping?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That sounds like a good plan, yeah.&rdquo; She smiled at <span>Lilwen</span>.
&ldquo;Plus it&rsquo;ll let us fuss over you for a while — you sure look like you
need it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am completely okay with this plan,&rdquo; she laughed.</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> returned, and they cleared space on the table for
the tray he carried, called the kittens for lunch, and all sat down
together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
