<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-04T16:32:17-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[NaNoWriMo 2016, #1: The Village It Takes]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-01-the-village-it-takes/"/>
      
    <updated>2016-11-04T16:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/nanowrimo-2016-01-the-village-it-takes</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am, taking on a November writing project again.
If you haven&rsquo;t seen me do this before, here&rsquo;s what I do.
I don&rsquo;t have a novel in me right now, so for NaNoWriMo I just do as many short stories as I can.
I use the social momentum and recognition of NaNoWriMo to push myself to spend a lot of time writing and to explain to others what I&rsquo;m doing.
As with the novels people produce during NaNo, I try to be very forgiving towards myself and my work; it is okay to just drop an idea when I get stuck and move on to the next story.
It&rsquo;s been working out very well so far: here&rsquo;s the first one for this year.</p>

<hr />

<p>&ldquo;Hey. Hey, hey. Mommo. What&rsquo;s that? That&rsquo;s not orange juice.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> crouched, then jumped up, catching her mother&rsquo;s
dress in little hands and huffing as she began to climb.
<span>Myrtle</span> casually reached around with one hand, nudging her
cub upwards.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That&rsquo;s a martini, honey. Not for kittens.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Why?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> laughed quietly, her martini glass clinking as she
set it down on the sun-warmed glass tabletop amid a few bottles, a large
carafe of juice, and a half-shrinkwrapped cluster of juice boxes.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I see someone&rsquo;s discovered &lsquo;why,&rsquo; haven&rsquo;t they.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A couple weeks ago, actually.&rdquo; She turned her head back to the small
lion. &ldquo;Martinis are difficult, kitten.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> hauled herself up to <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s shoulder,
leaning over it, her chest on the lioness' wide shoulder, one paw on her
collarbone, the other waving towards <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s martini.
<span>Myrtle</span> reached up with her free hand, rubbing
<span>Rynher</span>&rsquo;s head and giving her a few fond licks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Whyyyyyyy are they difficult?&rdquo; <span>Rynher</span> asked, her toeclaws
digging into the back of <span>Myrtle</span>&rsquo;s dress as she headbutted
her mother&rsquo;s jaw.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Because they&rsquo;re complicated,&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> replied, sipping
her own. &ldquo;Would you like me to tell you about how they&rsquo;re complicated?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> wiggled for a moment, dark-tipped tail flicking.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yes please!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Polite kitten!&rdquo; The tigress beamed, leaning forward, elbows on the
table. &ldquo;Okay. Martinis have a lot of alcohol in them. Alcohol has good
and bad things in it. The bad things depend on how big your body is:
they spread out more in bigger people&rsquo;s bodies. Your mom and I are big
cats, so we can drink some alcohol and we get the good parts with only a
little bit of the bad parts. If <em>you</em> drank alcohol, you&rsquo;d get some good
parts, but because you&rsquo;re a small cat, you&rsquo;d get a lot of the bad parts
like losing your sense of balance, throwing up, and headaches. It would
not be fun, and it might hurt you badly. So that&rsquo;s why alcohol is okay
for big cats and not okay for small cats.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> put her own glass down as the explanation proceeded,
keeping one hand on <span>Rynher</span>&rsquo;s back to steady her. She
extracted a juice box from the clump, speared its straw in, and lifted
it for <span>Rynher</span>, who squealed happily, putting both paws
forward for it.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Do you understand that, kitten?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yuh-huh!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What do you say?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She turned to <span>Arabella</span>.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thank you Miss <span>Arabella</span>!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good kitten.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Rynher</span> took the juice box in both hands and sucked on its
straw happily. <span>Myrtle</span> made eye contact with
<span>Arabella</span>, pointing briefly up at her cub, then away.
<span>Arabella</span> nodded, stood, and came around behind her: she
gently put both hands on <span>Rynher</span>, picked her up, extracted
her toeclaws, and put her down on the patio. She scampered away, both
adults grinning after her.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Thanks for the save.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem. Mine are just getting there too. <span>Cam</span>&rsquo;s better
at the &lsquo;why&rsquo; game than I am, but I&rsquo;m okay at it. Probably goes with his
job.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh yeah — how&rsquo;s his quest for tenure going?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> rolled her eyes and shook her head.
<span>Myrtle</span> raised her eyebrows curiously, then turned away,
craning her neck to get a look at the four kittens as
<span>Rynher</span> rejoined the other three, splashing around in the
swimming pool across the yard.</p>

<p>&ldquo;That bad, huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;d rather not get into it, and honestly I think you shouldn&rsquo;t mention
it to him today either. He&rsquo;s focusing on making us lunch right now, and
after that he&rsquo;s gonna shut himself in the bedroom with a couple of
dildos for stress-relief time.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You think he&rsquo;ll want company?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Ask him, not me. But if I had to guess, I&rsquo;d say he&rsquo;ll want the kind of
company that can top the hell out of him. The kittens had a cold
recently, so of course we both got it, and that pushed things to an even
lower level than normal. So your odds are pretty good.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Cool. I might go for that. You okay soloing all four of the kids for a
while? I imagine <span>Lilwen</span> is gonna have her hands full
already.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, I&rsquo;ll be fine. After pool time and lunch they should all be a bit
tired anyhow; I&rsquo;ll throw some pillows on the trampoline and have them
all make a nest.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Great. Thanks babe.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> leaned over and kissed the side of her muzzle.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Save some of him for me, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p>They laughed together, then picked up their glasses and sipped in
unison. At the sound of a sliding door, they turned, then grinned
widely.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Lilwen</span>!&rdquo; &ldquo;Heyyyy!&rdquo; &ldquo;Welcome welcome!&rdquo; The leopard stepped
through the door gingerly, <span>Campbell</span> ushering her out. In a
sling against her chest she held a little bundle, a tiny paw reaching
out of it and batting slowly at her bosom. <span>Arabella</span> and
<span>Myrtle</span> rose together, smiling widely, coming to meet her.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How&rsquo;ve you <em>been</em>, babe?&rdquo; She made a resigned smile as she carefully
hugged them.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Really tired, basically all of the time. I thought I was gonna be done
after, you know, birth, but the whole thing is <em>still</em> kicking my ass.
Thanks again for setting this up for me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course! This stuff&rsquo;s really difficult. We just wanted to make time
for you to sit down and have a breather.&rdquo; &ldquo;And to get introduced to the
itty-bitty one, of course.&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> pulled a grin out,
standing up straighter, ears perking.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Her name&rsquo;s <span>Sinavena</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And what a fine little thing <span>Sinavena</span> is!&rdquo;
<span>Arabella</span> leaned in, wiggling her fingers gently at the
bundled-up, grey-furred cub. &ldquo;Hey little terror. How you feelin' today?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Diminutive paws waved at her fingers eagerly, accompanied by high,
squeaky mews.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pretty fierce for all of, what, three and a half weeks?&rdquo; &ldquo;Shit, most
days she&rsquo;s got more energy than I do.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh, that reminds me —&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> straightened up, beckoning
to <span>Lilwen</span> with a wave over her shoulder as she returned to
the table. She picked up a tall shopping bag, turned around, then
chuckled and smiled patiently as she saw <span>Lilwen</span> and
<span>Myrtle</span> sharing a slow kiss, <span>Myrtle</span> leaning
over the leopardess' shoulder while kneading her shoulders firmly. When
they finished, <span>Arabella</span> stepped forward, eyebrows raised
expectantly. <span>Lilwen</span> shrugged at her, rocking her cub
demonstratively.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Be my hands for a minute?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No problem.&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span> stepped forward, taking the bag and
holding it open for the tigress, who reached into it. She withdrew a
dark blue dress with a flourish, shaking it out to unfold it, holding it
by the collar as she gestured to the its palm-wide grey stripes that
fell from shoulders to hips to knees.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course <span>Sinavena</span> won&rsquo;t be climbing age for a while yet,
but she&rsquo;ll get there quicker than you think. Probably quicker than mine
— <span>Teruleth</span>&rsquo;s not much of a climber. Not as active as I&rsquo;d
like at all, really: I have to encourage him to swim, too. But
<span>Gadayra</span> is just up and down and up and down all day, she&rsquo;s
the fittest little thing.&rdquo; &ldquo;No wonder you learned to make these
yourself. It&rsquo;s so nice!&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> reached out with one hand,
rubbing the thick cloth between forefinger and thumb.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, it&rsquo;ll have little pawprints all over it soon enough, but that&rsquo;s
its own kind of nice.&rdquo; &ldquo;Yeah, it&rsquo;s one of those things where if it looks
pristine, that&rsquo;s not good.&rdquo; &ldquo;And little <span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s gonna
have strong claws to dig into it soon, isn&rsquo;t she?&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span>
leaned over as she raised the question, presenting her own fingers for
<span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s inquisitive paws. The kitten grabbed eagerly at
her, then chewed on the presented fingers with stubby little milk-fangs.
An indulgent smile met the chewing.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Soon, but hopefully not quite yet. I want her claws in the dress, not
in my tits.&rdquo;</p>

<p>They laughed together, returning to the table.</p>

<p>&ldquo;So — congratulations! Welcome back. Super happy for you.&rdquo;
<span>Arabella</span> beamed at <span>Lilwen</span>, raising her glass
in a toast as she leaned back. &ldquo;Okay if I throw a nosy question at you?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Go for it.&rdquo; <span>Lilwen</span> shifted her sling, coaxing the kitten
towards her breast, hand gently holding the back of her grey-furred
head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How&rsquo;d the perineal massage work out?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> snort-laughed indelicately, splashing some of her
martini on her face, then holding her hand over her muzzle as she
snickered. <span>Lilwen</span> chuckled, her ears flicking, guiding the
kitten&rsquo;s paws towards herself with one finger.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I mean, I don&rsquo;t have a lot of basis for comparison. I haven&rsquo;t tried
having a kid without it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Did it feel like it helped?&rdquo; &ldquo;Well, it felt like — let me put it this
way, I have <em>zero</em> questions left about what I can take. I&rsquo;m like, okay,
I got her out, smaller stuff I&rsquo;ll be fine with.&rdquo; They laughed together,
and <span>Lilwen</span> leaned back in her chair, sighing. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m still
pretty sore, though.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> nodded sympathetically. &ldquo;Yup. Took a full month for
me before I could sit down to piss comfortably.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Worth it,&rdquo; <span>Arabella</span> opined, jabbing her forefinger
emphatically.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Hell yeah, worth it. But you and I are saying that with the benefit of
a few years already behind us to get used to it.&rdquo; She nodded towards the
leopard. &ldquo;Give her a while before the evangelizing, huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not evangelizing.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Arabella</span>, honey, I have known you for a solid ten years. I
don&rsquo;t doubt your politics at all, but you were always kinda pretty het
compared to the rest of us, you were always really clear that you wanted
kids.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh come on. I sucked a lot of dick in college, which is emphatically
not the same thing, and then I settled down and married a nice girl. I
ended up with a husband and that&rsquo;s working out great, but come on, I was
never <em>that</em> het. That&rsquo;s actually a thing that makes me and
<span>Cam</span> uncomfortable sometimes: we look really het at events
compared to you and <span>Iris</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Lilwen</span> gave <span>Arabella</span> a puzzled look. &ldquo;Didn&rsquo;t
know you&rsquo;d had another marriage before <span>Cam</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I hadn&rsquo;t.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A high, sustained, squeal-yowl interrupted them, along with a chorus of
&ldquo;Mom!&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> swore, lunging up, her chair clattering over
backwards, glass falling onto the table. She dashed towards the pool,
hands pulling her dress open. <span>Myrtle</span> grabbed
<span>Lilwen</span>&rsquo;s shoulder hard as she soothed
<span>Sinavena</span>&rsquo;s upset at the noises.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You: chill. We&rsquo;ll handle it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She rose and briskly jogged after the tigress, turning aside to come
through the gate in the low fence that <span>Arabella</span> had simply
vaulted directly over, leaving her heavy dress behind. There was a brief
splash as she dove into the pool headlong, submerging as she moved
towards the splashing, thrashing kitten on the other side.
<span>Myrtle</span> forced herself to move slowly on the wet concrete
around the pool, approaching <span>Rynher</span>, <span>Terandil</span>,
and <span>Gadayra</span> as they huddled worriedly in a knot. She fell
to a crouch and her hands shot out, grabbing the two smallest ones by
their scruffs, her head dipping to pick up the remaining cub by her
teeth.</p>

<p>Turning around and putting them down again, she growled, fangs bared
demonstratively. &ldquo;<strong>Stay here</strong>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She heard a wet splat and wheezy coughs as she turned around.
<span>Arabella</span> had dove under the kitten in the pool and lifted
him out by rising directly under him, her head and one hand shoving him
up out of the water. He curled up on his side, shaking as he coughed.
The tigress rose from the pool, dripping all over, panting. She nodded
wearily as the kitten cried, sitting down cross-legged and holding him
against her chest.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shhhh. It&rsquo;s okay, <span>Ruru</span>. Mom&rsquo;s here. I got you. Keep
breathing. You&rsquo;re gonna be okay.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He clung to her as <span>Myrtle</span> ushered the other three away,
herding two of them and carrying the third in one arm. When she returned
to the table, <span>Campbell</span> was there with <span>Lilwen</span>,
frowning in concern.</p>

<p>&ldquo;What happened?&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> coaxed the trio onto a bench together and chuffed
encouragingly at them as she distributed juice boxes and thin, soft
strips of jerky.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Ruru</span> fell in,&rdquo; <span>Terandil</span> volunteered.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Uh-huh?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And he fell in the deep part, he was scared.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> stood on his tiptoes to get a look at the pool,
then visibly relaxed, nodding and prompting the kittens to continue with
a wave. They looked back and forth among themselves, recounting it
slowly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;He was trying to climb out.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;We tried to help him.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;He couldn&rsquo;t grab hands.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;And I was telling people not to fall in more,&rdquo; <span>Gadayra</span>
piped up.</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> dragged out a smile. &ldquo;Oh yeah? Being a clever
kitten and remembering the rules?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah!&rdquo;</p>

<p>He stepped forward to kiss the top of <span>Gadayra</span>&rsquo;s head.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good job, <span>Gada</span>.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> looked expectantly at the three of them. &ldquo;Everyone
remembers that rule, right?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You can&rsquo;t help someone out if you fall in,&rdquo; they chorused, nodding.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good job!&rdquo; <span>Campbell</span> nodded firmly. &ldquo;You kept that in mind
and made it so Mom could come and help. That was the right thing to do.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Arabella</span> returned, holding <span>Teruleth</span> with both
hands, curled up with his arms around her neck. She wrapped
<span>Teruleth</span> in a dry towel, then sat down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Okay. <em>Okay</em>. Emergency over.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> draped a towel over her shoulders in turn, leaning
down for fretful licks and cheek-rubs. She leaned up to kiss him
briefly.</p>

<p>&ldquo;<span>Ruru</span> fell in and got scared. He&rsquo;s okay now.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> spoke up.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Kids, please go grab blankets and pillows from the closet and set them
up on the trampoline, okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The kittens nodded and trotted off, <span>Campbell</span> following them
after a nod from <span>Arabella</span>. <span>Myrtle</span> sat down
beside her, stroking her back up and down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You doing okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Give me a few minutes for my heart rate to settle down. I&rsquo;m just glad
this guy&rsquo;s okay.&rdquo; She nuzzled down at <span>Teruleth</span>, who made a
quiet, shaky mew and hid his head under her chin. &ldquo;You&rsquo;re gonna be
okay,&rdquo; she repeated to him. &ldquo;You forgot to be careful for a minute, but
now you&rsquo;re okay, and you can learn to be more careful. Everyone forgets
sometimes; that&rsquo;s why we practice things. So we&rsquo;re gonna practice that
again later, carefully, so you don&rsquo;t have to be scared like that again.
Okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The small tiger nodded, still curled up against her. She gave him a warm
squeeze.</p>

<p>&ldquo;And right now we&rsquo;re all gonna have a nice lunch together and you&rsquo;re
gonna take a nap in the blanket fort with <span>Gada</span>,
<span>Tern</span>, and <span>Rynnie</span>. How&rsquo;s that sound?&rdquo; Another
nod, slightly more energetic. <span>Arabella</span> carefully put him
down, draping the towel over his shoulders like a cape. &ldquo;Good. Okay: go
help <span>Gada</span> with putting the blanket fort together, all
right?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;All right.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He trotted off with increasing steadiness, and <span>Arabella</span>
slumped in her chair, putting her hands over her face.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Criminy.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;You keep breathing too, babe,&rdquo; <span>Myrtle</span> said, coming around
behind her and rubbing her shoulders.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah, that looked like three quarters of a heart attack,&rdquo;
<span>Lilwen</span> concurred.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Maybe just one quarter of a heart attack, but yeah.&rdquo; She chuckled
ruefully. &ldquo;What I got from him was that they were roughhousing, he
tripped and fell into the pool, swallowed some water, and panicked. So
once I got him out, he was fine, just shaken.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Honestly, you look more shaken than he does.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I probably am: <em>I&rsquo;m</em> old enough to be fuckin' terrified of mortality —
especially my kids' mortality.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Lilwen</span> grimaced. &ldquo;Yeah, that&rsquo;s reasonable. I had that scare
at six months, I was telling you about the one set of ultrasounds.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That was pretty horrible.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Right, and until they figured out what was actually happening, I was a
wreck. So I feel you on that.&rdquo;</p>

<p><span>Myrtle</span> leaned forward over <span>Arabella</span>&rsquo;s
shoulder.</p>

<p>&ldquo;How about I drag out the air mattress and the three of us just cuddle
on that out here while the kids are napping?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;That sounds like a good plan, yeah.&rdquo; She smiled at <span>Lilwen</span>.
&ldquo;Plus it&rsquo;ll let us fuss over you for a while — you sure look like you
need it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am completely okay with this plan,&rdquo; she laughed.</p>

<p><span>Campbell</span> returned, and they cleared space on the table for
the tray he carried, called the kittens for lunch, and all sat down
together.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monsters, Marginalization, and Identity: surviving the demand to consider ourselves unworthy]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/monsters-marginalization-and-identity/"/>
      
    <updated>2016-09-19T18:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/monsters-marginalization-and-identity</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Men who regard their egos as more important than women&rsquo;s autonomy are common as dirt, but it&rsquo;s rare for such a man to so thoroughly make an ass of himself in public as the author of &ldquo;<a href="http://archive.is/juTA1">How to Talk to a Woman Who is Wearing Headphones</a>&rdquo; did.
He got thoroughly heckled and mocked, as he entirely deserved.
One response, though, stood out for me: Alexandra Petri&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/compost/wp/2016/08/30/so-you-must-talk-to-the-woman-who-is-wearing-headphones/">So, You Must Talk to the Woman Who Is Wearing Headphones</a>.&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>
It took a very literary approach to its critique, using a conceit of women as dangerous, wild, and fierce, to reflect and expose the <em>How To Talk</em> author&rsquo;s unspoken conception of women as a monstrous Other.
It&rsquo;s a conception much older than him, and Petri&rsquo;s response deftly invoked older examples of feminine monsters, re-appropriating them to celebrate the idea of women&rsquo;s danger, wildness, and ferocity.
In addition to Petri&rsquo;s work, Lucian Clark of <em>Gender Terror</em> recently published &ldquo;<a href="https://genderterror.com/2016/08/29/monsters-of-our-own/">Monsters Of Our Own: Monster Symbolism in the Trans Community</a>,&rdquo; which examines the intersection of monster narratives and trans narratives by way of several volunteers' personal accounts of monstrosity.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>
I believe there&rsquo;s a tremendous power in re-appropriating those monstrous images and narratives.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>
We can use them to build selves better equipped to survive and resist marginalization.
I&rsquo;m going to explain my personal connection to monsters and to spend some time talking about how they connect to experiences of marginalization, in hopes of showing you that you have the ability to conceptualize yourself as a strong, beautiful monster.
Like the women in Petri&rsquo;s poem, you can be dangerous, wild, and fierce.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p>

<hr />

<p><br>I have monsters in me.
As a woman, my navigating the world requires me to be aware of how heteronormative femininity is a very specific narrative that very many people are willing and able to violently enforce, even though those people generally regard women who depart from heteronormative femininity as unnatural, bizarre, or fearful: as monstrous.
As a trans woman, my surviving in the world requires me to be aware of how many people regard my selfhood as unnatural and my body as something to be punished: again, as monstrous.
I&rsquo;m confronted with people, media, and structures in the world (lots of them!) that either treat my personhood as debatable and optional or outright take for granted that I am some kind of lesser being.
Sometimes I have the energy and desire to demand to be treated as a peer, as a full person, as a normal person instead of as the Other.
It&rsquo;s impossible for me (or anyone else in marginalized communities) to sustain that desire and energy all the time, though.</p>

<p>Even when we do have the desire and the energy, sometimes the mechanisms that enforce marginalization coerce us into compliance — yet coercion, however violent, cannot force us to regard ourselves in our hearts as fundamentally unworthy, as not being full people, as deserving only the scraps of dignity and justice that they choose to allow us.
Brief digression: structures of marginalization often inflict trauma and mental health problems on us that <em>can</em> make us hate ourselves like that, but despite bearing scars and pain, we have good days and flashes of strength in which we can once again perceive clearly that we are just as fundamentally worthy of health, happiness, safety, and kindness as everyone else in the world.
I send my solidarity and love to everyone bearing those scars.
You have that strength, you are worthy, and the system is what&rsquo;s broken, not you.</p>

<p>When we&rsquo;re in those situations, though, whether we&rsquo;re coerced or weary or simply don&rsquo;t give a fuck today, we&rsquo;re presented with another question: &ldquo;who am I, then?&rdquo;
We can&rsquo;t just assert &ldquo;I really am a person!&rdquo; directly because it&rsquo;d require the energy, desire, or freedom that we don&rsquo;t have in those situations.
At the same time, we do know in our hearts that the situation that denies our personhood, is doing us an injustice.
How, then, do we express <em>to ourselves</em> a resolution between the external situation that demands suppression of our selfhood and our internal knowledge of its reality and importance?
There are many tactics for resistance that focus on cultivating the energy and desire to assert ourselves more often, or on helping us muster resistance against coercion.
Such tactics are good and important, but there are limits to the help they can give us.
Beyond those limits dwell monsters who can lend us their strength.</p>

<p>We can answer the question &ldquo;who am I?&rdquo; with &ldquo;I am a monster,&rdquo; with a self-image that neither requires us to externally demand acknowledgement nor  to internally regard ourselves as unworthy and abject.
The way we are treated as Other can become an affirmation of monster-ness, rather than a sign of unworthiness.
Even when we can&rsquo;t escape mistreatment, a monstrous narrative of self lets us resist the demand that we think of ourself as deserving mistreatment.
Building our own monstrous narrative of self lets us choose alternate explanations, instead of being forced into the explanation offered by those who mistreat us.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></p>

<p>The explanation that <em>Monsters Of Our Own</em> offers, about monsters and trans-ness, is a good place to start:</p>

<blockquote><p>For some trans people, monsters represent the way society sees them. It is a
reclamation of a title given to their existence, forced on them for being who
they are. For others, they represent the factors of their bodies and the
conflict they experience. They may also represent the escape, the strength,
needed to deal with a society that views you as other, grotesque, terrifying,
horrific. Monsters represent how society sees trans people [and reflect trans
people&rsquo;s] own experiences of violence, rejection, and exclusion, [creating]
an empathetic tie to monsters.</p></blockquote>

<p>As a furry, I&rsquo;ve spent a lot of time using nonhuman images of self as a way to ask &ldquo;who am I?&rdquo; and &ldquo;who do I want and need to be?&rdquo; as well as using those images as tools with which to build answers.
The furry subculture not only cultivates conversations about nonhuman images of self, but also creates spaces where participants can adopt those selves as primary and expect to be treated accordingly even if a participant&rsquo;s embodied-world presence diverges widely from the self they adopt.
After years of participating in the conversations and the spaces, the selves that I now use for almost everything are the anthropomorphic tigress who is my avatar-self, together with werewolf, space alien, and gorgon layers on top of that core self (visual reference: <a href="https://www.weasyl.com/submission/978197/commission-krinn-twitter-banner">here we are together</a>).
I&rsquo;m going to talk about how these identities<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" rel="footnote">6</a></sup> are important tools for me, about the monster archetypes they embody, and about how they co-habit with the rest of my selfhood.
My personal usage of these tools is only a fraction of what&rsquo;s possible, but I hope that its example can point you towards ways of using the tools that will be most productive for you.</p>

<!-- Tigerwolf -->


<p>The werewolf version of me is a combination of tiger and wolf, outrageous and Dionysian (visual reference: <a href="http://sigilgoat.tumblr.com/post/122837779280/this-months-theme-for-patreon-was-swimsuits">in this photoset, right-hand column, light green swimsuit</a>).
I draw my idiom of werewolves less from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_Monsters">Universal horror movies</a> and more from the sexualized werewolves that Internet-mediated fandom communities have made prominent: there&rsquo;s a specific experience that the latter are helpful for taking on.
Part of the experience of living in a marginalized community, is the experience of the dominant community&rsquo;s willingness to coercively regulate your sexuality.
For women, especially trans women, this coercion is a central feature of our experience.<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" rel="footnote">7</a></sup>
The dominant culture regards mass-media broadcasts, individual conversations, and everything in between as appropriate venues to speculate about our appearances, our sexual tastes, and our fuckability.
Taking on this monstrous aspect lets me reverse heteronormativity&rsquo;s demand that women be sexually submissive, meek, and undemanding of our own pleasure: when I&rsquo;m in tigerwolf mode, I am sexually dominant, I assert my autonomy, I gleefully enjoy sexual pleasure.
Because I am a trans woman, the dominant culture considers my genitals dangerous and unnatural despite that the idea of penetrating someone with them makes me flinch with discomfort and revulsion.
When I&rsquo;m in tigerwolf mode, I proudly have and take pleasure from monstrous, non-cisnormative genitals, unconcerned with disguising them or with passing as a cis person.
My tigerwolf self has the privilege of universal acceptance when I assert that my body is feminine and enjoys the luxury of only having conversations about my appearance, my sexual tastes, and my fuckability when they&rsquo;re conducted on my terms.</p>

<p>The tigerwolf also incorporates some elements from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maenad">the Maenads</a>.
Werewolf narrative skews towards being male-coded, but it also overlaps with accounts of the Maenads, who are somewhat more obscure.
For all that the Maenads are definitely human women, they are still portrayed as monstrous: like werewolves, they&rsquo;re stereotypically bloodthirsty, irrational, and dangerous.
However, when we notice that our knowledge of this group of women is entirely mediated through writing by men (not very much of it, either), we have to question the accuracy of our &ldquo;knowledge&rdquo;.
What would they have to say for themselves?
Given that there are many feminine monsters (especially ones from the ancient Mediterranean like the Maenads) where our knowledge of them comes only from accounts by men, this is a question that we should ask often.
It&rsquo;s certainly not good that other accounts didn&rsquo;t survive (or never existed), but at the same time it&rsquo;s an opportunity.</p>

<p>The Maenads' voicelessness is an overwhelmingly common experience of marginalized communities.
We are required to understand the dominant group in order to survive, but dominance lets them shirk the emotional labor of understanding us on our own terms; further, others know us not by what we&rsquo;d like to say about ourselves, but by what&rsquo;s said <em>about</em> us by the dominant group.<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" rel="footnote">8</a></sup>
Because of this shared experience, members of marginalized communities in the present are well-qualified to reconstruct alternate accounts of such monsters<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" rel="footnote">9</a></sup> by asking &ldquo;what did the dominant group say about <em>us</em> when we were kept from speaking in our own voices?&rdquo;
In answering this question, we triangulate from the known accounts and approach the missing ones: once in their neighborhood, we reconstruct what the monsters might tell us about themselves if given the chance to speak with their own voices.
Even though it&rsquo;s impossible to forensically or archaeologically verify the accounts that we reconstruct, we can verify immediately whether or not they resonate with our experience of being made voiceless, whether they have the same relationship to the dominant group&rsquo;s descriptions as our accounts of ourselves do.
Accounts that resonate, are ones we can use when we become monsters.
Personally, I&rsquo;m guided by the way that both werewolves and Maenads are beings of the wild, outside of and feared by the &ldquo;civilized&rdquo; world (presumed to be ruled by men).
When I inhabit my tigerwolf self, I am enlisting these monsters' help in resisting the way that today&rsquo;s &ldquo;civilized&rdquo; world treats me.</p>

<!-- Xenokitty -->


<p>The space alien version of me is a xenokitty, a mix of familiar and unfamiliar (visual reference: <a href="http://www.furaffinity.net/view/15979688/">this picture, (exposed breasts, login required)</a>).
Like E.T., Ford Prefect, and similar aliens in media, she&rsquo;s a friendly, curious outsider.<sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" rel="footnote">10</a></sup>
Where the tigerwolf embodies a pointed rejection of the &ldquo;civilized&rdquo; world by someone from a neighboring area who&rsquo;s <em>capable</em> of complying with its demands despite rejecting them, the xenokitty is from far, far outside that world.
She explores, confidently and actively seeking new experiences even in distant and unfamiliar surroundings.
She takes it for granted that she is dramatically different from the people around her, and is thoroughly comfortable with that status.
It leads her to value her differences with others as things to be learned from, as opportunities to explore, and as entertainment.</p>

<p>Sometimes, people enacting marginalization aren&rsquo;t so much aggressive as they are uncomprehending.
Members of the dominant group may be unaware of even extremely basic parameters of our lives.
When this lack of understanding surfaces, we sometimes can take the opportunity to teach, to explain our experience in our own voices to someone who may be open to hearing something other than the dominant group&rsquo;s account of us.
Teaching takes significant effort and the expectation that we will exert ourselves happily is also part of marginalization, but the opportunity is real.
When these opportunities come along, it&rsquo;s a good time for me to be a space alien.
When I&rsquo;m in xenokitty mode, I&rsquo;m eager to explore difference and novelty.
I am okay with others not understanding my experience: it&rsquo;s not theirs, and they don&rsquo;t need to understand it for it to be healthy, good, and valid.
This reduces the pressure that comes with the teaching: it&rsquo;s stressful to be a <em>de facto</em> representative of your entire community, especially on short notice.
Being a space alien gives me the confidence to fluently explain myself and to teach people about my experience without apologizing for it.
It also helps me defer the anger that comes from how explaining one&rsquo;s experience of marginalization inevitably calls to mind the injustice of that experience: the anger is a valid and relevant response, but it&rsquo;s very difficult to use it helpfully for the work of teaching.
Finally, being in xenokitty mode is helpful specifically in trans and queer contexts: I delight in finding siblings and other explorers.
Some of them need reassurance that their homeworlds are okay places to which it is possible to return, that there exist places that are safe for them, and that there are other voyagers out there who know what it&rsquo;s like to be far from home.</p>

<!-- Gorgon -->


<p>The gorgon version of me is both feline and ophidian, a creature of earth and stone (visual reference: <a href="https://www.weasyl.com/submission/647178/the-gorgon-character-sheet">this picture</a>).
Gnomic and obscure, she&rsquo;s focused on her creative and investigative work, avoiding the dominant culture because interacting with it would be a time-consuming tedium unworthy of her attention.
Unlike the xenokitty, she is uninterested in explaining herself.
Instead of an explorer, she is a hermit — like the gorgons or their siblings the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graeae">Graeae</a>, not a particularly safe one to seek out.
She can be found, but the kind of person capable of finding her is already halfway outside of the orthodox world.
Finding her may result in the seeker&rsquo;s transformation.</p>

<p>The triangulation mentioned earlier with the Maenads is particularly fruitful with the Gorgons of Greek myth.
As with the Maenads, the various accounts we have come to us through men, but unlike them, one account is distinctly strongest and foremost: the Perseus myth.
In it, Perseus feuds with King Polydectes, who sends him to dispatch Medusa in the expectation that the Gorgons' petrifying abilities will result in Perseus' death: instead, with help from Athena, Perseus shields himself from petrification, beheads Medusa, and uses her severed head to petrify several other men in various tales.
What would Medusa and her sisters have to say for themselves?</p>

<p>To me, the Perseus story has some very familiar elements.
I can read the Gorgons as women whose appearances stunned the men of their world, leaving them unable to process what they beheld, paralyzed by something about these women that they were deeply afraid of: a metaphorical petrification.
These men reacted with violence.
Perseus' story includes not only his aid from Athena, but his coercing aid from the Graeae and the Hesperides.
He seeks out the Gorgons, inflicts deadly violence on them, and uses the result of this violence to raise his status among other men.
Even in death, Medusa is denied her own account: Perseus' account goes unchallenged and gives him much glory.
It is a very small extrapolation to say that Perseus <em>exploits</em> the Gorgons: instead of having their own voices, Perseus' voice is substituted for theirs in a way that gains Perseus great worldly profit (on top of the harm he inflicted in his encounter with them).</p>

<p>When we look at the story this way, trans people, women, and queer people can&rsquo;t help but recognize our own collective experiences.
Many are the men who have reacted to our appearance with violence, and then sought to justify the violence by claiming that we are a danger to them.
Many are the men who have sought us out and then interposed themselves between us and others, silencing us by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vivek_Wadhwa">claiming to speak for us and collecting profits for their speech</a>.
Many are the men who have done us harm without even acknowledging us, like Perseus and the Graeae/Hesperides, on their way to work some harm on our siblings.
Many, too, are the men who regard their desires as more important than our autonomy: even though the author of <em>How To Talk</em> does a smaller harm than the deadly violence Perseus used, they are on the same continuum.</p>

<p>In gorgon mode, I turn my face from the world that calls me dangerous and worthy of deadly aggression.
I am a calm recluse, focused on my creative work: I am unconcerned with being understood by the &ldquo;civilized&rdquo; world.
I expect that my body, my desires, and my self will be incomprehensible to them, and I proudly become an enigma.
When people receptive to my work find me, I welcome them, but I make no effort to be easy to understand or find (rather, the opposite).
Keeping in solidarity with Medusa, a tragically slain sibling, I stay mindful of the violence that may be enacted against me based on my appearance, and do what work I can to shield myself against it.</p>

<p>Like anyone else in a marginalized community, I sometimes resist the mechanisms of marginalization in ways the external world can see, but I don&rsquo;t always have the energy, desire, or freedom to do so.
Together, these three alternate selves are extremely helpful to my internal resistance.
They give me strength to reject the demand that I internally submit to marginalization by regarding myself as deserving to be treated as less than a person.
Importantly, the archetypes that work for me aren&rsquo;t the only ones.
I&rsquo;m acquainted with genies (tapping into the juxtaposition of power and powerlessness as a way to grapple with heteronormativity&rsquo;s paradoxical accounts of women&rsquo;s sexuality), with fae (alien creatures, beautiful and dangerous), and with robots (extending the idea of our bodies as artificial to explore the possibilities of truly being able to choose an embodiment).
There are many, many monsters to choose from.
Go, and become monstrous.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Ursula Vernon&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://tkingfisher.tumblr.com/post/149767984883/this-vote-is-legally-binding">This Vote Is Legally Binding</a>&rdquo; is also wonderful, but does not contain monsters.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>They generously invited me to contribute, but &ldquo;meet a deadline&rdquo; is by a pretty wide margin my worst skill as a writer. Sorry, Lucian!<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>My favorite example of these narratives' strength comes from a <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/slacktivist/2008/10/08/false-witnesses-2/">post by Fred Clark</a>: &ldquo;Ask most people, &lsquo;Do you believe in vampires?&rsquo; and they will answer No. But ask those same people if vampires can be killed with a wooden stake and they&rsquo;ll tell you Yes.&rdquo; Even when we deny the literal truth of stories, they have important effects on us.<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>I am a trans woman and I&rsquo;m writing this piece primarily for women (for every kind of woman). If your life experience is something else, I unfortunately can&rsquo;t promise that this piece will be helpful, but I send my well-wishing and solidarity for any monster-narrative-reappropriating work of yours and also encourage you to notice and support others when they&rsquo;re using the tools I&rsquo;m writing about.<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>I&rsquo;m not an academic and I don&rsquo;t know of any scholarly/Theoryville work about marginalization and monster identity — but I&rsquo;d be completely shocked if none exists. If you know of work like that, please do tell me about it.<a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>These three identities are ways of being that I actively put on and take off. They&rsquo;re part of me, but they&rsquo;re much closer to being the kind of self-extension that an actor who plays the same part many times develops than to being part of a multiple system. For more information about what multiple systems are and aren&rsquo;t, I recommend <a href="http://healthymultiplicity.com/">listening to what they have to say for themselves</a>.<a href="#fnref:6" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>To reinforce, though, it&rsquo;s a universal aspect of marginalization. For example, black men are portrayed as sexual predators, physically disabled people as sexless, and poor people as sexually irresponsible.<a href="#fnref:7" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p>Here I&rsquo;m leaning on the discussion of &ldquo;interpretive labor&rdquo; in David Graeber&rsquo;s <em>Dead Zones of the Imagination</em>.<a href="#fnref:8" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:9">
<p>Consider <em>Creature From The Black Lagoon</em> and its portrayal of a monstrous Other with no voice, present in body but narrativized only by statements from the emissaries of the orthodox world.<a href="#fnref:9" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:10">
<p>Jon Carroll&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0811803074">Near Life Experiences</a>&rdquo; also has an excellent story about a space alien: &ldquo;She has considered the matter carefully; she has talked it over with a few trusted friends. And her conclusion: I am not crazy. I am only a space alien.&rdquo; It is a compassionate story.<a href="#fnref:10" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Promises I Make When I Talk To You]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/promises-i-make-when-i-talk-to-you/"/>
      
    <updated>2016-08-22T17:57:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/promises-i-make-when-i-talk-to-you</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I say this a lot in casual conversation, so I may as well write it down.
Here are some promises I&rsquo;m making when I&rsquo;m talking to people.
These hold for everyone I talk to; I also think they&rsquo;re good rules in general.</p>

<ol>
<li>I promise that you are the first and only judge of whether or not you care about something, whether or not it&rsquo;s important to you.</li>
<li>I promise that you are not boring when you talk about the stuff you care about.</li>
<li>I promise that it&rsquo;s okay to talk about what&rsquo;s important to you without apology or shame.</li>
<li>I promise that stuff that&rsquo;s important to you, is important enough to talk about: your life <em>should</em> matter to you!
That the rest of the world exists, doesn&rsquo;t obviate that the events of your life are important to you.</li>
<li>I promise it is okay to talk about the things you want and need to talk about.</li>
<li>I promise that it is okay to <em>not</em> talk about the things you don&rsquo;t want to talk about.</li>
<li>I promise it is okay to talk about things that you&rsquo;re unsure about.
Thinking about something by talking about it is a valuable tool.
Some thoughts are much easier to think with that tool than with wordless solo introspection.</li>
<li>I promise you are qualified to talk about your own experience and your own opinion.</li>
</ol>


<p>Basically, I like to think that when I talk to people I&rsquo;m fond of (I try to also do this with people I dislike, but I do not always succeed), I default to taking you seriously, listening as a peer, and assuming that you <em>matter.</em>
You deserve safety, health, and happiness.
We all deserve that.</p>

<p>My ideas here are heavily informed by Alice Miller&rsquo;s notion of a &ldquo;helping witness,&rdquo; but going into detail about that is another post (and a rather grim one, at that).</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nobody Gives A Shit About Freedom Zero &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://web.archive.org/web/20100608015359/http://diveintomark.org/archives/2008/01/17/of-canaries-and-coal-mines"/>
      
    <updated>2013-10-19T09:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/nobody-gives-a-shit-about-freedom-zero</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>So I went back in time a little today and noted Mark &ldquo;410 Gone&rdquo; Pilgrim&rsquo;s 2008 post,
&ldquo;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20100608015359/http://diveintomark.org/archives/2008/01/17/of-canaries-and-coal-mines">Of Canaries And Coal Mines</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>So after 18 months, I think we can safely say that no, Cory [Doctorow] and I were not &ldquo;canaries
in the coal mine.&rdquo; There are not hordes of fed-up consumers rejecting Apple&rsquo;s vision of
cryptographic lock-in. There are not mass graves where people ceremoniously dump their crippled,
non-general-purpose computing devices. Outside of Planet Debian and my own personal echo chamber,
nobody gives a shit about Freedom 0.</p></blockquote>

<p>Since then, things have only gone further in the direction that Pilgrim and Doctorow despaired
about. Apple has sold a preposterously large number of iPhones and iPads, large enough that it&rsquo;s
actually a bit difficult to get a grasp on how much the game has changed. I&rsquo;m just gonna quote
Marco Arment, since <a href="http://www.marco.org/2010/08/19/a-smartphone-retrospective">he absolutely called it</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Smartphones were an established consumer-electronics market with devices that people thought were
pretty cool, but often frustrating and with serious shortcomings and design flaws. &hellip; Other
manufacturers had neglected touchscreens for years, but Apple figured out how to do a touchscreen
well, and did.  Fans of the former types of smartphones and much of the tech press declared this
smartphone useless or not capable enough because of its lack of a keyboard, its non-removable
battery, its lack of expansion slots or ports, and other hardware features in which Apple chose
differently from what most other manufacturers were doing.  That ended up not mattering. Now,
most high-end smartphones look like [the iPhone]. &hellip; [Criticism of the iPad] ended up not
mattering. And now, other manufacturers are scrambling to build tablet products as quickly as
possible.  How do you think the subcompact, inexpensive computer category will look in three
years?</p></blockquote>

<p>Now, I&rsquo;m willing to take some cheap shots at this: it&rsquo;s what I do, I snicker a little cruelly when
I imagine Cory Doctorow <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20110716072627/http://www.adcouncil.org/default.aspx?id=132">in the role of Iron Eyes Cody</a>, a single tear rolling down
his cheek as he realizes that there are untold billions of people who don&rsquo;t care about &ldquo;Freedom
Zero.&rdquo; His tear is the tear of the modernist project, the realization that whoops, Western European
affluent-white-dude values are not in fact universal, and there may have to be some difficult
negotiation in the future to figure out (a) what values people advocate (b) what values they
actually live by and &copy; whether people can get along within the self-imposed constraints of (a)
and (b).</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t get genuinely angry at Doctorow, though. I&rsquo;m pretty bummed out when I think that billions
of people don&rsquo;t share <em>my</em> values, because I&rsquo;m as egotistical as anyone else and still have a nice
little candle in my heart of &ldquo;If <em>I</em> was running the show you&rsquo;d see some changes around here pretty
darn quick!&rdquo; At worst I think he&rsquo;s kinda naïve. It&rsquo;s borderline tautological to say that people
outside the engineer/hacker culture and professions do not share its ideological concerns. If you
walked up to an attorney cold and asked her what &ldquo;Freedom Zero&rdquo; was, you would probably get an
answer that has nothing to do with &ldquo;screws, not glue.&rdquo; The phrase might register as a complete
non-sequitur to a scuba dive instructor, a barista, a social worker, an undergraduate working the
register at a gas station, a costumed worker at Disneyland.</p>

<p>I acknowledge the counterargument of &ldquo;if people were more informed about the issue, they&rsquo;d care,&rdquo;
but you have to note that that&rsquo;s an argument you can make about <em>anything</em> and it&rsquo;s perilously
close to the fallacy of &ldquo;if people were better informed they&rsquo;d agree with me!&rdquo; So I think that it&rsquo;s
to be avoided. What I think is that people care about themselves first&mdash;thinking as our
rational-logical selves, paying rigorous attention to our professed ideals and to how our actions
fit them or fail to, is difficult and we&rsquo;re usually half-assing it. Yes, all of us, because we&rsquo;re
all fallible people prone to thinking more about what we want than whether getting it is worthwhile
or having it will actually make us as happy as we think.</p>

<p>One of my favorite jabs at this human tendency comes from the San Francisco stand-up comic Will
Durst, who <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/album/id260036485?partnerId=30&amp;siteID=k*tkOlz87uA">had a great riff on it in the early Bush years</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, man. That 300 bucks last August&mdash;that rebate check came in handy. I live
here in town, I paid off two parking tickets with it. But we had this windfall, we could have
done <em>anything</em> with it. We could have paid for every hot lunch program in America through the
year 2054. We could have put in a down payment on prescription drugs, which they talked about
last November and now we haven&rsquo;t heard Word One of. We could have done a lot.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh no, no, you can&rsquo;t do that. Uh-uh. No.&rdquo; &ldquo;Why?&rdquo; &ldquo;Well, the American People <em>want</em> tax cuts.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Well <strong>duh!</strong> The American People also want drive-through nickel beer night! The American People
want to lose weight by eating ice cream. The American People would chew off their own <em>foot</em> if
Oprah told them there was liquid gold in their ankle veins! The American People love the Home
Shopping Network because it&rsquo;s commercial-free.</p></blockquote>

<p>Humanity has a long and illustrious track record of wanting things that aren&rsquo;t particularly good
for us. I&rsquo;m not saying that Freedom Zero is one of those things. I&rsquo;m actually with Doctorow in that
I think that more people tinkering, exploring, and creating, is inherently a Good Thing. I just
think that Freedom Zero is a bit too narrowly defined, and thus Doctorow tends to undervalue good
things produced by people who don&rsquo;t care as much about freedom-to-tinker as he does. At this point
I think it&rsquo;s very safe to say that the &ldquo;iPads are for consumption&rdquo; canard is dead, but it&rsquo;s not
just that. The deal with iPhones and the Apple ecosystem in general, is that they&rsquo;re a
trade-off. It&rsquo;s fine for Doctorow to reject that trade-off for himself, but I think that he&rsquo;s in
error with his rationale for encouraging others to reject it; I think he&rsquo;s projecting his values
onto them. That&rsquo;s an error. If you go and look at what people are doing with their devices, you&rsquo;ll
find that they&rsquo;re doing things that are valuable to <em>them,</em> which is unrelated to what&rsquo;s valuable
to Cory Doctorow.</p>

<p>If you want to persuade others, to talk them into changing their behavior, you need to figure out
what&rsquo;s important to them and avoid assuming that what matters to you matters to them. That&rsquo;s part
of what makes persuasion hard&mdash;that and the massive disconnect between what we profess to want and
what we are actually happier to have. That&rsquo;s my vote for what people <em>should</em> care about: being
clear on our own desires.</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/nobody-gives-a-shit-about-freedom-zero/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Before Time Travel Was Easy-Peasy]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/before-time-travel-was-easy-peasy/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-10-12T14:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/before-time-travel-was-easy-peasy</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to have this here because apparently the lyrics-crap sites (and boy <em>there&rsquo;s</em> a genre of
website that makes you glad you got ad blocking and NoScript) haven&rsquo;t picked up on Deltron Event II
yet. As long as I&rsquo;m listening to this song a bunch I may as well transcribe it and have a reference
for the lyrics.</p>

<blockquote><p><em>Old-Timer 1:</em> Oh the city! Chillin' on the stoop in the future.</p>

<p><em>Old-Timer 2:</em> You said it, space friend!</p>

<p><em>Old-Timer 1</em>: Boy, I tell you things these days move too fast! Makes me wanna crack wise about how
it was back in the day. Yo, homeless robot! Drop a stupid-ass beatbox.</p>

<p><em>Homeless Robot:</em> Shit is not going well for homeless robot 235</p>

<p>{old-timer 1 raps}</p>

<p>Before a best seller meant your record went interstellar <br>
Before the impeccable smeller <br>
Before they banned Old Yeller <br>
In the wake of the Presidential dogfucking scandal <br></p>

<p>When astronauts rocked sports sandals and didn&rsquo;t have expandable mandibles <br>
And granules of Jack Daniels didn&rsquo;t heal the wounds of animals <br>
When botanicals still weren&rsquo;t a biological weapon <br>
In the war with the tarantulas <br></p>

<p>Back in the day before time travel was easy-peasy <br>
But now I go back, re-rap to make it sound repeaty <br>
Back in the day before time travel was easy-peasy <br>
Back in the day before time travel was easy-peasy <br>
Now we change history like the feat is measly <br></p>

<p>Stars these days don&rsquo;t know how good they have it <br>
We used to have plutonium in our jet pack and <br>
We had to take the supertube before it had hyperdrive <br>
Makes me wanna holler! Unh! But we&rsquo;re still alive! <br></p>

<p>{miscellaneous robot-abusing chatter}</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s an interesting bit of world-building, especially since it encourages us to mistrust the
narrators a bit - &ldquo;back in <em>my</em> day&rdquo; is already a tall-tale genre, and what might people who think
it&rsquo;s acceptable to abuse synthpersons be ignoring about the past?</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sprinkle Some PFAF On Your Morning &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://youtu.be/PP1TAQUsdt4"/>
      
    <updated>2013-07-07T07:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/sprinkle-some-pfaf-on-your-morning</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The aim was to explore the relationship between geometry and audio in unique ways.&rdquo; A delightful
compilation of micro-length animations, little glimpses of fantastic. Nice little brain-tickler.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PP1TAQUsdt4?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe>

<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/sprinkle-some-pfaf-on-your-morning/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Ultimatums]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/on-ultimatums/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-07-05T20:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/on-ultimatums</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don&rsquo;t issue ultimatums. Why not? Because you&rsquo;ll see yourself like this:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/s8YO5icNGn0?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe>


<p>And they&rsquo;ll see you like this:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_SbgEYBG-Y8?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe>


<p>Ultimatums are almost never the right tool. Use them as infrequently as possible, or a little less.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conspiracy Is Void]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-conspiracy-is-void/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-07-04T18:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-conspiracy-is-void</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While there are many things I like about Tumblr, I have a bottomless appetite for cheap shots at it
(e.g. <a href="http://mightygodking.com/2013/06/04/this-act-of-creative-and-historical-vandalism-is-not-technically-my-fault/">Folsom Prison Feels</a>) and a few serious beefs. The one that I&rsquo;m here to talk about
today is not about Tumblr as a company or platform but Tumblr as a culture, and particularly about
the crop of young social-justice advocates coming up through it. Of course I make allowance here
for the way that any generation of activists will spend a fair bit of time carping about the next:
good lord, just thinking of what particularly vocal second-wave feminists have to say about my
cohort makes the roots of my hair tingle.</p>

<p>I want to talk about this problem, though, partially because it&rsquo;s a failure of thought-rigor that
we&rsquo;re all prone to. I just see it more often in the Tumblr crowd&mdash;I have ideas about why that is,
but certainly they&rsquo;re not the only people capable of this fallacy. The fallacy goes like this:
given that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kyriarchy">The Patriarchy and other toxic power systems</a> exist, as unavoidably
widespread and oppressive forces, and given that they are a member of a class that those systems do
harm to, too many people behave as though the partiarchy (or power system <em>du jour</em>) is a
conspiracy that is out to get them particularly.</p>

<p>This is fallacious in both its halves: part of why the toxic power systems are so hard to deal with
is that they are <em>not</em> conspiracies, and that they are <em>not</em> after you in particular: it is
enough that you are there and you are a member of some disfavored class. Ignoring your
individuality is a feature of the system.</p>

<p>I am of course indebted to <a href="http://zingerella.livejournal.com/73987.html?format=light">an older exploration of the matter</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, there is no one Patriarch, leastaways not outside of Constantinople. There&rsquo;s no single dude
in a nifty hat at the top of the power structure, surrounded by scantily clad women whom he
feeds to tigers for his kicks and giggles. If it were only that simple, we could off the old
wanker, free the women and give them some trousers, find loving homes for the tigers, and have a
great party around the bonfire of his palace (after salvaging all the good art, books, and
chocolate). Alas, because the patriarchy is instead a very very old system that has warped
everyone&rsquo;s thinking right down to the sub-rational, axiomatic, non-verbal ideological level, it&rsquo;s
much more difficult to overthrow. (We&rsquo;ve seen how well wars against ideas work.)</p>

<p>[&hellip;] The Gentleman complained that calling the androcentric system of how things are, or male
privilege &ldquo;the patriarchy&rdquo; personifies it, and makes it seem like a conspiracy theory in which
all men are agents of this big conspiracy to keep women down. He said that saying that &ldquo;the
system serves to perpetuate itself,&rdquo; further personifies something that is, after all, merely a
structure put in place by people, and something that not all men support.</p>

<p>The patriarchy is not a system in the way that the Library of Congress system of cataloguing is a
system. It&rsquo;s not spelled out anywhere, no single person or group of people sat down and dreamed
it up, and people don&rsquo;t usually debate its merits over those of any other system that does the
same thing. I don&rsquo;t think even Men&rsquo;s Rights Activists get up in the morning and think &ldquo;Dude! I&rsquo;m
so glad I live in a patriarchy! I&rsquo;m gonna go subjugate me some women today!&rdquo; Instead we <strong>all</strong>
live in a system that exists on patriarchal premises.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about conspiracies. Conspiracy theories are a mode of thought that we&rsquo;re all prone to,
in varying degrees. This is because as humans, we are pattern-finders. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophenia">Apophenia</a>
is our life. Further, we&rsquo;re all self-centered&mdash;necessarily, for <em>your</em> life should be about
<em>you</em>, it can&rsquo;t healthily be about someone else. This has the side effect, though, that we&rsquo;re
prone to believing that events in the world around us are also about us. Very little that is
happening around you in your life is about you, though.</p>

<p>Conspiracy theories, then, are a natural outgrowth of this: they propose that something important
is being hidden by malicious actors working in concert. The combination of pattern-finding,
self-centeredness, and the simple fact that not all events in the world are comprehensible and few
are controllable, can lead any of us to explanations for those events that range into the
conspiratorial. A recent incident illustrated the tendency in what I find a grimly humorous way:
the 2010 paper <em>&ldquo;NASA faked the moon landing–therefore (climate) science is a hoax: an anatomy of
the motivated rejection of science&rdquo;</em> tentatively identified that people who think climate science
is a giant hoax or a conspiracy, also tend to have other conspiratorial-type
beliefs. Unsurprisingly, the rejecters of climate-change science had many criticisms of the
paper&mdash;which led to the same authors' 2013 paper <em>&ldquo;Recursive fury: conspiracist ideation in the
blogosphere in response to research on conspiracist ideation,&rdquo;</em> whose subtitle basically sums it up
(cheap shot interlude: &ldquo;Recursive Fury&rdquo; is my punk-covers-of-Douglas-Hofstatder band).</p>

<p>A <a href="http://academia.edu/1207098/Dead_and_alive_Beliefs_in_contradictory_conspiracy_theories">2012 paper from the University of Kent</a> uses a different way of illustrating the
point:</p>

<blockquote><p>Conspiracy theories can form a monological belief system: A self-sustaining worldview comprised
of a network of mutually supportive beliefs. The present research shows that even mutually
incompatible conspiracy theories are positively correlated in endorsement. In Study 1, the more
participants believed that Princess Diana faked her own death, the more they believed that she
was murdered. In Study 2, the more participants believed that Osama Bin Laden was already dead
when U.S. special forces raided his compound in Pakistan, the more they believed he is still
alive. Hierarchical regression models showed that mutually incompatible conspiracy theories are
positively associated because both are associated with the view that the authorities are engaged
in a cover-up. The monological nature of conspiracy belief appears to be driven not by conspiracy
theories directly supporting one another but by broader beliefs supporting conspiracy theories in
general.</p></blockquote>

<p><em>Recursive Fury</em>, meanwhile, uses a six-point set of criteria for conspiratorial thinking:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Nefarious Intent:</strong> Assuming that the presumed conspirators have nefarious intentions. For
example, if person X assumes that blogger Y colluded with the New York Times to publish a paper
damaging to X, then X presumes nefarious intent on the part of Y.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Persecuted Victim:</strong> Self-identifying as the victim of an organised persecution.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Nihilistic Skepticism:</strong> Refusing to believe anything that doesn&rsquo;t fit into the conspiracy
theory. Note that &ldquo;conspiracy theory&rdquo; here is a fairly broad term and need not involve a global
conspiracy (e.g., that NASA faked the moon landing) but can refer to small-scale events and
hypotheses.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Nothing Occurs By Accident:</strong> Weaving any small random event into the conspiracy narrative.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Something Must Be Wrong:</strong> Switching liberally between different, even contradictory
conspiracy theories that have in common only the presumption that there is something wrong in
the official account by the alleged conspirators. Thus, people may simultaneously believe that
Princess Diana faked her own death and that she was assassinated by MI5.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Self-Sealing Reasoning:</strong> Interpreting any evidence against the conspiracy as evidence for the
conspiracy. For example, when climate scientists are exonerated of any wrong-doing 9 times over
by different investigations, this is reinterpreted to imply that the climate-change conspiracy
involves not just the world’s climate scientists but also the investigating bodies and
associated governments.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I think it&rsquo;s crucially important here to avoid saying &ldquo;oh man those conspiracy buffs, they&rsquo;ll
believe anything.&rdquo; Conspiracy theories are a pattern of thought that we are <em>all</em> vulnerable to. In
varying degrees, true, but all of us are vulnerable, and a feeling of certainty is no defense. This
is part of why we feminists, we activists, we strivers for a better world, need to especially
beware of conspiracy-theory thinking. <strong>The patriarchy is not a conspiracy.</strong></p>

<p>We encounter the patriarchy and related toxic power systems most often in a context where they are
likely to do us personal harm: of course we take it personally! But you will go grievously wrong
assuming that the system (as opposed to individual actors) dislikes you personally. You are a
wonderful person but conspiracies, as Mr. Assange tirelessly reminds us, are needy beasts and you
are not worth the effort of keeping a conspiracy running. Instead, the patriarchy is a system of
interlocking systems, which long ago passed the point where the beneficiaries and those hoping for
their table-scraps needed only act in furtherance of their self-interest, without conspiring with
anyone else, for the system to be perpetuated. When we are harmed, when we are in pain, it is
difficult to believe that it is not about us, but it really isn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Another face of this system is the United States' mainstream media&mdash;or to call it more accurately,
the propaganda system by which Official Facts are distributed (I am drawing heavily from Chomsky
here). This system is harmful to many of us, and has the effect of maintaining elite power at the
expense of the common good. It too is not a conspiracy and it does not care about you, the
news-consumer, personally. It is just the same: the system is rigged such that actors pursue their
own self-interest independently and perpetuate the system in that way. That is precisely why the
propaganda system, and the patriarchal power structures in general, are so difficult to push back
against: they are in a sense decentralized.</p>

<p>No matter how much power he may personally wield, it is vanishingly rare that a beneficiary thinks
of himself as blessed with the power of a system backing him. Indeed he generally has had to expend
considerable effort disposing of rivals for that benefit, and takes this effort for evidence of
merit. He who reaches the VP suite or the Senate or the upper echelons of an important bureaucracy,
has had to do a great deal of work and apply a great deal of ingenuity. What he generally resists
seeing, is that someone who did as much work and applied as much ingenuity, but who did not have
the benefit of a system of power behind them, would not be rewarded in the same way (they may in
fact be punished: there&rsquo;s a strong argument that lynchings were
<a href="http://bradhicks.livejournal.com/378012.html?format=light">more an economic crime than a hate crime</a>).</p>

<p>Of course there are still further complications. The baneful power systems that we&rsquo;re trying to
disrupt operate as interlocking systems and at the most abstract level, they are systems of
interactions between classes of person (not just class in the economic sense, but in just about any
way you can divide people into Us and Them). But the operation of these large systems is to spawn
smaller systems, which may repeat the process, until actual work and reification-of-hierarchy gets
done at the margins. I am not a class of person unto myself, nor is a police officer, but together
we operate the system whereby the state asserts a monopoly on
<a href="http://crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/violence.php">the use and definition of violence</a>.</p>

<p>The reason that it&rsquo;s important to note this fractal nature of systems is that if you follow it down
far enough, you will find conspiracies. Small, petty, cruel conspiracies that ruin lives, bodies,
and minds, they are nasty operations&mdash;but they are not the system that they are embedded in,
rather they are a product of it. However, they are rarer than you might think, because the secrecy
criteria is important. Remember that we&rsquo;re not counting the Family Research Council as a
conspiracy: they are actors colluding to do harm to queers, women, and pretty much everyone, but
they&rsquo;re not doing so in secret: they are quite clear about their goals, membership, tactics,
etc. They issue press releases. There are plenty of subsystems like them, including some that do
target individuals, but we need to resist letting those lure us into conspiratorial thinking.</p>

<p>The six-point scale from <em>Recursive Fury</em> can be useful for pushing against this tendency: it&rsquo;s not
a panacea, but it is a useful reminder that we&rsquo;re talking about big sloppy human systems, not
against powerful, malicious schemers. Thinking in terms of systems is an important part of the
activist toolkit, because individual actions don&rsquo;t happen in a vacuum. They have antecedents and
causes. Even on the interpersonal level, a person is not any of their actions: they are at the very
least actions and discourses over time, which is very different. For groups, likewise. Conspiracies
are rare enough that you should assume that events in the world around you are <em>not</em> the result of
a conspiracy, even if they cause you pain and are difficult to understand. Perhaps especially then.</p>

<p>Now, I know a bunch of people who spend a lot of time in <a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2008/03/the_security_mi_1.html">the security mindset</a> who&rsquo;re
going to want some caveats to be attached to this. So: there certainly are situations where you&rsquo;ll
want to worry about conspiracies, and some of those conspiracies will have an agenda that amounts
to &ldquo;kill you if you get too inconvenient to entrenched power systems.&rdquo; The best example is how
police departments and the FBI routinely employ <em>agents provocateur</em> against anyone with a remotely
anti-hierarchical agenda (to the point of being assholes to Food Not Bombs, wielders of one of the
most innocuous activism tactics imaginable). However, these situations are both rare and
illustrative that conspiracies are expensive and difficult. The big-picture system being resisted
and disrupted, is not a conspiracy.</p>

<p>I started out by talking about Tumblr, but this is a problem that&rsquo;s specific to human cognition,
not specific to Tumblr. Tumblr just happens to be full of young folks, who are normal young folks
and thus charmingly overconfident and full of anger, not yet scarred in the specific way that
produces a certain <a href="http://woborders.wordpress.com/2012/02/13/debating-tactics-remember-to-ask-what-works/">pragmatism</a>, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murphy%27s_law">parsimony of causes</a>, and a
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor">cynical optimism about others' actions</a>. Age is no guarantee that a person will come
around to a productive approach&mdash;which is to say, eschewing dramatic first resorts, patient in
proportion to how they hope for their own (inevitable) follies to be treated with patience, and
always curious as to whether there is some item of mutual agreement that could be worked towards
rather than having yet another argument.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the real sin of conspiratorial thinking, if you ask me: by presenting tempting-but-wrong
explanations for the world, it will very effectively keep you from <em>getting things done.</em> As you
make your way through the world you cannot avoid encountering the painful, the inexplicable, and
the unjust. Working against them is difficult&mdash;and conspiratorial thinking will sabotage your
work. Perhaps we could consider inverting the checklist from <em>Recursive Fury</em>:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Selfish Intent:</strong> Assume that other people primarily care about themselves. They&rsquo;re not
stupid, they have a whole life to live, but that life is about them and not about you.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Bemused Observer:</strong> Be deeply conservative in assumptions about whether or not people are out
to get you, especially in an organized manner. People generally organize for themselves, not for
you (see 1).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Judicious Acceptance:</strong> Systems made up of humans are messy, not neat, and almost never
elegant. Dramatized stories about them almost always leave out the screw-ups, friction, and
dawdling. If a conspiracy looks excellently efficient, slick, and deft, it might not exist.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Acknowledgement Of Accidents:</strong> Plenty of things happen by accident or without
planning. Account for impulse and coincidence when you account for people&rsquo;s actions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>If There&rsquo;s No Plan, It Can&rsquo;t Be Going Wrong:</strong> Acknowledging that much of the world is not
just beyond your control, but beyond anyone&rsquo;s control, undermines the idea that a conspiracy is
bending events towards their ends. Of course the world is not quite as you would like it&mdash;but
you are just like everyone else in percieving that the world is imperfect.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Open-Ended Reasoning:</strong> Avoid at all costs becoming locked into non-falsifiable patterns of
thought: if you have a belief that can neither be proven nor disproven, you have a belief that
needs to be harshly examined. This is especially true of deciding that people you interact with
are malicious or untrustworthy: once you commit to that belief, you commit to a pattern of
actions that will make it extraordinarily hard for them to behave benevolently towards you or
extend trust to you, and your <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">confirmation bias</a> will carry the day.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Of course this is just a sketch towards the general plan of resisting conspiratorial thinking, but
it&rsquo;s a starting-place and that&rsquo;s important to have. The point of a starting-place is that you don&rsquo;t
remain there, that you make a concerted effort of getting to somewhere else. The metaphor of travel
also gives us this: look at the whole journey from time to time, not just the next step. Cultivate
a flexibility of perspective. After all, one way of looking at patriarchy is to call it the
conspiracy theory that women are all out to get you.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well, There Goes *That* Plan &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/appstore/dev/stdeula/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-07-03T13:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/well-there-goes-that-plan</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>Found in the <a href="http://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/appstore/dev/stdeula/">iTunes End User License Agreement</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>You also agree that you will not use these products for any purposes prohibited by United States
law, including, without limitation, the development, design, manufacture or production of
nuclear, missiles, or chemical or biological weapons.</p></blockquote>

<p>Total spoilsports. How am I supposed to work on my mad-science supervillainess world domination
plans without my Genius mix?</p>

<p>(<a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/2013/06/28/itunes-license-agreement-stipulates-you-cant-make-nuclear-weapons/">via</a>)</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/well-there-goes-that-plan/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Last Big Secret &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2013-05-02-the-quest-for-shadow-of-the-colossuss-last-big-secret"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-29T13:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-last-big-secret</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p><em>Shadow of the Colossus</em> is one of the great achievements of videogames. I tend towards comparing
it to <em>Super Metroid,</em> although one could go other directions. Both games cultivate an atmosphere
of solitude and the uncanny, focusing on a solo protagonist in an alien place. They&rsquo;re not only
masterfully executed, great fun as games, but also are achievers of a high ambition in games: they
expand the player&rsquo;s sense of the possible. The team who built <em>Ico</em> expanded and refined their
ideas, and as a result, <em>Shadow</em> was a truly great game, expanding a mass audience&rsquo;s sense of what
the medium of videogames was capable of.</p>

<p>All of this is on my mind because I recently encountered a Eurogamer article,
<a href="http://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2013-05-02-the-quest-for-shadow-of-the-colossuss-last-big-secret">&ldquo;The Quest for Shadow of the Colossus' Last Big Secret,&rdquo;</a> pointing out that a game
pushing ten years old is still drawing a small crowd of searchers determined to find everything
that can be found in the game. I&rsquo;m pleasantly reminded of how the executive-meddling-crippled
<em>KOTOR II</em> was the beneficiary of a fan effort to restore cut content and fix outstanding bugs. The
story of the searchers here is a compelling one, and I recommend it to you along with other
<a href="http://www.glitterberri.com/shadow-of-the-colossus/">fan-made</a> <a href="http://lparchive.org/Shadow-of-the-Colossus/">amplifications</a> of the game.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re feeling particularly nostalgic, you may wish to watch this
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dbUsuIr28SA&amp;list=PL894C9468F2597100">playthrough of the HD version</a> of the game as you read:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dbUsuIr28SA?list=PL894C9468F2597100?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe>



<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-last-big-secret/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Idea Will Not Work (The Following Philosophical Objections May Also Apply)]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/your-idea-will-not-work-the-following-philosophical-objections-may-also-apply/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-25T11:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/your-idea-will-not-work-the-following-philosophical-objections-may-also-apply</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was reminded of the classic template criticizing <a href="http://craphound.com/spamsolutions.txt">attempts to curb spam</a>,
a quiet little text file on Cory Doctorow&rsquo;s site, by my attempts to find the
<a href="http://secretvolcanobase.org/~tef/distributed_social_networks.txt">version about social networks</a>. It turns out there are quite a few
snowclones of this, and since I&rsquo;m a kitty who adores remix culture, I decided to try to find a few
more.</p>

<p>There are a few, and I&rsquo;d love to be made aware of more. Things that so far will not work:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.metafilter.com/85761/How-To-Save-Media#2776753">Your Plan To Save Journalism</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forum.rpg.net/showthread.php?396569-Trusted-Computing-to-save-PC-gaming-from-pirates&amp;p=8923949#post8923949">Your Approach To Fighting Videogame Piracy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forums.riftgame.com/game-discussions/classes-telara/rogue-discussion/260412-how-fix-bards-yet-another-suggestion.html#post3193324">Your Idea For Patching Bard</a></li>
<li><a href="http://jricher.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/porn_solutions.txt">Your Plan To Restrict Access To Objectionable Content</a></li>
<li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=608030">Your Approach To &ldquo;Fixing&rdquo; Advertising</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2009/01/26/689213/-Your-Idea-To-Fix-the-Housing-Crisis-Will-Not-Work">Your Idea To Fix The Housing Crisis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=89772.msg988857#msg988857">Your Countermeasures Against Bitcoin</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.owlfolio.org/research/on-replacements-for-passwords/">Your Replacement For Passwords</a></li>
<li><a href="http://qntm.org/calendar">Your Approach To Calendar Reform</a></li>
<li><a href="http://eu.battle.net/sc2/en/forum/topic/443017082#2">Your Enhancement To Battle.Net</a></li>
<li><a href="http://justenoughcraig.blogspot.com/2010/09/heavily-borrowed-from-original-spam.html">Your Economic Solution</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.snijders-it.nl/2010/10/location-separation-protocol-checklist.htlm">Your Method For Reducing The Size Of The Internet&rsquo;s Routing Table</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forums.theregister.co.uk/forum/1/2014/02/26/nsa_snooping_tactics_will_be_copied_by_criminals_in_35_years/#c_2119375">Your Tactic For Privacy On The Internet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.teamliquid.net/forum/user-streams/124660-stream-destiny?page=149#2965">Your Attempt To Justify Racist Comments</a></li>
<li><a href="http://carlos.bueno.org/2007/09/persai-your-company-advocates-x-pseudo.html">Your Startup Based On Scraped Content</a> (winceworthy)</li>
<li><a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Free_feminist_consulting_form_letter">Your Halfassed Attempt To Buy Feminist Cred</a></li>
<li><a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/More_women_in_CS_form_letter">Your Attempt To Spread Fatuous Justifications For Misogyny In Startup Culture</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.giantitp.com/forums/showthread.php?99887-Never-noticed-this-rule-before&amp;p=5496355&amp;viewfull=1#post5496355">Your Method For Fixing Editing And Rules Problems In Tabletop RPGs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I love how, at best, the form is a way to make critical thinking cheaper. Of course it may also
fail to do that&mdash;but on a good day, it&rsquo;s a way to repudiate bad ideas by contextualizing them, by
adding relevant information instead of by shouting. Snowcloning it into different contexts is also
at a sweet-spot difficulty level: easy enough to be tempting, but hard enough to be a bit of
serious work worth respecting. It&rsquo;s a great way to summarize &ldquo;here is the bar to entry for new
techniques, this problem is in fact hard.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Another amusing thing is how often the &ldquo;Asshats&rdquo; and &ldquo;No-one will be able to find the guy or
collect the money&rdquo; objections appear verbatim. Some things cross many, many fields of human
endeavour.</p>

<p>For bonus points, here&rsquo;s someone making an interesting argument that the original form was wrong,
<a href="http://blog.jwhitham.org/2013/05/users-of-email-will-not-put-up-with-it.html">&ldquo;Users Of Email Will Not Stand For It&rdquo;</a>, and a MetaFilter user who claims to have come
up with <a href="http://ask.metafilter.com/122211/technical-legislative-marketbased-vigilante#1751153">the original</a>.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shit One Cannot Make Up, Chapter 25233 &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://kottke.org/13/05/small-batch-artisanal-high-fructose-corn-syrup"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-19T08:07:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shit-one-cannot-make-up-chapter-25233</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>Small-batch, artisanal high-fructose corn syrup!</p>

<blockquote><p>Maya Weinstein has created a DIY kit for making your own HFCS (high-fructose corn syrup). You may
have already guessed that it&rsquo;s an art project and that the artist lives in Brooklyn.</p></blockquote>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shit-one-cannot-make-up-chapter-25233/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[She's Been Working On The Railroad &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/daylightatheism/2013/06/atlas-shrugged-how-to-build-a-railroad/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-15T12:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>Now I am the kind of person who read <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> once in high school and came away with an
uneasy feeling rather than a burning conviction: it felt somehow petty to me. This is probably
because I was reading Asimov&rsquo;s <em>Foundation</em> novels at the same time, and the contrast between Hari
Seldon and John Galt was dramatic and deeply unflattering to Galt. Faced with a cruel and
overbearing government, a lone genius opts to found a colony of the like-minded in a secluded
place. However, their tactics are strikingly different: Galt opts to affirmatively destroy the
system, heedless of consequences, while Hari Seldon is all about mindfulness of the consequences. I
think that&rsquo;s one of the things that really gets to me about the center of the Randian movement:
despite pretensions of intellectualism, they are blinded both to where they came from and where
they are going. That is not a good recipe for a movement.</p>

<p>Those are broad strokes, though: there is a specific thing I&rsquo;d forgotten, that Adam Lee ably points
out:</p>

<blockquote><p>Of all the businesses Rand could have chosen for her heroes, I always thought that railroads were
a bad choice to show the superiority of laissez-faire capitalism. After all, railroads, like
other forms of infrastructure, almost always take major government support and investment to
build. [&hellip;] In reality, the first American transcontinental railroad required major government
financial support&mdash;to the tune of $16,000 per mile, rising to $48,000 per mile over the Rocky
Mountains&mdash;plus extensive land grants. Modern engineering projects of similar scope, like the
Keystone XL pipeline, have been embroiled in court fights with dozens of private landowners who
don’t want to sell, and Keystone’s builders have been extremely aggressive about invoking eminent
domain.</p></blockquote>

<p>The story proceeds from merely unrealistic, as Lee notes here, to gleefully barbaric. It is part of
a pattern where every time I think &ldquo;well, I should maybe give <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> another chance, as
literature if not as dogma,&rdquo; some excerpt or another comes along and convinces me that Rand was
definitely the predecessor to L. Ron Hubbard: promulgating a con-job religion on the backs of some
awful sci-fi novels. Ugh.</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Reason Empire Was The Best Of The Original Trilogy &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://paka.livejournal.com/3362773.html"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-15T11:03:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/another-reason-empire-was-the-best-of-the-original-trilogy</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>My pal Paka has a great point about <em>The Empire Strikes Back</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Okay, so <strong>The Empire Strikes Back</strong> ends with the heroes failing miserably. They <strong>win,</strong> but
they do so failing. Han basically dies, keeping Chewie from losing his temper and getting Leia
killed in the process. Luke basically suicides but he doesn&rsquo;t join the Dark Side. And Lando, I&rsquo;ve
realized, gives up everything rather than being a nice little stoolie.</p>

<p>Think about this for a bit. Han has nothing to lose other than his life, two friends, and a ship
which has already been impounded. Luke would lose his ethics at the price of very probably
helping Vader kill Palpatine and at some point killing Vader and becoming Emperor himself. It
makes me grind teeth to realize that Leia is sort of The Obligatory Woman and doesn&rsquo;t really get
a character moment like that. Lando loses the most. He&rsquo;s been hoping this whole time that if he
plays nice with the legal authorities (and note here, he&rsquo;s one of three Black guys you ever see
in that universe, so he&rsquo;s the minority made good in a system run by crusty white rich people),
they&rsquo;ll let him have his business and his friends can make bail, and then the deal gets worse and
worse and worse. Lando could potentially accept worse and worse and worse and he&rsquo;d still come out
of it with a retirement plan, health care, stock options, and enough income to keep himself in
Colt 40 and awesome capes for the rest of his life. Things which he probably didn&rsquo;t have quite
that much of before when he was Lando scraping by on gambling. And boom, it&rsquo;s all gone because
being Lando freaking Calrissian is at the end way more important to him.</p></blockquote>

<p>Lando Calrissian has always complicated the <em>Star Wars</em> universe, and that&rsquo;s a good thing. I like
Paka&rsquo;s reading here quite a bit.</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/another-reason-empire-was-the-best-of-the-original-trilogy/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[EDIRD: Morphine-Seeky]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-morphine-seeky/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-14T10:01:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-morphine-seeky</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was struck recently by how <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060512806/?tag=usefultigress-20">Neal Stephenson&rsquo;s Cryptonomicon</a> has remained
relevant. Here&rsquo;s one of my favorite passages.</p>

<blockquote><p>Men who believe that they are accomplishing something by speaking speak in a different way from
men who believe that speaking is a waste of time. Bobby Shaftoe has learned most of his practical
knowledge&mdash;how to fix a car, butcher a deer, throw a spiral, talk to a lady, kill a Nip&mdash;from
the latter type of man. For them, trying to do anything by talking is like trying to pound in a
nail with a screwdriver. Sometimes you can even see the desperation spread over such a man&rsquo;s face
as he listens to himself speak.</p>

<p>Men of the other type, the ones who use speech as a tool of their work, who are confident and
fluent, aren&rsquo;t necessarily more intelligent, or even more educated. It took Shaftoe a long time
to figure that out. Anyway, everything was neat and tidy in Bobby Shaftoe&rsquo;s mind until he met two
of the men in Detachment 2702: Enoch Root and Lawrence Pritchard Waterhouse. [He began] to
suspect that there might be a third category of man, a kind so rare that Shaftoe never met any of
them until now.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t like the word &lsquo;addict&rsquo; because it has terrible connotations,&rdquo; Root says one day, as they
are sunning themselves on the afterdeck. &ldquo;Instead of slapping a label on you, the Germans would
describe you as &lsquo;Morphiumsüchtig.&rsquo; The verb &lsquo;suchen&rsquo; means to seek. So that might be translated,
loosely, as &lsquo;morphine seeky&rsquo; or even more loosely as &lsquo;morphine seeking.&rsquo; I prefer &lsquo;seeky&rsquo; because
it means that you have an inclination to seek morphine.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What the fuck are you talking about?&rdquo; Shaftoe says.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, suppose you have a roof with a hole in it. That means it is a leaky roof. It&rsquo;s leaky all
the time even if it&rsquo;s not raining at the moment. But it&rsquo;s only leaking when it happens to be
raining. In the same way, morphine seeky means that you always have this tendency to look for
morphine, even if you are not looking for it at the moment. But I prefer both of them to
&lsquo;addict,&rsquo; because they are adjectives modifying Bobby Shaftoe instead of a noun that obliterates
Bobby Shaftoe.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;So what&rsquo;s the point?&rdquo; Shaftoe asks. He asks this because he is expecting Root to give him an
order, which is usually what men of the talkative sort end up doing after jabbering on for a
while. But no order seems to be forthcoming, because that&rsquo;s not Root&rsquo;s agenda. Root just felt
like talking about words. [&hellip;] Waterhouse never gives direct orders, so men of the first
category don&rsquo;t know what to make of him. But apparently men of the second category fare no
better; such men usually talk like they have an agenda in their heads and they are checking off
boxes as they go, but Waterhouse&rsquo;s conversation doesn&rsquo;t go anywhere in particular. He speaks, not
as a way of telling you a bunch of stuff he&rsquo;s already figured out, but as a way of making up a
bunch of new shit as he goes along. And he always seems to be hoping that you&rsquo;ll join in. Which
no one ever does, except for Enoch Root.</p></blockquote>

<p>There are two things that I find compelling about this incident. One is that people&rsquo;s relationships
to words and meaning is a leitmotif of the book, and this moment makes explicit (as opposed to
demonstrating) that as Bobby Shaftoe does, you can live a satisfying life without getting deeply
into word-games and syntactic manipulation. The world around you is available to you directly:
abstractions are not the only valid way to engage with it. Randy, another protagonist, by contrast
worries that he&rsquo;s &ldquo;too much of a Platonist&rdquo; and spends a lot of time introspecting as he
participates in a plot to build a digital currency founded on cryptography&mdash;on meaning selectively
obscured.</p>

<p>The basic setup of the book, where one set of characters are attempting to jumpstart a digital,
crypto-based currency and are harassed by the US Government, should definitely remind you of
BitCoin, other digital currency experiments, and the particular tactics which the 2000-2013
government of the United States uses to retain power. That part&rsquo;s
easy. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Totalitarian">A government that demands ability to participate in every aspect of civic and private life</a>,
necessarily reacts with great hostility to the idea that people might have real privacy at all, let
alone a right to it. There has been plenty of ink spilled about this, so I&rsquo;ll leave off for the
moment.</p>

<p>The other way in which this passage sheds light is the spiel about being &ldquo;morphine-seeky.&rdquo; I have
come to find that very important to my views, or at least to be a good way of articulating
them. It&rsquo;s pretty much pure <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sapir-Whorf_Hypothesis">Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis</a> stuff: the way that you describe the
world has a feedback loop with how you percieve the world and how you act on those descriptions and
perceptions (notice again the connection to the book&rsquo;s themes about constructing meaning). This is
why I bristle when someone uses the shorthand &ldquo;illegals&rdquo; for anyone (in practice, anyone brown) who
is in the United States for an extended period of time without having gone through the
Wagner-length tragedy that is our immigration bureaucracy. &ldquo;Illegal&rdquo; is a noun that obliterates the
actual person&mdash;and a certain political persuasion likes little better than an excuse to do
violence to the person of immigrants or suspected immigrants.</p>

<p>It is also a good principle to keep in mind when we describe one another. I share a community, the
furry subculture, with a lot of people with mental health problems. We have a bit more practice at
dealing with the problem of integrating everyone in the community healthily, but we are just
people, and so we fail as often as anyone else at coping. One of the pole-stars for me in this
situation is Root&rsquo;s advice: adjectives, not nouns. Don&rsquo;t reduce people to their disabilities, their
tropes, their health problems, their kinks, their politics, or to the last thing they did that hurt
your feelings.</p>

<p>Of course it is also a good guideline for life in general: if you are reducing people to
conveniently dumbed-down nouns, you are refusing to acknowledge their full personhood. This is a
reliable way to rationalize harmful behavior. I buy into the notion that one of the roots of evil
is treating people as means to an end, rather than as ends in themselves&mdash;as fully realized beings
with their own aspirations, plans, and flaws. There is no simplification of a person that stands up
to great scrutiny, that works in the general case.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Unexpected Perspective &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2013/06/ben-bernanke-to-princeton-grads-the-world-isnt-fair-and-you-all-got-lucky/276471/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-13T11:20:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/an-unexpected-perspective</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>Of all the people, Ben Bernanke saying this!</p>

<blockquote><p>We have been taught that meritocratic institutions and societies are fair. Putting aside the
reality that no system, including our own, is really entirely meritocratic, meritocracies may be
fairer and more efficient than some alternatives. But fair in an absolute sense? Think about
it. A meritocracy is a system in which the people who are the luckiest in their health and
genetic endowment; luckiest in terms of family support, encouragement, and, probably, income;
luckiest in their educational and career opportunities; and luckiest in so many other ways
difficult to enumerate&mdash;these are the folks who reap the largest rewards. <strong>The only way for
even a putative meritocracy to hope to pass ethical muster, to be considered fair, is if those
who are the luckiest in all of those respects also have the greatest responsibility to work hard,
to contribute to the betterment of the world, and to share their luck with others.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>That is a deeply surprising and encouraging thing to hear one of the mascots of capitalism
saying. It is perhaps the case that saying this mostly accomplishes making him and the rich white
(mostly) kids he&rsquo;s addressing feel good about themselves. But it is still a true thing said
straightforwardly and firmly, and I applaud that.</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/an-unexpected-perspective/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rounding Off &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://www.thisiscolossal.com/2013/05/the-beetle-sphere-an-actual-1953-vw-beetle-formed-into-a-perfect-sphere-by-ichwan-noor/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-12T09:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/rounding-off</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<p>I carp about Twitter, but I&rsquo;m definitely importing some of my tropisms from there to here. This one
is a motif that I hope you&rsquo;ve heard by now.</p>

<p>And now for something &hellip; completely different:
<a href="http://www.thisiscolossal.com/2013/05/the-beetle-sphere-an-actual-1953-vw-beetle-formed-into-a-perfect-sphere-by-ichwan-noor/">a spherical automobile</a>.</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/rounding-off/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[EDIRD: Why Do Birds Suddenly Appear]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-why-do-birds-suddenly-appear/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-12T09:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-why-do-birds-suddenly-appear</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/re-6eOhrejE?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe>


<p>Speaking of cinema: <em>Mirrormask</em> was quite a thing. For one thing, giving Dave McKean millions of
dollars to make a movie results in visual deliciousness. For another thing, looking back, I see
this prefiguring a bunch of my friends' kinks. Hello clockwork robot mind-control scene with a hint
of transformation!</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Face Of The Clock &#x1f42f; ]]></title>
      <link href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2012/03/12/120312fa_fact_zalewski?currentPage=all"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-12T08:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-face-of-the-clock</id>
    
    <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[<blockquote><p>There were darker resonances, too. People went to the movies to lose track of time; this video
would pound viewers with an awareness of how long they’d been languishing in the dark. It would
evoke the laziest of modern pleasures—channel surfing—except that the time wasted would be
painfully underlined.</p>

<p>He would not be creating the first film with a running time of precisely one day. That
distinction went to <strong>24 Hour Psycho</strong>, a 1993 work, by Douglas Gordon, that stretched
Hitchcock’s taut thriller into excruciatingly portentous art. And Andy Warhol, in his 1964 film
“Empire”—eight hours of stationary footage of the Empire State Building fading into darkness—had
created a work whose point was to make viewers &ldquo;see time go by.&rdquo; There was a lineage of
avant-garde cinema that, with varying degrees of obscurity, examined the temporal qualities of
film. Marclay’s contribution to the cinema of duration, though, would be pleasurable to watch. He
sensed a creepy challenge. If his film was sufficiently seductive, he might coax people to sit
for hours, literally watching their lives tick away.</p></blockquote>

<p>Christian Marclay&rsquo;s <em>The Clock</em> is also something I&rsquo;d quite like to see. It sometimes feels strange
to me, wanting to see movies even though I probably won&rsquo;t see them. <em>The Clock</em> draws me
particularly because it&rsquo;s about the artifice of cinema, the way it gets into Picasso-style
lies-that-tell-truths&mdash;a subject that&rsquo;s grown on me over the years. Maybe I am okay with movies
and I just dislike theatres? At any rate it might be time to reconsider my stance that video is
just not a good match for me. I am not particularly sad to be wrong: people exceeding expectations
is a cause for celebration.</p>

<p>As a side note, the New Yorker seems to be a big fan of <em>The Clock</em>: there&rsquo;s also
&ldquo;<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/03/night-shift-with-the-clock.html">Night shift with The Clock</a>&rdquo; and &ldquo;<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/07/is-the-clock-worth-the-time.html">Is The Clock worth the time?</a>&rdquo; which
are both decent (and much shorter) reads, as well as
<a href="http://kottke.org/13/06/about-an-hour-of-christian-marclays-the-clock">Kottke&rsquo;s roundup of bootlegged clips</a> from the movie, which for obvious reasons is shown
as an installation and not available for purchase.</p>
<a rel="full-article" href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-face-of-the-clock/">Permalink</a>]]>
    </content>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
      
      <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killing In The Name Of]]></title>
      <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/killing-in-the-name-of/"/>
      
    <updated>2013-06-11T22:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/killing-in-the-name-of</id>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/SD5oMxbMcHM?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe>


<p>Werner Herzog and Errol Morris are collaborating on a documentary! I mean, that right there and I&rsquo;m
pretty much sold (although they are both in producer roles, not directing, but those two together
is a hell of a recommendation). Even if I wasn&rsquo;t, the story of <em>The Act Of Killing</em> (and isn&rsquo;t that
one hell of a name?) is compelling:</p>

<blockquote><p>When the government of Indonesia was overthrown by the military in 1965, Anwar and his friends
were promoted from small-time gangsters who sold movie theatre tickets on the black market to
death squad leaders. They helped the army kill more than one million alleged communists, ethnic
Chinese, and intellectuals in less than a year. As the executioner for the most notorious death
squad in his city, Anwar himself killed hundreds of people with his own hands. [&hellip;] Anwar and
his friends agree to tell us the story of the killings. But their idea of being in a movie is not
to provide testimony for a documentary: they want to star in the kind of films they most love
from their days scalping tickets at the cinemas. [And so] we challenge Anwar and his friends to
develop fiction scenes about their experience of the killings, adapted to their favorite genres:
gangster, western, musical. They write the scripts. They play themselves. And they play their
victims.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is one hell of a premise, and the trailer is great. I want to see this so badly.</p>

<p>As an aside, this also provides even more of an illustration of how awful, awful, <strong><em>awful</em></strong> Mark
Millar&rsquo;s supremely shitty and soul-of-the-world-impoverishing
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wanted_%28comics%29">Wanted</a> was and how Millar should live in
shame for having created it.</p>

<blockquote><p>Today, Anwar is revered as a founding father of a right-wing paramilitary organization that grew
out of the death squads. The organization is so powerful that its leaders include government
ministers, and they are happy to boast about everything from corruption and election rigging to
acts of genocide. <strong>The Act Of Killing</strong> is about killers who have won, and the sort of society
they have built. Unlike ageing Nazis or Rwandan génocidaires, Anwar and his friends have not been
forced by history to admit they participated in crimes against humanity. Instead, they have
written their own triumphant history, becoming role models for millions of young paramilitaries.
<strong>The Act of Killing</strong> is a journey into the memories and imaginations of the perpetrators,
offering insight into the minds of mass killers. And <strong>The Act of Killing</strong> is a nightmarish
vision of a frighteningly banal culture of impunity in which killers can joke about crimes
against humanity on television chat shows, and celebrate moral disaster with the ease and grace
of a soft shoe dance number.</p></blockquote>

<p>You want to challenge people&rsquo;s perceptions of good and evil through a &ldquo;bad guys win&rdquo; scenario?
That&rsquo;s how you fucking do it. Jesus, Mark Millar is such a hack.</p>
]]></content>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
