<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lol | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/lol/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-23T12:39:56-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well, There Goes *That* Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/well-there-goes-that-plan/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-03T13:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/well-there-goes-that-plan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Found in the <a href="http://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/appstore/dev/stdeula/">iTunes End User License Agreement</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>You also agree that you will not use these products for any purposes prohibited by United States
law, including, without limitation, the development, design, manufacture or production of
nuclear, missiles, or chemical or biological weapons.</p></blockquote>

<p>Total spoilsports. How am I supposed to work on my mad-science supervillainess world domination
plans without my Genius mix?</p>

<p>(<a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/2013/06/28/itunes-license-agreement-stipulates-you-cant-make-nuclear-weapons/">via</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Idea Will Not Work (The Following Philosophical Objections May Also Apply)]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/your-idea-will-not-work-the-following-philosophical-objections-may-also-apply/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T11:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/your-idea-will-not-work-the-following-philosophical-objections-may-also-apply</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was reminded of the classic template criticizing <a href="http://craphound.com/spamsolutions.txt">attempts to curb spam</a>,
a quiet little text file on Cory Doctorow&rsquo;s site, by my attempts to find the
<a href="http://secretvolcanobase.org/~tef/distributed_social_networks.txt">version about social networks</a>. It turns out there are quite a few
snowclones of this, and since I&rsquo;m a kitty who adores remix culture, I decided to try to find a few
more.</p>

<p>There are a few, and I&rsquo;d love to be made aware of more. Things that so far will not work:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.metafilter.com/85761/How-To-Save-Media#2776753">Your Plan To Save Journalism</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forum.rpg.net/showthread.php?396569-Trusted-Computing-to-save-PC-gaming-from-pirates&amp;p=8923949#post8923949">Your Approach To Fighting Videogame Piracy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forums.riftgame.com/game-discussions/classes-telara/rogue-discussion/260412-how-fix-bards-yet-another-suggestion.html#post3193324">Your Idea For Patching Bard</a></li>
<li><a href="http://jricher.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/porn_solutions.txt">Your Plan To Restrict Access To Objectionable Content</a></li>
<li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=608030">Your Approach To &ldquo;Fixing&rdquo; Advertising</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2009/01/26/689213/-Your-Idea-To-Fix-the-Housing-Crisis-Will-Not-Work">Your Idea To Fix The Housing Crisis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=89772.msg988857#msg988857">Your Countermeasures Against Bitcoin</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.owlfolio.org/research/on-replacements-for-passwords/">Your Replacement For Passwords</a></li>
<li><a href="http://qntm.org/calendar">Your Approach To Calendar Reform</a></li>
<li><a href="http://eu.battle.net/sc2/en/forum/topic/443017082#2">Your Enhancement To Battle.Net</a></li>
<li><a href="http://justenoughcraig.blogspot.com/2010/09/heavily-borrowed-from-original-spam.html">Your Economic Solution</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.snijders-it.nl/2010/10/location-separation-protocol-checklist.htlm">Your Method For Reducing The Size Of The Internet&rsquo;s Routing Table</a></li>
<li><a href="http://forums.theregister.co.uk/forum/1/2014/02/26/nsa_snooping_tactics_will_be_copied_by_criminals_in_35_years/#c_2119375">Your Tactic For Privacy On The Internet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.teamliquid.net/forum/user-streams/124660-stream-destiny?page=149#2965">Your Attempt To Justify Racist Comments</a></li>
<li><a href="http://carlos.bueno.org/2007/09/persai-your-company-advocates-x-pseudo.html">Your Startup Based On Scraped Content</a> (winceworthy)</li>
<li><a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Free_feminist_consulting_form_letter">Your Halfassed Attempt To Buy Feminist Cred</a></li>
<li><a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/More_women_in_CS_form_letter">Your Attempt To Spread Fatuous Justifications For Misogyny In Startup Culture</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.giantitp.com/forums/showthread.php?99887-Never-noticed-this-rule-before&amp;p=5496355&amp;viewfull=1#post5496355">Your Method For Fixing Editing And Rules Problems In Tabletop RPGs</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I love how, at best, the form is a way to make critical thinking cheaper. Of course it may also
fail to do that&mdash;but on a good day, it&rsquo;s a way to repudiate bad ideas by contextualizing them, by
adding relevant information instead of by shouting. Snowcloning it into different contexts is also
at a sweet-spot difficulty level: easy enough to be tempting, but hard enough to be a bit of
serious work worth respecting. It&rsquo;s a great way to summarize &ldquo;here is the bar to entry for new
techniques, this problem is in fact hard.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Another amusing thing is how often the &ldquo;Asshats&rdquo; and &ldquo;No-one will be able to find the guy or
collect the money&rdquo; objections appear verbatim. Some things cross many, many fields of human
endeavour.</p>

<p>For bonus points, here&rsquo;s someone making an interesting argument that the original form was wrong,
<a href="http://blog.jwhitham.org/2013/05/users-of-email-will-not-put-up-with-it.html">&ldquo;Users Of Email Will Not Stand For It&rdquo;</a>, and a MetaFilter user who claims to have come
up with <a href="http://ask.metafilter.com/122211/technical-legislative-marketbased-vigilante#1751153">the original</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shit One Cannot Make Up, Chapter 25233]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shit-one-cannot-make-up-chapter-25233/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T08:07:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shit-one-cannot-make-up-chapter-25233</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Small-batch, artisanal high-fructose corn syrup!</p>

<blockquote><p>Maya Weinstein has created a DIY kit for making your own HFCS (high-fructose corn syrup). You may
have already guessed that it&rsquo;s an art project and that the artist lives in Brooklyn.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[She's Been Working On The Railroad]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T12:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now I am the kind of person who read <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> once in high school and came away with an
uneasy feeling rather than a burning conviction: it felt somehow petty to me. This is probably
because I was reading Asimov&rsquo;s <em>Foundation</em> novels at the same time, and the contrast between Hari
Seldon and John Galt was dramatic and deeply unflattering to Galt. Faced with a cruel and
overbearing government, a lone genius opts to found a colony of the like-minded in a secluded
place. However, their tactics are strikingly different: Galt opts to affirmatively destroy the
system, heedless of consequences, while Hari Seldon is all about mindfulness of the consequences. I
think that&rsquo;s one of the things that really gets to me about the center of the Randian movement:
despite pretensions of intellectualism, they are blinded both to where they came from and where
they are going. That is not a good recipe for a movement.</p>

<p>Those are broad strokes, though: there is a specific thing I&rsquo;d forgotten, that Adam Lee ably points
out:</p>

<blockquote><p>Of all the businesses Rand could have chosen for her heroes, I always thought that railroads were
a bad choice to show the superiority of laissez-faire capitalism. After all, railroads, like
other forms of infrastructure, almost always take major government support and investment to
build. [&hellip;] In reality, the first American transcontinental railroad required major government
financial support&mdash;to the tune of $16,000 per mile, rising to $48,000 per mile over the Rocky
Mountains&mdash;plus extensive land grants. Modern engineering projects of similar scope, like the
Keystone XL pipeline, have been embroiled in court fights with dozens of private landowners who
don’t want to sell, and Keystone’s builders have been extremely aggressive about invoking eminent
domain.</p></blockquote>

<p>The story proceeds from merely unrealistic, as Lee notes here, to gleefully barbaric. It is part of
a pattern where every time I think &ldquo;well, I should maybe give <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> another chance, as
literature if not as dogma,&rdquo; some excerpt or another comes along and convinces me that Rand was
definitely the predecessor to L. Ron Hubbard: promulgating a con-job religion on the backs of some
awful sci-fi novels. Ugh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Friedman Is A Giant Fucking Cretin]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/thomas-friedman-is-a-giant-fucking-cretin/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T06:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/thomas-friedman-is-a-giant-fucking-cretin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thomas Friedman is the perfect example of a modern courtier: you will never find his lips too far
from the cock of established power. He is always eager to tell you why his support for the existing
order of authorities and hierarchy is bold and courageous, eager to congratulate himself for his
daring and revolutionary thoughts that are in fact the most tedious kind of Beltway ass-kissing,
and eager to demonstrate that he is a creative genius by demonstrating a talent for cheap analogies
and overwrought metaphor to rival literary pimple Dan Brown.</p>

<p>Fortunately
<a href="http://brianmayer.com/2012/12/thomas-friedman-op-ed-generator/">Brian Mayer did a little mad-libbing</a>
and created the Thomas Friedman Op-Ed Generator. This is a bit of a relief, although I&rsquo;m still
tempted to cadge some Lexis-Nexis time from a friend, download Friedman&rsquo;s corpus, and apply some
proper Markov-chain fun. The thing is that the ease of creating artificial Friedman demonstrates
how shallow and meaningless the authentic Friedman is: rather tragic, really. But not enough so to
excuse that he&rsquo;s a buffoon who apologizes for monsters. My
<a href="http://www.tinyrevolution.com/mt/archives/001830.html">favorite cheap shot at Friedman</a> is Jon
Schwarz&rsquo;s: &ldquo;he suffers from the affliction [of] a large, furry parasite that has attached itself to
his upper lip and sucked his brain out through his nose,&rdquo; although
<a href="http://whoisioz.blogspot.com/search/label/Friedman">Monsieur IOZ</a> calls him &ldquo;the Milton of
infelicity&rdquo; and &ldquo;a guy who&rsquo;d go out to the desert to eat peyote and have a vision of the inside of
Best Buy,&rdquo; both of which are also corkers.</p>

<p>My problems with Friedman are a microcosm of my problems with the mainstream US media: they are
good at explaining the major arguments going on within the American aristocracy, and that&rsquo;s about
it. They are certainly not anything like defenders of truth, critics of power, or any other piece
of their inflated self-image: they are corporations that exist to make money, and their business
model is selling readers/viewers/listeners to advertisers. As Schwarz puts it,
&ldquo;<a href="http://www.tinyrevolution.com/mt/archives/000651.html">there is no Santa Claus</a>.&rdquo; Their
self-interest is only tangentially related to having a healthy community, and much more strongly
coupled to pleasing existing power structures. This is part of why I am not particularly sad over
the idea that the Internet is going to kill newspapers: newspapers produce as little journalism as
they can get away with, and in their role as propaganda outlets almost negate that which they do
produce. TV and radio &ldquo;news&rdquo; are even worse.</p>

<p>The bright side is that microbroadcasts like this blog are available to more and more
people&mdash;unfortunately, that&rsquo;s not evenly distributed and has its own problems. I&rsquo;ll still take it
over centralized and tamed news organizations any day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
