<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: frivolity | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/frivolity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-25T10:47:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Before Time Travel Was Easy-Peasy]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/before-time-travel-was-easy-peasy/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-12T14:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/before-time-travel-was-easy-peasy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to have this here because apparently the lyrics-crap sites (and boy <em>there&rsquo;s</em> a genre of
website that makes you glad you got ad blocking and NoScript) haven&rsquo;t picked up on Deltron Event II
yet. As long as I&rsquo;m listening to this song a bunch I may as well transcribe it and have a reference
for the lyrics.</p>

<blockquote><p><em>Old-Timer 1:</em> Oh the city! Chillin' on the stoop in the future.</p>

<p><em>Old-Timer 2:</em> You said it, space friend!</p>

<p><em>Old-Timer 1</em>: Boy, I tell you things these days move too fast! Makes me wanna crack wise about how
it was back in the day. Yo, homeless robot! Drop a stupid-ass beatbox.</p>

<p><em>Homeless Robot:</em> Shit is not going well for homeless robot 235</p>

<p>{old-timer 1 raps}</p>

<p>Before a best seller meant your record went interstellar <br>
Before the impeccable smeller <br>
Before they banned Old Yeller <br>
In the wake of the Presidential dogfucking scandal <br></p>

<p>When astronauts rocked sports sandals and didn&rsquo;t have expandable mandibles <br>
And granules of Jack Daniels didn&rsquo;t heal the wounds of animals <br>
When botanicals still weren&rsquo;t a biological weapon <br>
In the war with the tarantulas <br></p>

<p>Back in the day before time travel was easy-peasy <br>
But now I go back, re-rap to make it sound repeaty <br>
Back in the day before time travel was easy-peasy <br>
Back in the day before time travel was easy-peasy <br>
Now we change history like the feat is measly <br></p>

<p>Stars these days don&rsquo;t know how good they have it <br>
We used to have plutonium in our jet pack and <br>
We had to take the supertube before it had hyperdrive <br>
Makes me wanna holler! Unh! But we&rsquo;re still alive! <br></p>

<p>{miscellaneous robot-abusing chatter}</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s an interesting bit of world-building, especially since it encourages us to mistrust the
narrators a bit - &ldquo;back in <em>my</em> day&rdquo; is already a tall-tale genre, and what might people who think
it&rsquo;s acceptable to abuse synthpersons be ignoring about the past?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Shadow Of Homestuck]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-long-shadow-of-homestuck/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T13:49:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-long-shadow-of-homestuck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wonder sometimes if there was a graffiti artist who wrote <code>MSPA</code>. I wonder how many times he tagged that before Hussie&rsquo;s juggernaut came into being. I wonder how quickly it overwhelmed whatever SEO-fu he had. It&rsquo;s not just prose but Google Images results too. If you wanted to find MSPA the graffitti artist, you would have to know already where to look. I wonder if he changed his name or tag. I wonder if Miss Pennsylvania has similar problems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
