<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ayn rand | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/ayn-rand/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-23T12:31:48-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[She's Been Working On The Railroad]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T12:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now I am the kind of person who read <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> once in high school and came away with an
uneasy feeling rather than a burning conviction: it felt somehow petty to me. This is probably
because I was reading Asimov&rsquo;s <em>Foundation</em> novels at the same time, and the contrast between Hari
Seldon and John Galt was dramatic and deeply unflattering to Galt. Faced with a cruel and
overbearing government, a lone genius opts to found a colony of the like-minded in a secluded
place. However, their tactics are strikingly different: Galt opts to affirmatively destroy the
system, heedless of consequences, while Hari Seldon is all about mindfulness of the consequences. I
think that&rsquo;s one of the things that really gets to me about the center of the Randian movement:
despite pretensions of intellectualism, they are blinded both to where they came from and where
they are going. That is not a good recipe for a movement.</p>

<p>Those are broad strokes, though: there is a specific thing I&rsquo;d forgotten, that Adam Lee ably points
out:</p>

<blockquote><p>Of all the businesses Rand could have chosen for her heroes, I always thought that railroads were
a bad choice to show the superiority of laissez-faire capitalism. After all, railroads, like
other forms of infrastructure, almost always take major government support and investment to
build. [&hellip;] In reality, the first American transcontinental railroad required major government
financial support&mdash;to the tune of $16,000 per mile, rising to $48,000 per mile over the Rocky
Mountains&mdash;plus extensive land grants. Modern engineering projects of similar scope, like the
Keystone XL pipeline, have been embroiled in court fights with dozens of private landowners who
don’t want to sell, and Keystone’s builders have been extremely aggressive about invoking eminent
domain.</p></blockquote>

<p>The story proceeds from merely unrealistic, as Lee notes here, to gleefully barbaric. It is part of
a pattern where every time I think &ldquo;well, I should maybe give <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> another chance, as
literature if not as dogma,&rdquo; some excerpt or another comes along and convinces me that Rand was
definitely the predecessor to L. Ron Hubbard: promulgating a con-job religion on the backs of some
awful sci-fi novels. Ugh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
