<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cinema | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/cinema/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-19T18:43:09-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Face Of The Clock]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-face-of-the-clock/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T08:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-face-of-the-clock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>There were darker resonances, too. People went to the movies to lose track of time; this video
would pound viewers with an awareness of how long they’d been languishing in the dark. It would
evoke the laziest of modern pleasures—channel surfing—except that the time wasted would be
painfully underlined.</p>

<p>He would not be creating the first film with a running time of precisely one day. That
distinction went to <strong>24 Hour Psycho</strong>, a 1993 work, by Douglas Gordon, that stretched
Hitchcock’s taut thriller into excruciatingly portentous art. And Andy Warhol, in his 1964 film
“Empire”—eight hours of stationary footage of the Empire State Building fading into darkness—had
created a work whose point was to make viewers &ldquo;see time go by.&rdquo; There was a lineage of
avant-garde cinema that, with varying degrees of obscurity, examined the temporal qualities of
film. Marclay’s contribution to the cinema of duration, though, would be pleasurable to watch. He
sensed a creepy challenge. If his film was sufficiently seductive, he might coax people to sit
for hours, literally watching their lives tick away.</p></blockquote>

<p>Christian Marclay&rsquo;s <em>The Clock</em> is also something I&rsquo;d quite like to see. It sometimes feels strange
to me, wanting to see movies even though I probably won&rsquo;t see them. <em>The Clock</em> draws me
particularly because it&rsquo;s about the artifice of cinema, the way it gets into Picasso-style
lies-that-tell-truths&mdash;a subject that&rsquo;s grown on me over the years. Maybe I am okay with movies
and I just dislike theatres? At any rate it might be time to reconsider my stance that video is
just not a good match for me. I am not particularly sad to be wrong: people exceeding expectations
is a cause for celebration.</p>

<p>As a side note, the New Yorker seems to be a big fan of <em>The Clock</em>: there&rsquo;s also
&ldquo;<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/03/night-shift-with-the-clock.html">Night shift with The Clock</a>&rdquo; and &ldquo;<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/07/is-the-clock-worth-the-time.html">Is The Clock worth the time?</a>&rdquo; which
are both decent (and much shorter) reads, as well as
<a href="http://kottke.org/13/06/about-an-hour-of-christian-marclays-the-clock">Kottke&rsquo;s roundup of bootlegged clips</a> from the movie, which for obvious reasons is shown
as an installation and not available for purchase.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
