<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mpegs | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/mpegs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-25T10:47:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sprinkle Some PFAF On Your Morning]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/sprinkle-some-pfaf-on-your-morning/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T07:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/sprinkle-some-pfaf-on-your-morning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The aim was to explore the relationship between geometry and audio in unique ways.&rdquo; A delightful
compilation of micro-length animations, little glimpses of fantastic. Nice little brain-tickler.</p>

<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PP1TAQUsdt4?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Last Big Secret]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-last-big-secret/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-29T13:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-last-big-secret</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Shadow of the Colossus</em> is one of the great achievements of videogames. I tend towards comparing
it to <em>Super Metroid,</em> although one could go other directions. Both games cultivate an atmosphere
of solitude and the uncanny, focusing on a solo protagonist in an alien place. They&rsquo;re not only
masterfully executed, great fun as games, but also are achievers of a high ambition in games: they
expand the player&rsquo;s sense of the possible. The team who built <em>Ico</em> expanded and refined their
ideas, and as a result, <em>Shadow</em> was a truly great game, expanding a mass audience&rsquo;s sense of what
the medium of videogames was capable of.</p>

<p>All of this is on my mind because I recently encountered a Eurogamer article,
<a href="http://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2013-05-02-the-quest-for-shadow-of-the-colossuss-last-big-secret">&ldquo;The Quest for Shadow of the Colossus' Last Big Secret,&rdquo;</a> pointing out that a game
pushing ten years old is still drawing a small crowd of searchers determined to find everything
that can be found in the game. I&rsquo;m pleasantly reminded of how the executive-meddling-crippled
<em>KOTOR II</em> was the beneficiary of a fan effort to restore cut content and fix outstanding bugs. The
story of the searchers here is a compelling one, and I recommend it to you along with other
<a href="http://www.glitterberri.com/shadow-of-the-colossus/">fan-made</a> <a href="http://lparchive.org/Shadow-of-the-Colossus/">amplifications</a> of the game.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re feeling particularly nostalgic, you may wish to watch this
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dbUsuIr28SA&amp;list=PL894C9468F2597100">playthrough of the HD version</a> of the game as you read:</p>

<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dbUsuIr28SA?list=PL894C9468F2597100?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EDIRD: Why Do Birds Suddenly Appear]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-why-do-birds-suddenly-appear/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T09:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-why-do-birds-suddenly-appear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/re-6eOhrejE?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>

<p>Speaking of cinema: <em>Mirrormask</em> was quite a thing. For one thing, giving Dave McKean millions of
dollars to make a movie results in visual deliciousness. For another thing, looking back, I see
this prefiguring a bunch of my friends' kinks. Hello clockwork robot mind-control scene with a hint
of transformation!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killing In The Name Of]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/killing-in-the-name-of/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-11T22:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/killing-in-the-name-of</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/SD5oMxbMcHM?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>

<p>Werner Herzog and Errol Morris are collaborating on a documentary! I mean, that right there and I&rsquo;m
pretty much sold (although they are both in producer roles, not directing, but those two together
is a hell of a recommendation). Even if I wasn&rsquo;t, the story of <em>The Act Of Killing</em> (and isn&rsquo;t that
one hell of a name?) is compelling:</p>

<blockquote><p>When the government of Indonesia was overthrown by the military in 1965, Anwar and his friends
were promoted from small-time gangsters who sold movie theatre tickets on the black market to
death squad leaders. They helped the army kill more than one million alleged communists, ethnic
Chinese, and intellectuals in less than a year. As the executioner for the most notorious death
squad in his city, Anwar himself killed hundreds of people with his own hands. [&hellip;] Anwar and
his friends agree to tell us the story of the killings. But their idea of being in a movie is not
to provide testimony for a documentary: they want to star in the kind of films they most love
from their days scalping tickets at the cinemas. [And so] we challenge Anwar and his friends to
develop fiction scenes about their experience of the killings, adapted to their favorite genres:
gangster, western, musical. They write the scripts. They play themselves. And they play their
victims.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is one hell of a premise, and the trailer is great. I want to see this so badly.</p>

<p>As an aside, this also provides even more of an illustration of how awful, awful, <strong><em>awful</em></strong> Mark
Millar&rsquo;s supremely shitty and soul-of-the-world-impoverishing
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wanted_%28comics%29">Wanted</a> was and how Millar should live in
shame for having created it.</p>

<blockquote><p>Today, Anwar is revered as a founding father of a right-wing paramilitary organization that grew
out of the death squads. The organization is so powerful that its leaders include government
ministers, and they are happy to boast about everything from corruption and election rigging to
acts of genocide. <strong>The Act Of Killing</strong> is about killers who have won, and the sort of society
they have built. Unlike ageing Nazis or Rwandan génocidaires, Anwar and his friends have not been
forced by history to admit they participated in crimes against humanity. Instead, they have
written their own triumphant history, becoming role models for millions of young paramilitaries.
<strong>The Act of Killing</strong> is a journey into the memories and imaginations of the perpetrators,
offering insight into the minds of mass killers. And <strong>The Act of Killing</strong> is a nightmarish
vision of a frighteningly banal culture of impunity in which killers can joke about crimes
against humanity on television chat shows, and celebrate moral disaster with the ease and grace
of a soft shoe dance number.</p></blockquote>

<p>You want to challenge people&rsquo;s perceptions of good and evil through a &ldquo;bad guys win&rdquo; scenario?
That&rsquo;s how you fucking do it. Jesus, Mark Millar is such a hack.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronica Will Eat Itself]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/electronica-will-eat-itself/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T17:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/electronica-will-eat-itself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/52766487 "></iframe></div></p>

<p>This is a nifty video of a musical robot&mdash;but it&rsquo;s also a great example of how all culture builds
on what came before, how all culture is to some extent remix culture. It&rsquo;s a robot that physically
plays a set of instruments that correspond to the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roland_TR-808">TR-808</a>, which itself was a way of synthetically
producing the sounds of that set of instruments. Always we are consuming what came before;
sometimes we are making it our own and new, and ideally we are giving it freely to a future that
needs it just as badly as we need our own past.</p>

<p>(<a href="http://mischeathen.com/?p=18420">via</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
