<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: music | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-08T07:37:40-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eventually We Had More Ex-Bassists Than Audience Members]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/eventually-we-had-more-ex-bassists-than-audience-members/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T17:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/eventually-we-had-more-ex-bassists-than-audience-members</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>What’s it like being in a band that you think is amazing and everyone else is completely
indifferent to? Well, it’s a lot like a job where you’re the laziest guy on the shift and
everyone knows it; it’s not great, but it beats working. Except you’re working really hard and it
sucks. And all your friends are getting promotions, and even if they eventually get dropped by
their promotions, they at least got a taste and what did you get? First on a bill of three on a
Tuesday night. Like your life, the analogy eventually falls apart.</p></blockquote>

<p>Failure is something we all have to cope with. Sometimes I fail at coping with failure. So I have a
distinct interest in reading interesting things about failure, and recently I found this account of
failure from the lead singer of a band that, as I read it, died a quiet death mourned by very
few. The ability to look directly at one&rsquo;s own failures and critically assess them is a very
important one, so reading someone else&rsquo;s attempt to do that is instructive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently You Can Do Whatever You Want When You Get Old]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/apparently-you-can-do-whatever-you-want-when-you-get-old/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T10:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/apparently-you-can-do-whatever-you-want-when-you-get-old</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Christopher Lee is 91&mdash;crikey, I thought he was dead for some reason!&mdash;and has apparently decided
that that&rsquo;s a great time to be making metal albums. About Charlemagne!</p>

<blockquote><p>The first &lsquo;Charlemagne&rsquo; album is metal, of course, but what I sang was more symphonic. Now on
the second one, &lsquo;The Omens Of Death&rsquo;, it is one hundred percent heavy metal. I&rsquo;ve done my bits
and pieces, and they are heavy metal. I&rsquo;m not screaming or anything like that, but it is
definitely heavy metal.</p></blockquote>

<p>Mad respect. I want to hear this now. And to see in person
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CIVOVB8/?tag=usefultigress05-20">the gloriously cheesy Photoshop work of the cover</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind The Courtroom In Long Beach]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/behind-the-courtroom-in-long-beach/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-29T15:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/behind-the-courtroom-in-long-beach</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today in chance encounters:</p>

<blockquote><p>And what about the calmly lascivious hayseed who provides the voice-over on the untitled funk
fragment that goes in its entirety: &ldquo;Maureen&rsquo;s got five sisters. They all got ass. One of &lsquo;em has
eyes as big as Jolly Ranchers. Beautiful girl, she&rsquo;s a beautiful girl.&rdquo; What the hell is
<strong>that,</strong> you wonder. What does &ldquo;eyes as big as Jolly Ranchers&rdquo; even mean? For that matter, what
does the whole track mean? Why is it here? Yet the guy and his trope are both so paradigmatic, so
weirdly normal, that after three or four plays you find yourself greeting it as warmly as the
hook of &ldquo;It Takes Two.&rdquo;</p>

<p>But since one of the things that makes <strong>Endtroducing</strong> an art-rock record is its attention to
placement, there&rsquo;s no knowing whether the same bit would be as beguiling somewhere else. Its
organic absurdism follows a selection from Shadow&rsquo;s famous &ldquo;What Does Your Soul Look Like?&rdquo; and
right afterwards comes the lyrical first theme of the very multipartite &ldquo;Stem / Long Stem,&rdquo;
picked reflectively on a guitar or a keyb in drag. Heightened by the contrast, the theme&rsquo;s
yearning for the good and the beautiful is then accented with a triangle &mdash; only to be bombarded
a minute later by a drum-machine chain explosion, interrupted by a sub-Lenny Bruce monologue
about getting locked up in Long Beach (I now smack my lips over the strange phrase &ldquo;while I&rsquo;m
awaiting to be heard on my traffic offenses&rdquo;), then developed yet again. At 7:44, a nine-second
pause precedes a piano coda that you keep waiting to evolve into the theme track and never
does. And I&rsquo;m leaving stuff out. And that&rsquo;s just one track.</p>

<p>What I&rsquo;m describing is a highly potent species of musical structure […] Shadow didn&rsquo;t compose
these melodies, and [to] call them &ldquo;found&rdquo; would be too easy&mdash;&ldquo;discovered,&rdquo; maybe, although it&rsquo;s
more accurate to say they&rsquo;ve been accessed and reimagined. Because they&rsquo;re so anonymous, they
carry none of the wink-nudge intertextual referentiality of quoted bricolage, and though they&rsquo;re
nothing special to start with most of the time, they now give off the kind of direct aesthetic
emotion that&rsquo;s so hard to come by in this hyperconscious cultural era&mdash;an emotion you&rsquo;d hardly
expect to arise in such a formally pomo context. It&rsquo;s plain enough that Shadow loves the
disconcerting beats and impolite sounds of hip-hop and is no stranger to other ways of coping
with musical alienation. But it&rsquo;s just as plain that in his encyclopedic store of obscurities he
recognized dreams and aspirations from another cultural place, dreams that want nothing to do
with alienation except to vanquish it. I have no idea whether his ability to realize these dreams
is a promise of cultural health or a mark of individual genius.</p>

<p>&ndash; Robert Christgau, <strong>Grown Up All Wrong: 75 Great Rock and Pop Artists from Vaudeville to Techno</strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
