<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: postfurry | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/postfurry/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-23T12:39:56-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Evenly Not Just It's]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/distributed-evenly-not-just-its/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-05T08:06:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/distributed-evenly-not-just-its</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>These are the people who invented &ldquo;la vie de Boheme.&rdquo;
They invented the lifestyle of the urban middle-class
dropout art-gypsy.  They invented its terminology and its
tactics.  They brought us the &ldquo;succes de scandale,&rdquo; the
now time-honored tactic of shocking one&rsquo;s audience all the
way to the bank.  And the &ldquo;succes d'estime,&rdquo; the edgy and
hazardous life of the critics' darling.  The doctrine of
art for art&rsquo;s sake was theirs too (thank you, Theophile
Gautier).  And the ever-helpful notion of <em>epater les
bourgeoisie,</em> an act of consummately modern rebellion
which is nevertheless impossible without a <em>bourgeoisie</em> to
<em>epater,</em> an act which the bourgeoisie itself has lavishly
financed for decades in our culture&rsquo;s premiere example of
Aldissian enantiodromia &ndash; the transformation of things
into their opposites. The Paris Bohemians were the first genuine
industrial-scale counterculture.  This was the culture
that created Jules Verne.  It deserves a great deal of the
credit or blame for origination of the genres of horror,
fantasy, and science fiction.  It has a legitimate claim
on our attention and our loyalties.</p></blockquote>

<p>One of the experiences that <a href="http://en.wikifur.com/wiki/Postfurry">PR and PV</a> have had that I&rsquo;m a bit jealous of, is that of encountering Bruce Sterling for the first time in the mid-90s. It&rsquo;s debatable whether that&rsquo;s what you&rsquo;d call &ldquo;the height of his powers,&rdquo; but the man has a powerful and bone-deep vision of possible futures that he is compelled to share (he also nicely illustrates that a solid knowledge of history is indispensable if you want to write science fiction). Encountering him in the 90s and seeing what he has to say about the Internet and counterculture, I can see why one might feel compelled to tell others, to share the vision. PR and PV have said in about so many words, that part of why postfurry is a thing, is Bruce Sterling. The vision persists.</p>

<p>It opens questions that make me shiver. I talked to someone recently and found out that I am not sure that postfurry has enough heft to sustain being written about, analyzed, explained. On the other hand, I have a deep and persistent feeling that there is something interesting and worthwhile there.</p>

<p>One of the habits of the furry subculture that troubles me is the fear of excluding people. It makes me squint suspiciously. You <a href="http://thearchdruidreport.blogspot.com/2010/01/this-presupposition-of-passivity.html">can&rsquo;t have a community unless you have a rule</a> for who&rsquo;s in and who&rsquo;s out. It needn&rsquo;t be phrased too harshly - but such a rule must exist. In a geographic community, the rule is easy: if you&rsquo;re here, you&rsquo;re in, if you&rsquo;re not, you&rsquo;re out. But furry in general, because of its attachment to the Internet, and postfurry in particular, aims to be post-geographic. Thus, <em>some</em> rule is necessary - and if one is not consciously developed, one will de facto emerge from the community&rsquo;s id. I am not a fan of that prospect.</p>

<p>There are things to love about the furry subculture, and I love the postfurry community &mdash; but the future shape of a community is determined by the work invested in the present, and I&rsquo;m worried about that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
