<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-25T10:23:08-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Ultimatums]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/on-ultimatums/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-05T20:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/on-ultimatums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don&rsquo;t issue ultimatums. Why not? Because you&rsquo;ll see yourself like this:</p>

<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/s8YO5icNGn0?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>

<p>And they&rsquo;ll see you like this:</p>

<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_SbgEYBG-Y8?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>

<p>Ultimatums are almost never the right tool. Use them as infrequently as possible, or a little less.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conspiracy Is Void]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-conspiracy-is-void/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T18:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-conspiracy-is-void</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While there are many things I like about Tumblr, I have a bottomless appetite for cheap shots at it
(e.g. <a href="http://mightygodking.com/2013/06/04/this-act-of-creative-and-historical-vandalism-is-not-technically-my-fault/">Folsom Prison Feels</a>) and a few serious beefs. The one that I&rsquo;m here to talk about
today is not about Tumblr as a company or platform but Tumblr as a culture, and particularly about
the crop of young social-justice advocates coming up through it. Of course I make allowance here
for the way that any generation of activists will spend a fair bit of time carping about the next:
good lord, just thinking of what particularly vocal second-wave feminists have to say about my
cohort makes the roots of my hair tingle.</p>

<p>I want to talk about this problem, though, partially because it&rsquo;s a failure of thought-rigor that
we&rsquo;re all prone to. I just see it more often in the Tumblr crowd&mdash;I have ideas about why that is,
but certainly they&rsquo;re not the only people capable of this fallacy. The fallacy goes like this:
given that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kyriarchy">The Patriarchy and other toxic power systems</a> exist, as unavoidably
widespread and oppressive forces, and given that they are a member of a class that those systems do
harm to, too many people behave as though the partiarchy (or power system <em>du jour</em>) is a
conspiracy that is out to get them particularly.</p>

<p>This is fallacious in both its halves: part of why the toxic power systems are so hard to deal with
is that they are <em>not</em> conspiracies, and that they are <em>not</em> after you in particular: it is
enough that you are there and you are a member of some disfavored class. Ignoring your
individuality is a feature of the system.</p>

<p>I am of course indebted to <a href="http://zingerella.livejournal.com/73987.html?format=light">an older exploration of the matter</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, there is no one Patriarch, leastaways not outside of Constantinople. There&rsquo;s no single dude
in a nifty hat at the top of the power structure, surrounded by scantily clad women whom he
feeds to tigers for his kicks and giggles. If it were only that simple, we could off the old
wanker, free the women and give them some trousers, find loving homes for the tigers, and have a
great party around the bonfire of his palace (after salvaging all the good art, books, and
chocolate). Alas, because the patriarchy is instead a very very old system that has warped
everyone&rsquo;s thinking right down to the sub-rational, axiomatic, non-verbal ideological level, it&rsquo;s
much more difficult to overthrow. (We&rsquo;ve seen how well wars against ideas work.)</p>

<p>[&hellip;] The Gentleman complained that calling the androcentric system of how things are, or male
privilege &ldquo;the patriarchy&rdquo; personifies it, and makes it seem like a conspiracy theory in which
all men are agents of this big conspiracy to keep women down. He said that saying that &ldquo;the
system serves to perpetuate itself,&rdquo; further personifies something that is, after all, merely a
structure put in place by people, and something that not all men support.</p>

<p>The patriarchy is not a system in the way that the Library of Congress system of cataloguing is a
system. It&rsquo;s not spelled out anywhere, no single person or group of people sat down and dreamed
it up, and people don&rsquo;t usually debate its merits over those of any other system that does the
same thing. I don&rsquo;t think even Men&rsquo;s Rights Activists get up in the morning and think &ldquo;Dude! I&rsquo;m
so glad I live in a patriarchy! I&rsquo;m gonna go subjugate me some women today!&rdquo; Instead we <strong>all</strong>
live in a system that exists on patriarchal premises.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about conspiracies. Conspiracy theories are a mode of thought that we&rsquo;re all prone to,
in varying degrees. This is because as humans, we are pattern-finders. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophenia">Apophenia</a>
is our life. Further, we&rsquo;re all self-centered&mdash;necessarily, for <em>your</em> life should be about
<em>you</em>, it can&rsquo;t healthily be about someone else. This has the side effect, though, that we&rsquo;re
prone to believing that events in the world around us are also about us. Very little that is
happening around you in your life is about you, though.</p>

<p>Conspiracy theories, then, are a natural outgrowth of this: they propose that something important
is being hidden by malicious actors working in concert. The combination of pattern-finding,
self-centeredness, and the simple fact that not all events in the world are comprehensible and few
are controllable, can lead any of us to explanations for those events that range into the
conspiratorial. A recent incident illustrated the tendency in what I find a grimly humorous way:
the 2010 paper <em>&ldquo;NASA faked the moon landing–therefore (climate) science is a hoax: an anatomy of
the motivated rejection of science&rdquo;</em> tentatively identified that people who think climate science
is a giant hoax or a conspiracy, also tend to have other conspiratorial-type
beliefs. Unsurprisingly, the rejecters of climate-change science had many criticisms of the
paper&mdash;which led to the same authors' 2013 paper <em>&ldquo;Recursive fury: conspiracist ideation in the
blogosphere in response to research on conspiracist ideation,&rdquo;</em> whose subtitle basically sums it up
(cheap shot interlude: &ldquo;Recursive Fury&rdquo; is my punk-covers-of-Douglas-Hofstatder band).</p>

<p>A <a href="http://academia.edu/1207098/Dead_and_alive_Beliefs_in_contradictory_conspiracy_theories">2012 paper from the University of Kent</a> uses a different way of illustrating the
point:</p>

<blockquote><p>Conspiracy theories can form a monological belief system: A self-sustaining worldview comprised
of a network of mutually supportive beliefs. The present research shows that even mutually
incompatible conspiracy theories are positively correlated in endorsement. In Study 1, the more
participants believed that Princess Diana faked her own death, the more they believed that she
was murdered. In Study 2, the more participants believed that Osama Bin Laden was already dead
when U.S. special forces raided his compound in Pakistan, the more they believed he is still
alive. Hierarchical regression models showed that mutually incompatible conspiracy theories are
positively associated because both are associated with the view that the authorities are engaged
in a cover-up. The monological nature of conspiracy belief appears to be driven not by conspiracy
theories directly supporting one another but by broader beliefs supporting conspiracy theories in
general.</p></blockquote>

<p><em>Recursive Fury</em>, meanwhile, uses a six-point set of criteria for conspiratorial thinking:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Nefarious Intent:</strong> Assuming that the presumed conspirators have nefarious intentions. For
example, if person X assumes that blogger Y colluded with the New York Times to publish a paper
damaging to X, then X presumes nefarious intent on the part of Y.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Persecuted Victim:</strong> Self-identifying as the victim of an organised persecution.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Nihilistic Skepticism:</strong> Refusing to believe anything that doesn&rsquo;t fit into the conspiracy
theory. Note that &ldquo;conspiracy theory&rdquo; here is a fairly broad term and need not involve a global
conspiracy (e.g., that NASA faked the moon landing) but can refer to small-scale events and
hypotheses.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Nothing Occurs By Accident:</strong> Weaving any small random event into the conspiracy narrative.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Something Must Be Wrong:</strong> Switching liberally between different, even contradictory
conspiracy theories that have in common only the presumption that there is something wrong in
the official account by the alleged conspirators. Thus, people may simultaneously believe that
Princess Diana faked her own death and that she was assassinated by MI5.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Self-Sealing Reasoning:</strong> Interpreting any evidence against the conspiracy as evidence for the
conspiracy. For example, when climate scientists are exonerated of any wrong-doing 9 times over
by different investigations, this is reinterpreted to imply that the climate-change conspiracy
involves not just the world’s climate scientists but also the investigating bodies and
associated governments.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I think it&rsquo;s crucially important here to avoid saying &ldquo;oh man those conspiracy buffs, they&rsquo;ll
believe anything.&rdquo; Conspiracy theories are a pattern of thought that we are <em>all</em> vulnerable to. In
varying degrees, true, but all of us are vulnerable, and a feeling of certainty is no defense. This
is part of why we feminists, we activists, we strivers for a better world, need to especially
beware of conspiracy-theory thinking. <strong>The patriarchy is not a conspiracy.</strong></p>

<p>We encounter the patriarchy and related toxic power systems most often in a context where they are
likely to do us personal harm: of course we take it personally! But you will go grievously wrong
assuming that the system (as opposed to individual actors) dislikes you personally. You are a
wonderful person but conspiracies, as Mr. Assange tirelessly reminds us, are needy beasts and you
are not worth the effort of keeping a conspiracy running. Instead, the patriarchy is a system of
interlocking systems, which long ago passed the point where the beneficiaries and those hoping for
their table-scraps needed only act in furtherance of their self-interest, without conspiring with
anyone else, for the system to be perpetuated. When we are harmed, when we are in pain, it is
difficult to believe that it is not about us, but it really isn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Another face of this system is the United States' mainstream media&mdash;or to call it more accurately,
the propaganda system by which Official Facts are distributed (I am drawing heavily from Chomsky
here). This system is harmful to many of us, and has the effect of maintaining elite power at the
expense of the common good. It too is not a conspiracy and it does not care about you, the
news-consumer, personally. It is just the same: the system is rigged such that actors pursue their
own self-interest independently and perpetuate the system in that way. That is precisely why the
propaganda system, and the patriarchal power structures in general, are so difficult to push back
against: they are in a sense decentralized.</p>

<p>No matter how much power he may personally wield, it is vanishingly rare that a beneficiary thinks
of himself as blessed with the power of a system backing him. Indeed he generally has had to expend
considerable effort disposing of rivals for that benefit, and takes this effort for evidence of
merit. He who reaches the VP suite or the Senate or the upper echelons of an important bureaucracy,
has had to do a great deal of work and apply a great deal of ingenuity. What he generally resists
seeing, is that someone who did as much work and applied as much ingenuity, but who did not have
the benefit of a system of power behind them, would not be rewarded in the same way (they may in
fact be punished: there&rsquo;s a strong argument that lynchings were
<a href="http://bradhicks.livejournal.com/378012.html?format=light">more an economic crime than a hate crime</a>).</p>

<p>Of course there are still further complications. The baneful power systems that we&rsquo;re trying to
disrupt operate as interlocking systems and at the most abstract level, they are systems of
interactions between classes of person (not just class in the economic sense, but in just about any
way you can divide people into Us and Them). But the operation of these large systems is to spawn
smaller systems, which may repeat the process, until actual work and reification-of-hierarchy gets
done at the margins. I am not a class of person unto myself, nor is a police officer, but together
we operate the system whereby the state asserts a monopoly on
<a href="http://crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/violence.php">the use and definition of violence</a>.</p>

<p>The reason that it&rsquo;s important to note this fractal nature of systems is that if you follow it down
far enough, you will find conspiracies. Small, petty, cruel conspiracies that ruin lives, bodies,
and minds, they are nasty operations&mdash;but they are not the system that they are embedded in,
rather they are a product of it. However, they are rarer than you might think, because the secrecy
criteria is important. Remember that we&rsquo;re not counting the Family Research Council as a
conspiracy: they are actors colluding to do harm to queers, women, and pretty much everyone, but
they&rsquo;re not doing so in secret: they are quite clear about their goals, membership, tactics,
etc. They issue press releases. There are plenty of subsystems like them, including some that do
target individuals, but we need to resist letting those lure us into conspiratorial thinking.</p>

<p>The six-point scale from <em>Recursive Fury</em> can be useful for pushing against this tendency: it&rsquo;s not
a panacea, but it is a useful reminder that we&rsquo;re talking about big sloppy human systems, not
against powerful, malicious schemers. Thinking in terms of systems is an important part of the
activist toolkit, because individual actions don&rsquo;t happen in a vacuum. They have antecedents and
causes. Even on the interpersonal level, a person is not any of their actions: they are at the very
least actions and discourses over time, which is very different. For groups, likewise. Conspiracies
are rare enough that you should assume that events in the world around you are <em>not</em> the result of
a conspiracy, even if they cause you pain and are difficult to understand. Perhaps especially then.</p>

<p>Now, I know a bunch of people who spend a lot of time in <a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2008/03/the_security_mi_1.html">the security mindset</a> who&rsquo;re
going to want some caveats to be attached to this. So: there certainly are situations where you&rsquo;ll
want to worry about conspiracies, and some of those conspiracies will have an agenda that amounts
to &ldquo;kill you if you get too inconvenient to entrenched power systems.&rdquo; The best example is how
police departments and the FBI routinely employ <em>agents provocateur</em> against anyone with a remotely
anti-hierarchical agenda (to the point of being assholes to Food Not Bombs, wielders of one of the
most innocuous activism tactics imaginable). However, these situations are both rare and
illustrative that conspiracies are expensive and difficult. The big-picture system being resisted
and disrupted, is not a conspiracy.</p>

<p>I started out by talking about Tumblr, but this is a problem that&rsquo;s specific to human cognition,
not specific to Tumblr. Tumblr just happens to be full of young folks, who are normal young folks
and thus charmingly overconfident and full of anger, not yet scarred in the specific way that
produces a certain <a href="http://woborders.wordpress.com/2012/02/13/debating-tactics-remember-to-ask-what-works/">pragmatism</a>, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murphy%27s_law">parsimony of causes</a>, and a
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor">cynical optimism about others' actions</a>. Age is no guarantee that a person will come
around to a productive approach&mdash;which is to say, eschewing dramatic first resorts, patient in
proportion to how they hope for their own (inevitable) follies to be treated with patience, and
always curious as to whether there is some item of mutual agreement that could be worked towards
rather than having yet another argument.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the real sin of conspiratorial thinking, if you ask me: by presenting tempting-but-wrong
explanations for the world, it will very effectively keep you from <em>getting things done.</em> As you
make your way through the world you cannot avoid encountering the painful, the inexplicable, and
the unjust. Working against them is difficult&mdash;and conspiratorial thinking will sabotage your
work. Perhaps we could consider inverting the checklist from <em>Recursive Fury</em>:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Selfish Intent:</strong> Assume that other people primarily care about themselves. They&rsquo;re not
stupid, they have a whole life to live, but that life is about them and not about you.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Bemused Observer:</strong> Be deeply conservative in assumptions about whether or not people are out
to get you, especially in an organized manner. People generally organize for themselves, not for
you (see 1).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Judicious Acceptance:</strong> Systems made up of humans are messy, not neat, and almost never
elegant. Dramatized stories about them almost always leave out the screw-ups, friction, and
dawdling. If a conspiracy looks excellently efficient, slick, and deft, it might not exist.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Acknowledgement Of Accidents:</strong> Plenty of things happen by accident or without
planning. Account for impulse and coincidence when you account for people&rsquo;s actions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>If There&rsquo;s No Plan, It Can&rsquo;t Be Going Wrong:</strong> Acknowledging that much of the world is not
just beyond your control, but beyond anyone&rsquo;s control, undermines the idea that a conspiracy is
bending events towards their ends. Of course the world is not quite as you would like it&mdash;but
you are just like everyone else in percieving that the world is imperfect.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Open-Ended Reasoning:</strong> Avoid at all costs becoming locked into non-falsifiable patterns of
thought: if you have a belief that can neither be proven nor disproven, you have a belief that
needs to be harshly examined. This is especially true of deciding that people you interact with
are malicious or untrustworthy: once you commit to that belief, you commit to a pattern of
actions that will make it extraordinarily hard for them to behave benevolently towards you or
extend trust to you, and your <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">confirmation bias</a> will carry the day.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Of course this is just a sketch towards the general plan of resisting conspiratorial thinking, but
it&rsquo;s a starting-place and that&rsquo;s important to have. The point of a starting-place is that you don&rsquo;t
remain there, that you make a concerted effort of getting to somewhere else. The metaphor of travel
also gives us this: look at the whole journey from time to time, not just the next step. Cultivate
a flexibility of perspective. After all, one way of looking at patriarchy is to call it the
conspiracy theory that women are all out to get you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Face Of The Clock]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-face-of-the-clock/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T08:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-face-of-the-clock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>There were darker resonances, too. People went to the movies to lose track of time; this video
would pound viewers with an awareness of how long they’d been languishing in the dark. It would
evoke the laziest of modern pleasures—channel surfing—except that the time wasted would be
painfully underlined.</p>

<p>He would not be creating the first film with a running time of precisely one day. That
distinction went to <strong>24 Hour Psycho</strong>, a 1993 work, by Douglas Gordon, that stretched
Hitchcock’s taut thriller into excruciatingly portentous art. And Andy Warhol, in his 1964 film
“Empire”—eight hours of stationary footage of the Empire State Building fading into darkness—had
created a work whose point was to make viewers &ldquo;see time go by.&rdquo; There was a lineage of
avant-garde cinema that, with varying degrees of obscurity, examined the temporal qualities of
film. Marclay’s contribution to the cinema of duration, though, would be pleasurable to watch. He
sensed a creepy challenge. If his film was sufficiently seductive, he might coax people to sit
for hours, literally watching their lives tick away.</p></blockquote>

<p>Christian Marclay&rsquo;s <em>The Clock</em> is also something I&rsquo;d quite like to see. It sometimes feels strange
to me, wanting to see movies even though I probably won&rsquo;t see them. <em>The Clock</em> draws me
particularly because it&rsquo;s about the artifice of cinema, the way it gets into Picasso-style
lies-that-tell-truths&mdash;a subject that&rsquo;s grown on me over the years. Maybe I am okay with movies
and I just dislike theatres? At any rate it might be time to reconsider my stance that video is
just not a good match for me. I am not particularly sad to be wrong: people exceeding expectations
is a cause for celebration.</p>

<p>As a side note, the New Yorker seems to be a big fan of <em>The Clock</em>: there&rsquo;s also
&ldquo;<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/03/night-shift-with-the-clock.html">Night shift with The Clock</a>&rdquo; and &ldquo;<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2012/07/is-the-clock-worth-the-time.html">Is The Clock worth the time?</a>&rdquo; which
are both decent (and much shorter) reads, as well as
<a href="http://kottke.org/13/06/about-an-hour-of-christian-marclays-the-clock">Kottke&rsquo;s roundup of bootlegged clips</a> from the movie, which for obvious reasons is shown
as an installation and not available for purchase.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today We Have Naming Of Parts]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/today-we-have-naming-of-parts/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T17:53:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/today-we-have-naming-of-parts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>To-day we have naming of parts. Yesterday, <br>
We had daily cleaning. And to-morrow morning, <br>
We shall have what to do after firing. But to-day, <br>
To-day we have naming of parts. Japonica <br>
Glistens like coral in all of the neighboring gardens, <br>
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And to-day we have naming of parts.</p></blockquote>

<p>Life goes on even during its painful parts, even during the parts where routine is made to seem
ridiculous by the way in which it fails to address tragedy, heartbreak, loss. Life goes on and so
do we: routine is for reminding us of the onward force of time, which is indifferent to us and our
pain. We go on, we are swept on, we stumble on.</p>

<blockquote><p>Henry Reed&rsquo;s much-anthologized poem of World War II, &ldquo;Naming of Parts,&rdquo; concerns a British
sergeant-instructor delivering a lecture to his green recruits on the various parts of a
rifle. The progression of these lessons is as amusing as they are impeccably English: beginning
with proper cleaning of the weapon; succeeded by the grocery-list naming of parts; to be followed
the next day by &lsquo;what to do after firing.&rsquo; Conspicuously missing is a lesson in actual firing.</p></blockquote>

<p>Henry Reed&rsquo;s poem resonates in my head comparing the routine and the ridiculous and today we have
naming of parts. Poetry is a way of giving our expression different limits like an epiphyte vine
entangled with a cherry tree. Relationships are differently percieved and we may extract value from
the juxtaposition, which in my case I have not got. Relationships are differently percieved with
time and personhood and pain and abrupt changes of topic and today we have naming of parts.</p>

<p>We also have
<a href="http://nielsenhayden.com/makinglight/archives/015099.html#1341167">a satire of the poem</a> pointing
out the foibles of Wikipedia. The words are fragile and motionless, incompletely reflecting pain
and the fullness of the human experience, never letting anyone see any of them shed a tear.</p>

<p>Today we have naming of parts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Which I Am Exceedingly Surly About Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/in-which-i-am-exceedingly-surly/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-02T15:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/in-which-i-am-exceedingly-surly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been taking a break from Twitter and reflecting on why I needed to take a break from
Twitter. The short version is that dealing with other people is a fundamentally difficult problem
and I&rsquo;m not sure that Twitter is helping. I have hopes for Twitter, but I have several very
critical things to say about it too (and when I say them, I will be doing that thing where I argue
in favor of my position and just trust that there are valid points that people could make against
my position and not volunteer to make those points for them&mdash;it&rsquo;s <em>my</em> rant, dangit).</p>

<h3>What is Twitter good at?</h3>

<p>Much of what is good about Twitter is what&rsquo;s good about email: it makes practical a wider spectrum
of expression than before. At the point where email and Twitter came along, we already had lots of
ways to express ourselves - good ones, too! The written letter, the telegram, the telephone, the
fax, the postcard, the magazine, the newspaper article, the letter to the editor. These were all
good ways to express oneself: however, they were not, collectively, good at expressing all of the
things that a person might want to express. Change over time made some of them less good (farewell
telegrams) and overloaded some (the fax machine changed how people dealt with letters).</p>

<p>What email and Twitter have in common is that they made it <em>practical</em> to express things that were
before possible to express, but impractical. They are communications innovations not because they
do something better that older forms did well, but rather, because they do something well that
older forms did poorly. This is why Twitter is supremely unlikely to replace IRC: they are good at
different things. Conversely, this is why email often replaces a letter that is written on paper,
sealed in an envelope, marked with a stamp, and put in the mailbox: most of what you want a letter
to do, an email does better. Not all, but most.</p>

<p>So I don&rsquo;t harsh on Twitter for brevity and incompleteness: it&rsquo;s an ephemeral medium, by design,
and it&rsquo;s to the credit of Williams, Stone, and their team that they cultivated technical
limitations into an interesting way to express oneself. &ldquo;Twitter is not good at sustained and
complex conversation&rdquo; is merely facts on the ground: this is part of why
<a href="http://branch.com">Branch</a> and <a href="http://medium.com">Medium</a> exist.  On the other hand, I&rsquo;m
perfectly willing to kvetch at individual Twitter users for using the service for things that it is
not good at and never will be good at&mdash;more on that later.</p>

<p>The question of <em>what is Twitter for?</em> is perpetually up for debate; I won&rsquo;t attempt it here. What
I can authoritatively answer, though, is the question of <em>what do I want Twitter for?</em> I want a
stream of answers to the question &ldquo;what&rsquo;s interesting lately?&rdquo; (with a conscious caveat that people
of course provide the same variety of answers to that as they do in offline life), a river of
idea-seeds, and a conversation at the speed of a fencing match. Twitter should be a great place to
<em>start</em> things: to find or express a new idea, to ask a question and get concise answers, to point
people towards something that matters to you.</p>

<p>Often, Twitter falls short of this. This is not necessarily Twitter&rsquo;s fault, but it&rsquo;s certainly a
good enough reason to leave.</p>

<h3>Noise without signal</h3>

<p>Too often, Twitter is like a noisy party: even if it&rsquo;s full of people you like, you can&rsquo;t be paying
attention to everyone at once, and a high enough population means that it becomes difficult to
actually talk even with people who are trying to talk to you in return. That&rsquo;s an annoyingly easy
situation to get into even when you&rsquo;re trying to avoid it. By contrast, Twitter turned into the
flying, destructive, multi-generational party from <em>Life, the Universe, and Everything</em> some time
in 2010 and has not improved since (including the part about <em>&ldquo;one of the problems with a party
that never stops is that all the things that only seem like a good idea at parties continue to seem
like good ideas&rdquo;</em>).</p>

<p>The noisy-party thing is quite annoying to me: I&rsquo;m picky to start with, I can&rsquo;t stand following
more than about 100 people. My Twitter stream stops being useful and enjoyable when its population
gets significantly bigger than my
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar%27s_number">monkeysphere</a>. It&rsquo;s similar to my thoughts on how
many physical objects you should own: if you&rsquo;re ignoring an object in your home or a voice you&rsquo;re
following on Twitter, why is it there in the first place? You are a human with a finite attention
span that you don&rsquo;t actually have a choice about respecting. If you&rsquo;re following 1,000 people on
Twitter, it is almost certain that you&rsquo;re not really listening to what most of those people have to
say&mdash;which means in my opinion that you should just not be following them.</p>

<h3>People are used by spammers</h3>

<p>On top of that, people don&rsquo;t always speak for themselves, but regularly have their voices
appropriated (consensually or not as the case may be) by the most tediously screeching and
incoherent kind of commercial and political interests. Reading Twitter is less worth my time when
people push every gas-station fill-up, every FourSquare check-in, and every whale-shaving petition
they sign, to their Twitter stream&mdash;part of why
<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id428851691?partnerId=30&amp;siteID=k*tkOlz87uA">Tweetbot</a> and
<a href="http://www.floodgap.com/software/ttytter/">TTYtter</a> were my favorite clients was that they had
robust filtering abilities to silence such bullshit.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s just the things that people click on themselves, mind you: there&rsquo;s also a thriving community
of accounts that are spammers from top to bottom, ways to get people to tweet on your behalf
without noticing beforehand, and attempts to hijack Twitter accounts for the purpose of posting
malicious links of one kind or another. As busy as that community is, fortunately it is not very
successful. So the main problem here is less that malicious actors may jump in, than it is that
people choose to permit the forces of idiocy to speak on their half. Ugh.</p>

<h3>Private accounts are bullshit</h3>

<p>This annoyance is multiplied when people make it harder to listen to them speaking in the first
place by the expedient of private accounts&mdash;which I consider to be a wart on Twitter&rsquo;s
design. There are a small number of good reasons to have a locked Twitter account: if you have to
ask, yours probably doesn&rsquo;t make the grade. So I&rsquo;m talking about the majority of locked accounts
here, not 100% of them. That said: locked accounts degrade the Twitter experience and show poor
judgment, and I wouldn&rsquo;t be the least bit sad to see Twitter disable them entirely.</p>

<p>One of the big virtues of Twitter is serendipity: the property that things you say might be picked
up by unknown others, that you may have unplanned interactions, that someone may say &ldquo;ahah, but
what about <em>this</em> related piece of information?&rdquo; and you&rsquo;ll have something new and interesting in
your day. Private accounts are free-riders there, partaking of the benefits of that community
dynamic without giving back.</p>

<p>Locked accounts also make the Twitter experience worse by giving the middle finger to the normal
&ldquo;follow or not?&rdquo; decision. Normally on Twitter, you decide whether or not to follow someone by
looking at what they&rsquo;ve said and asking, &ldquo;do I want to see that in my stream of new messages?&rdquo; But
private accounts are like &ldquo;nope, trust me or fuck off.&rdquo; Your plan for evaluating whether a private
account is worth following rather involves being on the other side of this airtight
hatchway. That&rsquo;s bad, that breaks the virtuous cycle of &ldquo;if you want people to follow you, post
things worth reading.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Creating a private account also usually shows poor judgment: one of the normal failure modes of
private-account-holders is thinking that Twitter is a substitute for LiveJournal. In the
LiveJournal paradigm, it&rsquo;s totally reasonable to have an account where your statements are private
by default and once in a while you say something to the world at large, or to have your primary
account and your &ldquo;after dark&rdquo; account. That works somewhat on LiveJournal, but it&rsquo;s a ruinously bad
fit for Twitter.</p>

<p>On LJ, your replies to other people&rsquo;s statements (comments on their entries) are generally not
private, and you can selectively step out of private mode to say something to the
world. LiveJournal provides an array of technical tools that you can use to modulate your
expression between public and private. Twitter does not give you such tools: if you reply to
someone&rsquo;s tweet, they can&rsquo;t see you unless they&rsquo;re already on the other side of the airtight
hatchway, and you can&rsquo;t say &ldquo;this tweet will be public, but just this one time.&rdquo; So you&rsquo;re not a
full participant the way you are on LiveJournal.</p>

<p>The other way that private accounts show poor judgment is summed up in &ldquo;After Dark&rdquo; accounts. I
think that those are almost always a bad idea: maintaining multiple Twitter accounts is a major
headache, but more importantly, <em>Twitter is a broadcast medium.</em> You are not excused from
discretion! Even if Twitter is &ldquo;oh that&rsquo;s where my friends are&rdquo; to you, there are things that it&rsquo;s
a bad idea to say in public&mdash;and Twitter is public, like the Web in general. Communicating
discreetly with your friends about your kinks is definitely not one of the things that Twitter is
good at. I also think that if you are the kind of person who is comfortable talking about your sex
life (or your mental health, or similarly mainstream-culture-proscribed subjects) in your public
voice, then people who can&rsquo;t handle hearing about that from time to time should not be following
you. Your voice should be <em>yours</em> first, when it&rsquo;s a personal voice like Twitter: it is fine and
necessary to modulate one&rsquo;s professional voice according to audience demands, but a personal voice
should be <em>personal</em> and heartfelt and true-to-self above other things.</p>

<h3>False urgency and false equivalency</h3>

<p>Then there&rsquo;s a somewhat more abstract concern: the &ldquo;flattening&rdquo; of expression. Because of the size
limit on tweets and the way that Twitter strives for simplicity of presentation, all tweets have
roughly equal visual weight. Unfortunately, this means that drastically different content looks and
reads the same. It bothers me that &ldquo;my hopes for a good Transformers movie died,&rdquo; &ldquo;my dog died at
the age of 20,&rdquo; and &ldquo;my mother died at the age of 48&rdquo; all have the same look. It&rsquo;s extraordinarily
challenging to modulate this with regards to user-generated content, but I think that some level of
it is necessary because inviting us to consider every statement on Twitter to be equivalent in
importance, is not a good thing.</p>

<p>This is worse when it comes to arguments, because &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think the evidence supports that&rdquo; looks
like &ldquo;you smell like a goat&rsquo;s asshole&rdquo; in your timeline. Or more germanely: the sponsored tweet
looks very much like your friend&rsquo;s tweet about how the President is a godless Commie Muslim bent on
destroying the gold standard, which in turn looks very much like your other friend&rsquo;s tweet about
how the President is a simpering and ineffectual prat who&rsquo;s set back his cause by decades.</p>

<p>I am not entirely satisfied with the metaphor that Twitter &ldquo;flattens&rdquo; these expressions, but it&rsquo;s
important to me because it&rsquo;s symptomatic of a design that is not clearly enough communicating to
people what Twitter is good at and why they should use it for that&mdash;and not for other things. Of
course people are going to use Twitter for things that it&rsquo;s bad at as well as for things that it&rsquo;s
good at. We do that with email, letters, and video, too. It still bothers me.</p>

<p>One aspect which especially bothers me is that this flattening can lend a false urgency to
things. One feels a need to reify alarming and attention-grabbing tweets before they disappear by
replying to or acting on them. This is a dangerous road to walk. We already as humans have problems
judging urgency: misjudging urgency reliably drives us to do stupid things. Twitter&rsquo;s format
encourages this because the ephemeral nature of tweets creates a sense of time running out, of
opportunity in the middle of disappearing. It is no accident that that exact urgency is also used
as a sales technique: it drives us to make hasty and poorly-considered decisions.</p>

<p>I suspect that this problem would be less annoying if I were less enmeshed in the furry community,
which has an ongoing issue with people who are already grievously prone to inaccurately judging
urgency and to thereby creating massive social problems. The urgency problem is a human universal,
though, so I&rsquo;d probably see the same thing to greater or lesser degree among medievalists or
knitters.</p>

<h3>What now?</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure how badly all of these things bother me about Twitter&mdash;but it&rsquo;s definitely enough to
make me take a break for a while. I&rsquo;m also consciously cultivating other forms of my own
expression&mdash;like this blog!&mdash;to see whether I&rsquo;m thinking things that are best expressed in ways
other than Twitter. I&rsquo;m enjoying that so far, and I expect that it&rsquo;ll be a fruitful exercise.</p>

<p>If you decide to stay with Twitter, I wish you the best, and I hope that you either find these
problems less serious than I do or have better ways of coping with them (if you do, please mention
it to me). For my part, I&rsquo;ve noticed that in addition to these problems existing, they are problems
either with the design of Twitter as a service and social mileu, or with how other people use
Twitter. Neither is within my power to unilaterally change, which makes turning my face away from
Twitter more appealing since I can change that quite easily.</p>

<p><em>postscript:</em> A correspondant points out that
<a href="http://penny-arcade.com/comic/2013/02/11">Penny Arcade also has a critique</a> of
certain styles of Twitter usage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
