<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: perversions | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/perversions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-25T10:47:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EDIRD: Why Do Birds Suddenly Appear]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-why-do-birds-suddenly-appear/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T09:43:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-why-do-birds-suddenly-appear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="560" height="420"
        allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/re-6eOhrejE?color=white&theme=light"> </iframe></p>

<p>Speaking of cinema: <em>Mirrormask</em> was quite a thing. For one thing, giving Dave McKean millions of
dollars to make a movie results in visual deliciousness. For another thing, looking back, I see
this prefiguring a bunch of my friends' kinks. Hello clockwork robot mind-control scene with a hint
of transformation!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Werewolf In A Men's Prison]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/werewolf-in-a-mens-prison/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T18:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/werewolf-in-a-mens-prison</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good <a href="news:">news:</a> a judge pushing back against hate-your-sex-life obscenity laws!</p>

<p>Better <a href="news:">news:</a> by reading werewolf porn and deciding &ldquo;well that&rsquo;s not so bad&rdquo;!</p>

<p>The Atlantic Wire reports, in an article that you will not regret reading:</p>

<blockquote><p>Andres Martinez, serving time for attempted murder and robbery at the Secured Housing Unit at
Pelican Bay State Prison in California, is free to read his werewolf-human erotica novel,
according to a decision handed down by the First District Court of Appeal. [&hellip;] prison officials
confiscated the book, calling it obscene, because it contains sexually explicit passages and
&ldquo;advocates violence.&rdquo; [&hellip;] The case also pushes back on obscenity standards in its analysis of
the value of the overall text, making it more difficult to label a written work as obscene. In
short, more justices might have to read, think about, and write opinions on werewolf erotica.</p></blockquote>

<p>I am in favor of basically all of this, as a reader and writer of werewolf smut. :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
