<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: anarchism | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/anarchism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-08T07:37:40-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every Day Is Repost Day: Happy Birthday From Planet Motherfucker]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/every-day-is-repost-day-happy-birthday-from-planet-motherfucker/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T10:03:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/every-day-is-repost-day-happy-birthday-from-planet-motherfucker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>This is how it works. I ride my bike down the street looking in apartment
windows until I see a TV set. I ride right next to the sidewalk, letting the
very hot air move over my arms and chest. When I see a TV set, big blue
square through the parted curtains and behind the translucency of the insect
screen, I reach behind me and unsling the biathlon rifle from my back.</p>

<p>Fucking sights are bouncing all over because it&rsquo;s a standing shot - always
hard - and my heart rate is way up. I wait for the old ticker to bump the
sight picture back up and snap it off. A gratifying &ldquo;glass rod breaking&rdquo; 4
pound trigger pull and I watch the TV go dark and listen to the screaming
from inside the apartment. One down.</p></blockquote>

<p>I used to read a lot of <a href="http://everything2.com">E2</a> and to write a bit there. It&rsquo;s an older chunk
of the Internet, and a younger me loved it. The story I&rsquo;m linking to is one that stirred up
proto-anarchist impulses me in, and is also just a great bit of short fiction. I go back and
re-read it every year or two; I strongly recommend that you do likewise. It is still relevant,
sadly. I expect that the part about TVs will become irrelevant much earlier than the part about the
police forces and the evil idiocy of the authoritarian state.</p>

<p>Both as a writer and as a reader, you are an archaeologist: you are constantly interrogating the
past. So I try to make a habit of pointing out things from the past&mdash;I had a strong LiveJournal
habit of doing that, and if you followed me on LJ in years gone, well, you&rsquo;ll probably see some of
the same pieces popping up again. They have remained sweet, bitter, and enlightening.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
