<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: furry | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/furry/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-02T10:49:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Target Of Realism]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-target-of-realism/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-16T21:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-target-of-realism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The furry subculture has a troubled relationship with &ldquo;realism;&rdquo; I want to introduce a distinction
that helped me resolve the question in a satisfying way. When someone says &ldquo;realistic,&rdquo; they almost
always are assuming that realism is just one thing. It is not: realism assumes that there is a
reality and a portrayal and that the portrayal is more or less faithful to the reality. The
problems with this approach crop up quickly when you&rsquo;re talking about realism in the context of
fiction or speculation or <em>gedankenexperiments</em>. Is Maxwell&rsquo;s Demon realistic? Are the geopolitics
of Middle-Earth realistic? Is my inverse-square-law-violating furry avatar realistic? Attempts to
answer these questions get messy quickly.</p>

<p>What I want to introduce is the idea of realism as a direction. You are realistic <em>to</em> something,
not just &ldquo;realistic&rdquo; in general. Most of the time, &ldquo;realistic&rdquo; means that the thing whose realism
we are evaluating, is displaying more or less fidelty to our everyday lives and the world as we
experience it through fragile bodies and imperfect senses. So far, so good. But when we inhabit
furry avatars and personas and masks, that isn&rsquo;t and can&rsquo;t be what it means. We are being realistic
to something else.</p>

<p>People are being realistic <strong>to their own desires.</strong> In the case of the furry subculture&rsquo;s
collective sex life, that&rsquo;s realistic to their erotic desires. I argue that if you use this as your
lens of &ldquo;realism,&rdquo; you can spare yourself a great deal of <em>tsuris</em>. It is generally not necessary
to decide whether one dragon is more realistic than another and in the cases where it is, you
should be making the determination with a skill that everyone should be practicing: the ability to
detect sincerity.</p>

<p>If you want to see this kind of realism in a different context, I recommend reading
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1594650640/?tag=usefultigress-20">The Metabarons</a> and
considering how it is realistic to its creator&rsquo;s (batshit insane and very enjoyable) vision. It is
a great example of the sci-fi writers' dictum that you get one free break from reality-as-we-know
it and everything else must follow.</p>

<p>It won&rsquo;t make you happy to judge creative work by its fidelity to everyday life you experience
walking around when the creation of it gave no attention to that fidelity. It may say things about
everyday life that you want to engage with, but resist the urge to say that its relationship to
everyday life is the only thing that it can be realistic to. There are plenty of flaws that a thing
may have while still being faithful to itself (self-indulgent, dopey, insipid &mdash; it is all too
easy to be these things too while still being realistic to one&rsquo;s desires).</p>

<p>You should especially not fall into that realism-trap if you&rsquo;re actively participating in such
creative works&mdash;that is to say, you&rsquo;re publishing them on FurAffinity or Weasyl or participating
in collective creation on Tapestries, Shangri-La, and such. In those areas, you should definitely
prioritize being faithful to people&rsquo;s desires and fantasies, because that&rsquo;s the <em>raison d'être</em> of
those places: being realistic to people&rsquo;s erotic desires. The trap is a tempting one: resist it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
