<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: capitalism | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/capitalism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-19T21:43:15-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Unexpected Perspective]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/an-unexpected-perspective/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-13T11:20:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/an-unexpected-perspective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of all the people, Ben Bernanke saying this!</p>

<blockquote><p>We have been taught that meritocratic institutions and societies are fair. Putting aside the
reality that no system, including our own, is really entirely meritocratic, meritocracies may be
fairer and more efficient than some alternatives. But fair in an absolute sense? Think about
it. A meritocracy is a system in which the people who are the luckiest in their health and
genetic endowment; luckiest in terms of family support, encouragement, and, probably, income;
luckiest in their educational and career opportunities; and luckiest in so many other ways
difficult to enumerate&mdash;these are the folks who reap the largest rewards. <strong>The only way for
even a putative meritocracy to hope to pass ethical muster, to be considered fair, is if those
who are the luckiest in all of those respects also have the greatest responsibility to work hard,
to contribute to the betterment of the world, and to share their luck with others.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>That is a deeply surprising and encouraging thing to hear one of the mascots of capitalism
saying. It is perhaps the case that saying this mostly accomplishes making him and the rich white
(mostly) kids he&rsquo;s addressing feel good about themselves. But it is still a true thing said
straightforwardly and firmly, and I applaud that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Cola Road]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-cola-road/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-17T09:24:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-cola-road</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Has it come to this, that humanitarian efforts are reduced to being epiphytes
upon capitalism? While I admire the medical-supply-distributing efforts of the
people in this video, I&rsquo;m somewhat horrified by the thought that vampire-squid
capitalism has so penetrated the world that you can&rsquo;t get things done except by
following in its wake.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
