<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: firstperson | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/firstperson/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-22T18:16:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Promises I Make When I Talk To You]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/promises-i-make-when-i-talk-to-you/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-22T17:57:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2016/promises-i-make-when-i-talk-to-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I say this a lot in casual conversation, so I may as well write it down.
Here are some promises I&rsquo;m making when I&rsquo;m talking to people.
These hold for everyone I talk to; I also think they&rsquo;re good rules in general.</p>

<ol>
<li>I promise that you are the first and only judge of whether or not you care about something, whether or not it&rsquo;s important to you.</li>
<li>I promise that you are not boring when you talk about the stuff you care about.</li>
<li>I promise that it&rsquo;s okay to talk about what&rsquo;s important to you without apology or shame.</li>
<li>I promise that stuff that&rsquo;s important to you, is important enough to talk about: your life <em>should</em> matter to you!
That the rest of the world exists, doesn&rsquo;t obviate that the events of your life are important to you.</li>
<li>I promise it is okay to talk about the things you want and need to talk about.</li>
<li>I promise that it is okay to <em>not</em> talk about the things you don&rsquo;t want to talk about.</li>
<li>I promise it is okay to talk about things that you&rsquo;re unsure about.
Thinking about something by talking about it is a valuable tool.
Some thoughts are much easier to think with that tool than with wordless solo introspection.</li>
<li>I promise you are qualified to talk about your own experience and your own opinion.</li>
</ol>


<p>Basically, I like to think that when I talk to people I&rsquo;m fond of (I try to also do this with people I dislike, but I do not always succeed), I default to taking you seriously, listening as a peer, and assuming that you <em>matter.</em>
You deserve safety, health, and happiness.
We all deserve that.</p>

<p>My ideas here are heavily informed by Alice Miller&rsquo;s notion of a &ldquo;helping witness,&rdquo; but going into detail about that is another post (and a rather grim one, at that).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
