<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: fiction | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/fiction/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-23T12:32:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every Day Is Repost Day: Happy Birthday From Planet Motherfucker]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/every-day-is-repost-day-happy-birthday-from-planet-motherfucker/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T10:03:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/every-day-is-repost-day-happy-birthday-from-planet-motherfucker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>This is how it works. I ride my bike down the street looking in apartment
windows until I see a TV set. I ride right next to the sidewalk, letting the
very hot air move over my arms and chest. When I see a TV set, big blue
square through the parted curtains and behind the translucency of the insect
screen, I reach behind me and unsling the biathlon rifle from my back.</p>

<p>Fucking sights are bouncing all over because it&rsquo;s a standing shot - always
hard - and my heart rate is way up. I wait for the old ticker to bump the
sight picture back up and snap it off. A gratifying &ldquo;glass rod breaking&rdquo; 4
pound trigger pull and I watch the TV go dark and listen to the screaming
from inside the apartment. One down.</p></blockquote>

<p>I used to read a lot of <a href="http://everything2.com">E2</a> and to write a bit there. It&rsquo;s an older chunk
of the Internet, and a younger me loved it. The story I&rsquo;m linking to is one that stirred up
proto-anarchist impulses me in, and is also just a great bit of short fiction. I go back and
re-read it every year or two; I strongly recommend that you do likewise. It is still relevant,
sadly. I expect that the part about TVs will become irrelevant much earlier than the part about the
police forces and the evil idiocy of the authoritarian state.</p>

<p>Both as a writer and as a reader, you are an archaeologist: you are constantly interrogating the
past. So I try to make a habit of pointing out things from the past&mdash;I had a strong LiveJournal
habit of doing that, and if you followed me on LJ in years gone, well, you&rsquo;ll probably see some of
the same pieces popping up again. They have remained sweet, bitter, and enlightening.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dreamblogging: Encountering the second wave]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/dreamblogging-encountering-the-second-wave/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-05T15:25:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/dreamblogging-encountering-the-second-wave</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My dream was an arthouse film. The director wanted to both interrogate her experience of second-wave feminism and to partially rebuke it. It was a murder anti-mystery. The murder happens ten minutes in and it is never in doubt to characters or audience who did it. The murder victim is the only male character in the story, and I&rsquo;m not sure whether he had a name. Everyone on-screen was a woman. The murderer was tracked down, apprehended, tried, and convicted, but most of the people involved were aware that her resistance to any of these steps was perfunctory. The whole edifice of justice operates without men involved - it was distinctly not vigilante justice, it was just an operation of the courts that happened not to involve men at all. The women involved spanned a wide age range - there were definitely some precocious ten-year-olds and tweens in there as well as some high-school students. The point was to show participants and audience a world in which women operate all of these things is not only not particularly difficult to imagine, but it&rsquo;s also possible to enact if you&rsquo;re clever about it. The world is not better or worse run by just women - but isn&rsquo;t it peculiar that the world we live in is run mostly like this but with men at the helm?</p>

<p>I have some problems with the system independent of who&rsquo;s operating it and I&rsquo;m not sure that the director agreed with me about that. But it was a good movie, and it appealed to me that the protagonist and her unseen collaborators among the police and prosecution only with difficulty came to the conclusion that demonstrating their principles was worth two lives.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
