<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: politics | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-19T21:43:15-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nobody Gives A Shit About Freedom Zero]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/nobody-gives-a-shit-about-freedom-zero/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-19T09:18:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/nobody-gives-a-shit-about-freedom-zero</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I went back in time a little today and noted Mark &ldquo;410 Gone&rdquo; Pilgrim&rsquo;s 2008 post,
&ldquo;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20100608015359/http://diveintomark.org/archives/2008/01/17/of-canaries-and-coal-mines">Of Canaries And Coal Mines</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>So after 18 months, I think we can safely say that no, Cory [Doctorow] and I were not &ldquo;canaries
in the coal mine.&rdquo; There are not hordes of fed-up consumers rejecting Apple&rsquo;s vision of
cryptographic lock-in. There are not mass graves where people ceremoniously dump their crippled,
non-general-purpose computing devices. Outside of Planet Debian and my own personal echo chamber,
nobody gives a shit about Freedom 0.</p></blockquote>

<p>Since then, things have only gone further in the direction that Pilgrim and Doctorow despaired
about. Apple has sold a preposterously large number of iPhones and iPads, large enough that it&rsquo;s
actually a bit difficult to get a grasp on how much the game has changed. I&rsquo;m just gonna quote
Marco Arment, since <a href="http://www.marco.org/2010/08/19/a-smartphone-retrospective">he absolutely called it</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Smartphones were an established consumer-electronics market with devices that people thought were
pretty cool, but often frustrating and with serious shortcomings and design flaws. &hellip; Other
manufacturers had neglected touchscreens for years, but Apple figured out how to do a touchscreen
well, and did.  Fans of the former types of smartphones and much of the tech press declared this
smartphone useless or not capable enough because of its lack of a keyboard, its non-removable
battery, its lack of expansion slots or ports, and other hardware features in which Apple chose
differently from what most other manufacturers were doing.  That ended up not mattering. Now,
most high-end smartphones look like [the iPhone]. &hellip; [Criticism of the iPad] ended up not
mattering. And now, other manufacturers are scrambling to build tablet products as quickly as
possible.  How do you think the subcompact, inexpensive computer category will look in three
years?</p></blockquote>

<p>Now, I&rsquo;m willing to take some cheap shots at this: it&rsquo;s what I do, I snicker a little cruelly when
I imagine Cory Doctorow <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20110716072627/http://www.adcouncil.org/default.aspx?id=132">in the role of Iron Eyes Cody</a>, a single tear rolling down
his cheek as he realizes that there are untold billions of people who don&rsquo;t care about &ldquo;Freedom
Zero.&rdquo; His tear is the tear of the modernist project, the realization that whoops, Western European
affluent-white-dude values are not in fact universal, and there may have to be some difficult
negotiation in the future to figure out (a) what values people advocate (b) what values they
actually live by and &copy; whether people can get along within the self-imposed constraints of (a)
and (b).</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t get genuinely angry at Doctorow, though. I&rsquo;m pretty bummed out when I think that billions
of people don&rsquo;t share <em>my</em> values, because I&rsquo;m as egotistical as anyone else and still have a nice
little candle in my heart of &ldquo;If <em>I</em> was running the show you&rsquo;d see some changes around here pretty
darn quick!&rdquo; At worst I think he&rsquo;s kinda naïve. It&rsquo;s borderline tautological to say that people
outside the engineer/hacker culture and professions do not share its ideological concerns. If you
walked up to an attorney cold and asked her what &ldquo;Freedom Zero&rdquo; was, you would probably get an
answer that has nothing to do with &ldquo;screws, not glue.&rdquo; The phrase might register as a complete
non-sequitur to a scuba dive instructor, a barista, a social worker, an undergraduate working the
register at a gas station, a costumed worker at Disneyland.</p>

<p>I acknowledge the counterargument of &ldquo;if people were more informed about the issue, they&rsquo;d care,&rdquo;
but you have to note that that&rsquo;s an argument you can make about <em>anything</em> and it&rsquo;s perilously
close to the fallacy of &ldquo;if people were better informed they&rsquo;d agree with me!&rdquo; So I think that it&rsquo;s
to be avoided. What I think is that people care about themselves first&mdash;thinking as our
rational-logical selves, paying rigorous attention to our professed ideals and to how our actions
fit them or fail to, is difficult and we&rsquo;re usually half-assing it. Yes, all of us, because we&rsquo;re
all fallible people prone to thinking more about what we want than whether getting it is worthwhile
or having it will actually make us as happy as we think.</p>

<p>One of my favorite jabs at this human tendency comes from the San Francisco stand-up comic Will
Durst, who <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/album/id260036485?partnerId=30&amp;siteID=k*tkOlz87uA">had a great riff on it in the early Bush years</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, man. That 300 bucks last August&mdash;that rebate check came in handy. I live
here in town, I paid off two parking tickets with it. But we had this windfall, we could have
done <em>anything</em> with it. We could have paid for every hot lunch program in America through the
year 2054. We could have put in a down payment on prescription drugs, which they talked about
last November and now we haven&rsquo;t heard Word One of. We could have done a lot.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Oh no, no, you can&rsquo;t do that. Uh-uh. No.&rdquo; &ldquo;Why?&rdquo; &ldquo;Well, the American People <em>want</em> tax cuts.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Well <strong>duh!</strong> The American People also want drive-through nickel beer night! The American People
want to lose weight by eating ice cream. The American People would chew off their own <em>foot</em> if
Oprah told them there was liquid gold in their ankle veins! The American People love the Home
Shopping Network because it&rsquo;s commercial-free.</p></blockquote>

<p>Humanity has a long and illustrious track record of wanting things that aren&rsquo;t particularly good
for us. I&rsquo;m not saying that Freedom Zero is one of those things. I&rsquo;m actually with Doctorow in that
I think that more people tinkering, exploring, and creating, is inherently a Good Thing. I just
think that Freedom Zero is a bit too narrowly defined, and thus Doctorow tends to undervalue good
things produced by people who don&rsquo;t care as much about freedom-to-tinker as he does. At this point
I think it&rsquo;s very safe to say that the &ldquo;iPads are for consumption&rdquo; canard is dead, but it&rsquo;s not
just that. The deal with iPhones and the Apple ecosystem in general, is that they&rsquo;re a
trade-off. It&rsquo;s fine for Doctorow to reject that trade-off for himself, but I think that he&rsquo;s in
error with his rationale for encouraging others to reject it; I think he&rsquo;s projecting his values
onto them. That&rsquo;s an error. If you go and look at what people are doing with their devices, you&rsquo;ll
find that they&rsquo;re doing things that are valuable to <em>them,</em> which is unrelated to what&rsquo;s valuable
to Cory Doctorow.</p>

<p>If you want to persuade others, to talk them into changing their behavior, you need to figure out
what&rsquo;s important to them and avoid assuming that what matters to you matters to them. That&rsquo;s part
of what makes persuasion hard&mdash;that and the massive disconnect between what we profess to want and
what we are actually happier to have. That&rsquo;s my vote for what people <em>should</em> care about: being
clear on our own desires.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[She's Been Working On The Railroad]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T12:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/shes-been-working-on-the-railroad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now I am the kind of person who read <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> once in high school and came away with an
uneasy feeling rather than a burning conviction: it felt somehow petty to me. This is probably
because I was reading Asimov&rsquo;s <em>Foundation</em> novels at the same time, and the contrast between Hari
Seldon and John Galt was dramatic and deeply unflattering to Galt. Faced with a cruel and
overbearing government, a lone genius opts to found a colony of the like-minded in a secluded
place. However, their tactics are strikingly different: Galt opts to affirmatively destroy the
system, heedless of consequences, while Hari Seldon is all about mindfulness of the consequences. I
think that&rsquo;s one of the things that really gets to me about the center of the Randian movement:
despite pretensions of intellectualism, they are blinded both to where they came from and where
they are going. That is not a good recipe for a movement.</p>

<p>Those are broad strokes, though: there is a specific thing I&rsquo;d forgotten, that Adam Lee ably points
out:</p>

<blockquote><p>Of all the businesses Rand could have chosen for her heroes, I always thought that railroads were
a bad choice to show the superiority of laissez-faire capitalism. After all, railroads, like
other forms of infrastructure, almost always take major government support and investment to
build. [&hellip;] In reality, the first American transcontinental railroad required major government
financial support&mdash;to the tune of $16,000 per mile, rising to $48,000 per mile over the Rocky
Mountains&mdash;plus extensive land grants. Modern engineering projects of similar scope, like the
Keystone XL pipeline, have been embroiled in court fights with dozens of private landowners who
don’t want to sell, and Keystone’s builders have been extremely aggressive about invoking eminent
domain.</p></blockquote>

<p>The story proceeds from merely unrealistic, as Lee notes here, to gleefully barbaric. It is part of
a pattern where every time I think &ldquo;well, I should maybe give <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> another chance, as
literature if not as dogma,&rdquo; some excerpt or another comes along and convinces me that Rand was
definitely the predecessor to L. Ron Hubbard: promulgating a con-job religion on the backs of some
awful sci-fi novels. Ugh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EDIRD: Morphine-Seeky]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-morphine-seeky/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-14T10:01:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/edird-morphine-seeky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was struck recently by how <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060512806/?tag=usefultigress-20">Neal Stephenson&rsquo;s Cryptonomicon</a> has remained
relevant. Here&rsquo;s one of my favorite passages.</p>

<blockquote><p>Men who believe that they are accomplishing something by speaking speak in a different way from
men who believe that speaking is a waste of time. Bobby Shaftoe has learned most of his practical
knowledge&mdash;how to fix a car, butcher a deer, throw a spiral, talk to a lady, kill a Nip&mdash;from
the latter type of man. For them, trying to do anything by talking is like trying to pound in a
nail with a screwdriver. Sometimes you can even see the desperation spread over such a man&rsquo;s face
as he listens to himself speak.</p>

<p>Men of the other type, the ones who use speech as a tool of their work, who are confident and
fluent, aren&rsquo;t necessarily more intelligent, or even more educated. It took Shaftoe a long time
to figure that out. Anyway, everything was neat and tidy in Bobby Shaftoe&rsquo;s mind until he met two
of the men in Detachment 2702: Enoch Root and Lawrence Pritchard Waterhouse. [He began] to
suspect that there might be a third category of man, a kind so rare that Shaftoe never met any of
them until now.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t like the word &lsquo;addict&rsquo; because it has terrible connotations,&rdquo; Root says one day, as they
are sunning themselves on the afterdeck. &ldquo;Instead of slapping a label on you, the Germans would
describe you as &lsquo;Morphiumsüchtig.&rsquo; The verb &lsquo;suchen&rsquo; means to seek. So that might be translated,
loosely, as &lsquo;morphine seeky&rsquo; or even more loosely as &lsquo;morphine seeking.&rsquo; I prefer &lsquo;seeky&rsquo; because
it means that you have an inclination to seek morphine.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What the fuck are you talking about?&rdquo; Shaftoe says.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, suppose you have a roof with a hole in it. That means it is a leaky roof. It&rsquo;s leaky all
the time even if it&rsquo;s not raining at the moment. But it&rsquo;s only leaking when it happens to be
raining. In the same way, morphine seeky means that you always have this tendency to look for
morphine, even if you are not looking for it at the moment. But I prefer both of them to
&lsquo;addict,&rsquo; because they are adjectives modifying Bobby Shaftoe instead of a noun that obliterates
Bobby Shaftoe.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;So what&rsquo;s the point?&rdquo; Shaftoe asks. He asks this because he is expecting Root to give him an
order, which is usually what men of the talkative sort end up doing after jabbering on for a
while. But no order seems to be forthcoming, because that&rsquo;s not Root&rsquo;s agenda. Root just felt
like talking about words. [&hellip;] Waterhouse never gives direct orders, so men of the first
category don&rsquo;t know what to make of him. But apparently men of the second category fare no
better; such men usually talk like they have an agenda in their heads and they are checking off
boxes as they go, but Waterhouse&rsquo;s conversation doesn&rsquo;t go anywhere in particular. He speaks, not
as a way of telling you a bunch of stuff he&rsquo;s already figured out, but as a way of making up a
bunch of new shit as he goes along. And he always seems to be hoping that you&rsquo;ll join in. Which
no one ever does, except for Enoch Root.</p></blockquote>

<p>There are two things that I find compelling about this incident. One is that people&rsquo;s relationships
to words and meaning is a leitmotif of the book, and this moment makes explicit (as opposed to
demonstrating) that as Bobby Shaftoe does, you can live a satisfying life without getting deeply
into word-games and syntactic manipulation. The world around you is available to you directly:
abstractions are not the only valid way to engage with it. Randy, another protagonist, by contrast
worries that he&rsquo;s &ldquo;too much of a Platonist&rdquo; and spends a lot of time introspecting as he
participates in a plot to build a digital currency founded on cryptography&mdash;on meaning selectively
obscured.</p>

<p>The basic setup of the book, where one set of characters are attempting to jumpstart a digital,
crypto-based currency and are harassed by the US Government, should definitely remind you of
BitCoin, other digital currency experiments, and the particular tactics which the 2000-2013
government of the United States uses to retain power. That part&rsquo;s
easy. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Totalitarian">A government that demands ability to participate in every aspect of civic and private life</a>,
necessarily reacts with great hostility to the idea that people might have real privacy at all, let
alone a right to it. There has been plenty of ink spilled about this, so I&rsquo;ll leave off for the
moment.</p>

<p>The other way in which this passage sheds light is the spiel about being &ldquo;morphine-seeky.&rdquo; I have
come to find that very important to my views, or at least to be a good way of articulating
them. It&rsquo;s pretty much pure <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sapir-Whorf_Hypothesis">Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis</a> stuff: the way that you describe the
world has a feedback loop with how you percieve the world and how you act on those descriptions and
perceptions (notice again the connection to the book&rsquo;s themes about constructing meaning). This is
why I bristle when someone uses the shorthand &ldquo;illegals&rdquo; for anyone (in practice, anyone brown) who
is in the United States for an extended period of time without having gone through the
Wagner-length tragedy that is our immigration bureaucracy. &ldquo;Illegal&rdquo; is a noun that obliterates the
actual person&mdash;and a certain political persuasion likes little better than an excuse to do
violence to the person of immigrants or suspected immigrants.</p>

<p>It is also a good principle to keep in mind when we describe one another. I share a community, the
furry subculture, with a lot of people with mental health problems. We have a bit more practice at
dealing with the problem of integrating everyone in the community healthily, but we are just
people, and so we fail as often as anyone else at coping. One of the pole-stars for me in this
situation is Root&rsquo;s advice: adjectives, not nouns. Don&rsquo;t reduce people to their disabilities, their
tropes, their health problems, their kinks, their politics, or to the last thing they did that hurt
your feelings.</p>

<p>Of course it is also a good guideline for life in general: if you are reducing people to
conveniently dumbed-down nouns, you are refusing to acknowledge their full personhood. This is a
reliable way to rationalize harmful behavior. I buy into the notion that one of the roots of evil
is treating people as means to an end, rather than as ends in themselves&mdash;as fully realized beings
with their own aspirations, plans, and flaws. There is no simplification of a person that stands up
to great scrutiny, that works in the general case.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reagan Was Not Alone In Horridness]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/reagan-was-not-alone-in-horridness/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T07:39:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/reagan-was-not-alone-in-horridness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a supplement to making it clear that I think that
<a href="http://www.usefultigress.com/blog/2013/this-is-what-anger-looks-like/">Ronald Reagan was Satan&rsquo;s agent on earth</a>,
I should also point out that Margaret Thatcher was a totally despicable person who remained
loathsome long past her actual term in office. It was only today that I found out that in 2002,
Thatcher
<a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/0,,SB1024265060635816880,00.html">advocated the US invasion of Iraq</a>. I
was not surprised to discover so, but Jon Schwarz does a good job of examining some of the other
Reagan-Bush-Thatcher connections in the linked article.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Friedman Is A Giant Fucking Cretin]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/thomas-friedman-is-a-giant-fucking-cretin/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T06:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/thomas-friedman-is-a-giant-fucking-cretin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thomas Friedman is the perfect example of a modern courtier: you will never find his lips too far
from the cock of established power. He is always eager to tell you why his support for the existing
order of authorities and hierarchy is bold and courageous, eager to congratulate himself for his
daring and revolutionary thoughts that are in fact the most tedious kind of Beltway ass-kissing,
and eager to demonstrate that he is a creative genius by demonstrating a talent for cheap analogies
and overwrought metaphor to rival literary pimple Dan Brown.</p>

<p>Fortunately
<a href="http://brianmayer.com/2012/12/thomas-friedman-op-ed-generator/">Brian Mayer did a little mad-libbing</a>
and created the Thomas Friedman Op-Ed Generator. This is a bit of a relief, although I&rsquo;m still
tempted to cadge some Lexis-Nexis time from a friend, download Friedman&rsquo;s corpus, and apply some
proper Markov-chain fun. The thing is that the ease of creating artificial Friedman demonstrates
how shallow and meaningless the authentic Friedman is: rather tragic, really. But not enough so to
excuse that he&rsquo;s a buffoon who apologizes for monsters. My
<a href="http://www.tinyrevolution.com/mt/archives/001830.html">favorite cheap shot at Friedman</a> is Jon
Schwarz&rsquo;s: &ldquo;he suffers from the affliction [of] a large, furry parasite that has attached itself to
his upper lip and sucked his brain out through his nose,&rdquo; although
<a href="http://whoisioz.blogspot.com/search/label/Friedman">Monsieur IOZ</a> calls him &ldquo;the Milton of
infelicity&rdquo; and &ldquo;a guy who&rsquo;d go out to the desert to eat peyote and have a vision of the inside of
Best Buy,&rdquo; both of which are also corkers.</p>

<p>My problems with Friedman are a microcosm of my problems with the mainstream US media: they are
good at explaining the major arguments going on within the American aristocracy, and that&rsquo;s about
it. They are certainly not anything like defenders of truth, critics of power, or any other piece
of their inflated self-image: they are corporations that exist to make money, and their business
model is selling readers/viewers/listeners to advertisers. As Schwarz puts it,
&ldquo;<a href="http://www.tinyrevolution.com/mt/archives/000651.html">there is no Santa Claus</a>.&rdquo; Their
self-interest is only tangentially related to having a healthy community, and much more strongly
coupled to pleasing existing power structures. This is part of why I am not particularly sad over
the idea that the Internet is going to kill newspapers: newspapers produce as little journalism as
they can get away with, and in their role as propaganda outlets almost negate that which they do
produce. TV and radio &ldquo;news&rdquo; are even worse.</p>

<p>The bright side is that microbroadcasts like this blog are available to more and more
people&mdash;unfortunately, that&rsquo;s not evenly distributed and has its own problems. I&rsquo;ll still take it
over centralized and tamed news organizations any day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
