<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tumblr | Useful Tigress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/categories/tumblr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://usefultigress.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-01-23T12:39:56-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://usefultigress.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krinn DNZ]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conspiracy Is Void]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-conspiracy-is-void/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-04T18:08:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/the-conspiracy-is-void</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While there are many things I like about Tumblr, I have a bottomless appetite for cheap shots at it
(e.g. <a href="http://mightygodking.com/2013/06/04/this-act-of-creative-and-historical-vandalism-is-not-technically-my-fault/">Folsom Prison Feels</a>) and a few serious beefs. The one that I&rsquo;m here to talk about
today is not about Tumblr as a company or platform but Tumblr as a culture, and particularly about
the crop of young social-justice advocates coming up through it. Of course I make allowance here
for the way that any generation of activists will spend a fair bit of time carping about the next:
good lord, just thinking of what particularly vocal second-wave feminists have to say about my
cohort makes the roots of my hair tingle.</p>

<p>I want to talk about this problem, though, partially because it&rsquo;s a failure of thought-rigor that
we&rsquo;re all prone to. I just see it more often in the Tumblr crowd&mdash;I have ideas about why that is,
but certainly they&rsquo;re not the only people capable of this fallacy. The fallacy goes like this:
given that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kyriarchy">The Patriarchy and other toxic power systems</a> exist, as unavoidably
widespread and oppressive forces, and given that they are a member of a class that those systems do
harm to, too many people behave as though the partiarchy (or power system <em>du jour</em>) is a
conspiracy that is out to get them particularly.</p>

<p>This is fallacious in both its halves: part of why the toxic power systems are so hard to deal with
is that they are <em>not</em> conspiracies, and that they are <em>not</em> after you in particular: it is
enough that you are there and you are a member of some disfavored class. Ignoring your
individuality is a feature of the system.</p>

<p>I am of course indebted to <a href="http://zingerella.livejournal.com/73987.html?format=light">an older exploration of the matter</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, there is no one Patriarch, leastaways not outside of Constantinople. There&rsquo;s no single dude
in a nifty hat at the top of the power structure, surrounded by scantily clad women whom he
feeds to tigers for his kicks and giggles. If it were only that simple, we could off the old
wanker, free the women and give them some trousers, find loving homes for the tigers, and have a
great party around the bonfire of his palace (after salvaging all the good art, books, and
chocolate). Alas, because the patriarchy is instead a very very old system that has warped
everyone&rsquo;s thinking right down to the sub-rational, axiomatic, non-verbal ideological level, it&rsquo;s
much more difficult to overthrow. (We&rsquo;ve seen how well wars against ideas work.)</p>

<p>[&hellip;] The Gentleman complained that calling the androcentric system of how things are, or male
privilege &ldquo;the patriarchy&rdquo; personifies it, and makes it seem like a conspiracy theory in which
all men are agents of this big conspiracy to keep women down. He said that saying that &ldquo;the
system serves to perpetuate itself,&rdquo; further personifies something that is, after all, merely a
structure put in place by people, and something that not all men support.</p>

<p>The patriarchy is not a system in the way that the Library of Congress system of cataloguing is a
system. It&rsquo;s not spelled out anywhere, no single person or group of people sat down and dreamed
it up, and people don&rsquo;t usually debate its merits over those of any other system that does the
same thing. I don&rsquo;t think even Men&rsquo;s Rights Activists get up in the morning and think &ldquo;Dude! I&rsquo;m
so glad I live in a patriarchy! I&rsquo;m gonna go subjugate me some women today!&rdquo; Instead we <strong>all</strong>
live in a system that exists on patriarchal premises.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about conspiracies. Conspiracy theories are a mode of thought that we&rsquo;re all prone to,
in varying degrees. This is because as humans, we are pattern-finders. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophenia">Apophenia</a>
is our life. Further, we&rsquo;re all self-centered&mdash;necessarily, for <em>your</em> life should be about
<em>you</em>, it can&rsquo;t healthily be about someone else. This has the side effect, though, that we&rsquo;re
prone to believing that events in the world around us are also about us. Very little that is
happening around you in your life is about you, though.</p>

<p>Conspiracy theories, then, are a natural outgrowth of this: they propose that something important
is being hidden by malicious actors working in concert. The combination of pattern-finding,
self-centeredness, and the simple fact that not all events in the world are comprehensible and few
are controllable, can lead any of us to explanations for those events that range into the
conspiratorial. A recent incident illustrated the tendency in what I find a grimly humorous way:
the 2010 paper <em>&ldquo;NASA faked the moon landing–therefore (climate) science is a hoax: an anatomy of
the motivated rejection of science&rdquo;</em> tentatively identified that people who think climate science
is a giant hoax or a conspiracy, also tend to have other conspiratorial-type
beliefs. Unsurprisingly, the rejecters of climate-change science had many criticisms of the
paper&mdash;which led to the same authors' 2013 paper <em>&ldquo;Recursive fury: conspiracist ideation in the
blogosphere in response to research on conspiracist ideation,&rdquo;</em> whose subtitle basically sums it up
(cheap shot interlude: &ldquo;Recursive Fury&rdquo; is my punk-covers-of-Douglas-Hofstatder band).</p>

<p>A <a href="http://academia.edu/1207098/Dead_and_alive_Beliefs_in_contradictory_conspiracy_theories">2012 paper from the University of Kent</a> uses a different way of illustrating the
point:</p>

<blockquote><p>Conspiracy theories can form a monological belief system: A self-sustaining worldview comprised
of a network of mutually supportive beliefs. The present research shows that even mutually
incompatible conspiracy theories are positively correlated in endorsement. In Study 1, the more
participants believed that Princess Diana faked her own death, the more they believed that she
was murdered. In Study 2, the more participants believed that Osama Bin Laden was already dead
when U.S. special forces raided his compound in Pakistan, the more they believed he is still
alive. Hierarchical regression models showed that mutually incompatible conspiracy theories are
positively associated because both are associated with the view that the authorities are engaged
in a cover-up. The monological nature of conspiracy belief appears to be driven not by conspiracy
theories directly supporting one another but by broader beliefs supporting conspiracy theories in
general.</p></blockquote>

<p><em>Recursive Fury</em>, meanwhile, uses a six-point set of criteria for conspiratorial thinking:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Nefarious Intent:</strong> Assuming that the presumed conspirators have nefarious intentions. For
example, if person X assumes that blogger Y colluded with the New York Times to publish a paper
damaging to X, then X presumes nefarious intent on the part of Y.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Persecuted Victim:</strong> Self-identifying as the victim of an organised persecution.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Nihilistic Skepticism:</strong> Refusing to believe anything that doesn&rsquo;t fit into the conspiracy
theory. Note that &ldquo;conspiracy theory&rdquo; here is a fairly broad term and need not involve a global
conspiracy (e.g., that NASA faked the moon landing) but can refer to small-scale events and
hypotheses.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Nothing Occurs By Accident:</strong> Weaving any small random event into the conspiracy narrative.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Something Must Be Wrong:</strong> Switching liberally between different, even contradictory
conspiracy theories that have in common only the presumption that there is something wrong in
the official account by the alleged conspirators. Thus, people may simultaneously believe that
Princess Diana faked her own death and that she was assassinated by MI5.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Self-Sealing Reasoning:</strong> Interpreting any evidence against the conspiracy as evidence for the
conspiracy. For example, when climate scientists are exonerated of any wrong-doing 9 times over
by different investigations, this is reinterpreted to imply that the climate-change conspiracy
involves not just the world’s climate scientists but also the investigating bodies and
associated governments.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I think it&rsquo;s crucially important here to avoid saying &ldquo;oh man those conspiracy buffs, they&rsquo;ll
believe anything.&rdquo; Conspiracy theories are a pattern of thought that we are <em>all</em> vulnerable to. In
varying degrees, true, but all of us are vulnerable, and a feeling of certainty is no defense. This
is part of why we feminists, we activists, we strivers for a better world, need to especially
beware of conspiracy-theory thinking. <strong>The patriarchy is not a conspiracy.</strong></p>

<p>We encounter the patriarchy and related toxic power systems most often in a context where they are
likely to do us personal harm: of course we take it personally! But you will go grievously wrong
assuming that the system (as opposed to individual actors) dislikes you personally. You are a
wonderful person but conspiracies, as Mr. Assange tirelessly reminds us, are needy beasts and you
are not worth the effort of keeping a conspiracy running. Instead, the patriarchy is a system of
interlocking systems, which long ago passed the point where the beneficiaries and those hoping for
their table-scraps needed only act in furtherance of their self-interest, without conspiring with
anyone else, for the system to be perpetuated. When we are harmed, when we are in pain, it is
difficult to believe that it is not about us, but it really isn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Another face of this system is the United States' mainstream media&mdash;or to call it more accurately,
the propaganda system by which Official Facts are distributed (I am drawing heavily from Chomsky
here). This system is harmful to many of us, and has the effect of maintaining elite power at the
expense of the common good. It too is not a conspiracy and it does not care about you, the
news-consumer, personally. It is just the same: the system is rigged such that actors pursue their
own self-interest independently and perpetuate the system in that way. That is precisely why the
propaganda system, and the patriarchal power structures in general, are so difficult to push back
against: they are in a sense decentralized.</p>

<p>No matter how much power he may personally wield, it is vanishingly rare that a beneficiary thinks
of himself as blessed with the power of a system backing him. Indeed he generally has had to expend
considerable effort disposing of rivals for that benefit, and takes this effort for evidence of
merit. He who reaches the VP suite or the Senate or the upper echelons of an important bureaucracy,
has had to do a great deal of work and apply a great deal of ingenuity. What he generally resists
seeing, is that someone who did as much work and applied as much ingenuity, but who did not have
the benefit of a system of power behind them, would not be rewarded in the same way (they may in
fact be punished: there&rsquo;s a strong argument that lynchings were
<a href="http://bradhicks.livejournal.com/378012.html?format=light">more an economic crime than a hate crime</a>).</p>

<p>Of course there are still further complications. The baneful power systems that we&rsquo;re trying to
disrupt operate as interlocking systems and at the most abstract level, they are systems of
interactions between classes of person (not just class in the economic sense, but in just about any
way you can divide people into Us and Them). But the operation of these large systems is to spawn
smaller systems, which may repeat the process, until actual work and reification-of-hierarchy gets
done at the margins. I am not a class of person unto myself, nor is a police officer, but together
we operate the system whereby the state asserts a monopoly on
<a href="http://crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/violence.php">the use and definition of violence</a>.</p>

<p>The reason that it&rsquo;s important to note this fractal nature of systems is that if you follow it down
far enough, you will find conspiracies. Small, petty, cruel conspiracies that ruin lives, bodies,
and minds, they are nasty operations&mdash;but they are not the system that they are embedded in,
rather they are a product of it. However, they are rarer than you might think, because the secrecy
criteria is important. Remember that we&rsquo;re not counting the Family Research Council as a
conspiracy: they are actors colluding to do harm to queers, women, and pretty much everyone, but
they&rsquo;re not doing so in secret: they are quite clear about their goals, membership, tactics,
etc. They issue press releases. There are plenty of subsystems like them, including some that do
target individuals, but we need to resist letting those lure us into conspiratorial thinking.</p>

<p>The six-point scale from <em>Recursive Fury</em> can be useful for pushing against this tendency: it&rsquo;s not
a panacea, but it is a useful reminder that we&rsquo;re talking about big sloppy human systems, not
against powerful, malicious schemers. Thinking in terms of systems is an important part of the
activist toolkit, because individual actions don&rsquo;t happen in a vacuum. They have antecedents and
causes. Even on the interpersonal level, a person is not any of their actions: they are at the very
least actions and discourses over time, which is very different. For groups, likewise. Conspiracies
are rare enough that you should assume that events in the world around you are <em>not</em> the result of
a conspiracy, even if they cause you pain and are difficult to understand. Perhaps especially then.</p>

<p>Now, I know a bunch of people who spend a lot of time in <a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2008/03/the_security_mi_1.html">the security mindset</a> who&rsquo;re
going to want some caveats to be attached to this. So: there certainly are situations where you&rsquo;ll
want to worry about conspiracies, and some of those conspiracies will have an agenda that amounts
to &ldquo;kill you if you get too inconvenient to entrenched power systems.&rdquo; The best example is how
police departments and the FBI routinely employ <em>agents provocateur</em> against anyone with a remotely
anti-hierarchical agenda (to the point of being assholes to Food Not Bombs, wielders of one of the
most innocuous activism tactics imaginable). However, these situations are both rare and
illustrative that conspiracies are expensive and difficult. The big-picture system being resisted
and disrupted, is not a conspiracy.</p>

<p>I started out by talking about Tumblr, but this is a problem that&rsquo;s specific to human cognition,
not specific to Tumblr. Tumblr just happens to be full of young folks, who are normal young folks
and thus charmingly overconfident and full of anger, not yet scarred in the specific way that
produces a certain <a href="http://woborders.wordpress.com/2012/02/13/debating-tactics-remember-to-ask-what-works/">pragmatism</a>, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murphy%27s_law">parsimony of causes</a>, and a
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor">cynical optimism about others' actions</a>. Age is no guarantee that a person will come
around to a productive approach&mdash;which is to say, eschewing dramatic first resorts, patient in
proportion to how they hope for their own (inevitable) follies to be treated with patience, and
always curious as to whether there is some item of mutual agreement that could be worked towards
rather than having yet another argument.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the real sin of conspiratorial thinking, if you ask me: by presenting tempting-but-wrong
explanations for the world, it will very effectively keep you from <em>getting things done.</em> As you
make your way through the world you cannot avoid encountering the painful, the inexplicable, and
the unjust. Working against them is difficult&mdash;and conspiratorial thinking will sabotage your
work. Perhaps we could consider inverting the checklist from <em>Recursive Fury</em>:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Selfish Intent:</strong> Assume that other people primarily care about themselves. They&rsquo;re not
stupid, they have a whole life to live, but that life is about them and not about you.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Bemused Observer:</strong> Be deeply conservative in assumptions about whether or not people are out
to get you, especially in an organized manner. People generally organize for themselves, not for
you (see 1).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Judicious Acceptance:</strong> Systems made up of humans are messy, not neat, and almost never
elegant. Dramatized stories about them almost always leave out the screw-ups, friction, and
dawdling. If a conspiracy looks excellently efficient, slick, and deft, it might not exist.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Acknowledgement Of Accidents:</strong> Plenty of things happen by accident or without
planning. Account for impulse and coincidence when you account for people&rsquo;s actions.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>If There&rsquo;s No Plan, It Can&rsquo;t Be Going Wrong:</strong> Acknowledging that much of the world is not
just beyond your control, but beyond anyone&rsquo;s control, undermines the idea that a conspiracy is
bending events towards their ends. Of course the world is not quite as you would like it&mdash;but
you are just like everyone else in percieving that the world is imperfect.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Open-Ended Reasoning:</strong> Avoid at all costs becoming locked into non-falsifiable patterns of
thought: if you have a belief that can neither be proven nor disproven, you have a belief that
needs to be harshly examined. This is especially true of deciding that people you interact with
are malicious or untrustworthy: once you commit to that belief, you commit to a pattern of
actions that will make it extraordinarily hard for them to behave benevolently towards you or
extend trust to you, and your <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">confirmation bias</a> will carry the day.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Of course this is just a sketch towards the general plan of resisting conspiratorial thinking, but
it&rsquo;s a starting-place and that&rsquo;s important to have. The point of a starting-place is that you don&rsquo;t
remain there, that you make a concerted effort of getting to somewhere else. The metaphor of travel
also gives us this: look at the whole journey from time to time, not just the next step. Cultivate
a flexibility of perspective. After all, one way of looking at patriarchy is to call it the
conspiracy theory that women are all out to get you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anger, Pain, and Social Justice]]></title>
    <link href="http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/anger-pain-and-social-justice/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-02T17:59:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://usefultigress.com/blog/2013/anger-pain-and-social-justice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just over five years ago, there was
<a href="http://obsidianwings.blogs.com/obsidian_wings/2007/02/liberating_iraq.html">a short essay called &ldquo;Liberating Iraq&rdquo;</a>
that resonated with me a great deal, and has informed a great deal of my thinking since then:</p>

<blockquote><p>During this conference, there was a recurring disagreement about the role of violence in fighting
deeply unjust regimes. On one side were the women from India, who argued against the use of
violence, generally on Gandhian grounds. On the other were many of the women who lived under
deeply unjust regimes; I recall, in particular, the South Africans arguing that however laudable
nonviolence might be, their situation was sufficiently desperate that they could not afford the
luxury of waiting for nonviolence to work.</p>

<p>It seemed to me that at the heart of this disagreement was this one fact: that the women from
India were from a country that had already achieved independence, and were living with the
problems that came afterwards, whereas the women from South Africa were trying to achieve that
self-government in the first place. The South Africans seemed to think that the women from India
had forgotten what it was like to be subjugated. <em>We need to win our freedom as quickly as
possible,</em> they seemed to say. <em>We realize that it would be preferable to win that freedom in the
best possible way. If we could win it just as quickly through non-violent means, we would surely
do so. But you would not ask us to wait if you really understood what it is like to live in
slavery.</em></p>

<p>By contrast, many of the arguments made by the Indians turned on the effects that achieving
self-government through violence had on one&rsquo;s own people. <em>Don&rsquo;t do this,</em> they seemed to be
saying: <em>once you win your freedom, you will find that you and your people have grown accustomed
to settling disputes by force and to demonizing your opponents. Think now about how to use the
struggle you are waging to teach yourselves how to become citizens and to practice
self-government. Do not wait until you win your independence to discover that self-government
requires not just political power, but political responsibility.</em></p>

<p>What made this argument so fascinating and painful to watch was that it was so easy to see both
points of view. Who could possibly deny the justice of either side? And yet I thought the Indian
women were right. I did not think that they had forgotten what it was like to be oppressed. I
thought they were warning the others off a mistake that they knew would be tragic, however
comprehensible it might be. So one thing I thought that the Indian women saw was this:</p>

<p><strong>Violence is not a way of getting where you want to go, only more quickly.</strong> Its existence
changes your destination. If you use it, you had better be prepared to find yourself in the kind
of place it takes you to.</p>

<p>And another was this: <strong>liberation is not just a matter of removing an oppressive government.</strong>
It can seem that way when you live under tyranny. Nothing is more comprehensible than people
living in apartheid South Africa, or under Saddam, thinking: if only that government were removed
from power, things would be better. They would have to be. After all, how could they possibly be
worse?</p>

<p>Unfortunately, there are almost always ways in which things could be worse.</p></blockquote>

<p>Methodologies and tactics are important: the destination can&rsquo;t be fully separated from the means
used to make the journey. This is something that worries me considerably when I look at Tumblr and
its social-justice advocacy crowd. Fortunately, it&rsquo;s not the foremost thing to worry about - but
it&rsquo;s worth keeping in mind because one of the surest ways to take tactical roads that can&rsquo;t lead to
the desired destination, is to ignore that possibility.</p>

<p>Putting it another way: when we strive to overthrow a toxic structure (of any kind!), we contend
with the Scylla of ineffectual action and the Charybdis of overthrowing the toxic structure and
then immediately re-creating it. Both are more than capable of devouring us and our
fellow-travellers.</p>

<p>Fortunately there is almost no-one in the social-justice movement advocating violence itself. I am
acquainted with anarchists who are willing to raise the possibility, but who rightly find it very
suspect, and while I identify as part of the anarcho-whateverist spectrum, generally that crowd
isn&rsquo;t the crowd we&rsquo;re talking when we talk about &ldquo;the social-justice movement.&rdquo; What worries me is
that the social-justice crowd is willing to use tactics that do not demonstrate a commitment to its
professed values.</p>

<p>One of the most important things that the Internet has offered those of us striving for a better
world, is relief from isolation. When I first found the blogs and discussions of these topics, I
was hugely relieved: <em>it&rsquo;s not just me: these problems are real!</em> And there were people that I
could talk to who <em>took it for granted</em> that the problems were real and important and urgent, where
you didn&rsquo;t have to trudge yet again through pointing out that women are human, patriarchy exists,
and the US Government lies routinely. You could just start the discussion there and talk about how
it impacts your life, how you feel about it, and what to do about it.</p>

<p>This is a powerful thing drawing folks to the Tumblr scene: I see many people having that exulting,
joyful, mind-warping transformation, having their lives and selves and lived experiences
validated. It is a powerful thing. But like many ecstatic experiences, it&rsquo;s hard to dryly <em>explain</em>
it to someone who has not had it - and to inhabit it all the time, is counterproductive.</p>

<p>I notice this most with anger. Anger at the Current Arrangement is valid and healthy: without it no
one would be striving for change in any direction. It is likewise important to have a place for
that anger: if you cannot speak the anger, you&rsquo;re carrying Buddha&rsquo;s hot coal. So that&rsquo;s another
good thing that the Internet does for those striving for change: it has many places where it is
safe to speak your anger, radiantly, passionately, with all your pain and tears and rage and blood
and claws and fangs and hoarse throat and scraped skin and aching head. Places where you don&rsquo;t have
to be <em>sorry</em> for pointing out your own pain, pointing out how fucked-up the world can be, pointing
out how much pain someone can cause by not seeing you as a real person.</p>

<p>That voice is crucially important. That voice, however, is not the voice of persuasion. Persuasion,
especially when we venture into Sinclair-esque &ldquo;It is difficult to get a man to understand
something, when his salary depends upon his not understanding it!&rdquo; zones, is very, very
difficult. I have a theory that many people who have been held down by the Current Arrangement as
though by the heavy lid of a giant cast-iron slow-cooker pot, find the places where it is safe to
be angry, safe to hurt, safe to <em>be</em> instead of unsafe to exist as one&rsquo;s own self, and say: <em>why
should I again hide my anger, my pain, my own self?</em></p>

<p>Because, tragic as it is, that doesn&rsquo;t persuade people.</p>

<p>Persuading people who don&rsquo;t already agree with you is hard enough that it is called by science&rsquo;s
dryly humorous term &ldquo;Outstanding Problem In The Field.&rdquo; Simplifying tremendously, we are unlikely
to change our opinions in a vacuum because it&rsquo;s expensive, likely to rationalize whatever we&rsquo;re
already doing in terms of our professed beliefs, and unlikely to change our opinions when we&rsquo;re not
applying our rational-verbal-analytical minds to doing so. A rational-verbal-analytical mind is
costly to operate, so most of the time we don&rsquo;t do that. This is why, for example, the economics
profession erred so greatly in assuming that humans are rational economic actors: we kinda-sorta
are in aggregate and over significant time, but when it comes to individuals in day-to-day life
we&rsquo;re not at all purely rational utility-seekers; we&rsquo;re just people, people who can be fatigued,
frightened, and rushed.</p>

<p>So that&rsquo;s a major part of why it&rsquo;s so hard to persuade us: most of the time we&rsquo;re not
persuadeable. Persuasion stems from trust, safety, and calm. It&rsquo;s tricky to create these
conditions, and the most reliable routes take quite a bit of time. Part of why &ldquo;we&rsquo;re here, we&rsquo;re
queer, get used to it&rdquo; worked so well for the queer-rights movement despite its confrontational
tone was that it took advantage of this dynamic: once someone was here and visibly queer for long
enough, people did get used to it. People saw that queers are just another group of people, not the
frightening and mysterious Other. The success that I would really like hasn&rsquo;t arrived, but the
trend is clear and positive.</p>

<p>An aside: as with the post about escalation, I am not advocating that you do or cease doing any
particular thing. I am advocating that you adopt my view of the risks of certain behaviors and
adapt that to your own particular circumstances; I accept that doing that in goodwill, will
probably lead to decisions that would make me say WTF, because your circumstances are not mine and
I can&rsquo;t fully know them because I&rsquo;m not you.</p>

<p>The Tumblosphere in particular, likely because its demographics trend young, tends to have a strong
dose of this. It comes in form of &ldquo;wait a minute, shouldn&rsquo;t my being <em>right</em> be enough to persuade
people?&rdquo; When you say this,
<a href="http://seattletimes.com/html/businesstechnology/2020275838_boeingoutsourcingxml.html">a thousand grizzled engineers shake their heads ruefully</a>,
remembering the times when that didn&rsquo;t work for telling management what&rsquo;s right; a thousand
politicians do likewise, thinking of their campaigns, and so too do a thousand evangelists,
activists, and salesfolk. Persuasion is totally (and tragically: this is why Cassandra is
interesting) unrelated to being right.</p>

<p>Ideally, having the affirming, supportive space that Internet social connections give, would give
us a stable place on which to stand, from which we can build a way of persuading people who do not
experience the same pain to work together with us to build a better world. We fail, though, if we
take the voice of anger and pain out of that safe space and use it to shout at those people. Again,
this is not to say that the anger is unmerited, but only that it is not persuasive, for the same
reason that you don&rsquo;t talk to your boss at a meeting the way you talk to your friends over coffee -
and for the same reason that you probably don&rsquo;t like it when other people are shouting at you with
the voice of anger and pain.</p>

<p>I believe that it&rsquo;s crucially important that we continue to support one another, to create safe
spaces, and to give people a space to legitimately and productively speak with voices of anger and
pain. Yet at the same time we will have failed if that is is the only thing we do or the only voice
we empower people to speak with. When we are pulled between that Scylla and Charybdis of
ineffectuality and self-subversion, we must use a wide variety of tactics to preserve ourselves and
our ideals.</p>

<p>On the whole, I&rsquo;m optimistic about Internet communities of activists, deviants, and strivers for
better worlds of various kinds. They subject many ideas to a harsh but necessary test of survival
in the small. If I can&rsquo;t build a vibrant Internet community of any size on my ideas, can&rsquo;t build a
circle of a couple dozen talkative people improving their lives with my ideas, can&rsquo;t build a chatty
long-term email thread of friends debating my ideas and enjoying them, then my ideas certainly have
not hope in the larger world. Of course there&rsquo;s flex: not every idea that has a small passionate
Internet community is destined for mass-audience traction. But if an idea can roam the Internet and
not find any community at all, that&rsquo;s a profoundly bad sign for its future as a mass-audience
making-a-better-world idea.</p>

<p>We in the social-justice advocacy stream of thought fail when we make our ideals into just another
form of tribalism, when we adopt and enforce rigid hierarchies among ourselves, when we assume that
just because we&rsquo;re right, others will be persuaded towards our vision of a better world. Our
challenge is to balance our mutual support, our places where it&rsquo;s safe to express anger and pain
without fear of being punished for being vulnerable, with the practical necessity of persuading
others towards solving the problems we see by the courses that our ideals demand.</p>

<p>These are both very challenging things! They&rsquo;re ridiculously hard, and many of us say to them &mdash;
<em>I am already weary from my anger and pain, how is it that I am expected to take on this task as
well?</em> That is a totally reasonable dismay to be stricken with. But the task is ours, us in the
social-justice line of thought, because the vision is ours: if someone else does the work of social
change, they will work towards their vision. This is another reason that our infrastructure of
mutual support is so important: we acknowledge that the pain can come from one another, and we work
towards our own community modeling the solutions we&rsquo;d like to see enacted in the world at large.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
